<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-03T17:50:14+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Everyone could be a carrier Covering the covid 19 pandemic in rural India</title><link href="/Everyone-could-be-a-carrier-Covering-the-covid-19-pandemic-in-rural-India/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everyone could be a carrier Covering the covid 19 pandemic in rural India" /><published>2020-09-03T17:01:27+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T17:01:27+05:30</updated><id>/Everyone-could-be-a-carrier-Covering-the-covid-19-pandemic-in-rural-India</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Everyone-could-be-a-carrier-Covering-the-covid-19-pandemic-in-rural-India/">&lt;p&gt;BHAGALPUR : “Every person you meet is a potential carrier of the disease,” a doctor said to me when I visited the town of Bhagalpur and its nearby villages to cover the raging coronavirus pandemic in India’s countryside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Kumar Gaurav, a psychiatrist who conveyed that warning, was put in charge of the main hospital in Bhagalpur after the epidemic struck down some of his colleagues and others refused the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infections in India now total over 3.5 million, rising from two million in just over three weeks - the third highest number of coronavirus infections in the world. The disease is rampant in rural India, where people often have to rely on the most basic health facilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to show the human toll of the disease in the countryside, home to two-thirds of India’s 1.3 billion people. So, I headed out to one of the country’s most poverty-stricken regions – Bihar state in eastern India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The area I went to was not easy to reach. Wary of the risk of infection from using public transport, I and a driver travelled for four days by car across India’s northern plains from New Delhi, through floods and along rutted roads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried full personal protection suits, masks, goggles and sanitisers – which was far more than hospital staff I encountered had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Bhagalpur, I found patients and their families desperate for help and medical staff struggling with a shortage of manpower and equipment that left them at risk of infection. Often, even the equipment they did have did not work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gaurav’s hospital was dedicated to treating patients with COVID-19, serving a population of about 10 million people, and it still received other patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most COVID-19 patients came in with relatives, who accompanied them to the intensive care wards. After trying to care of the sick – sitting with them, massaging and feeding them, these relatives would go home for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gaurav said the healthcare system was close to breaking point. One of the points of constant strain, he said, was trying to limit the visits from relatives to patients in the ICU given the risk that they could spread the infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That underlined his warning to me that everyone I meet could be carrying the disease - it wasn’t a casual comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The town was under a strict lockdown, but most of the residents were not wearing masks or following any social distancing rules. Traffic was frenetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After four days in Bihar, we were on the road back to New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gaurav remained behind, the last doctor standing in his hospital on the banks of the Ganges River.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we saw him, he was making the rounds with armed guards to try to enforce rules in the hospital. He told me he felt compelled to step up to take charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A lot of my colleagues refused,” he said. “I had to take up the responsibility.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to newsletters * Enter a valid email * Thank you for subscribing to our newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share Via&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">BHAGALPUR : “Every person you meet is a potential carrier of the disease,” a doctor said to me when I visited the town of Bhagalpur and its nearby villages to cover the raging coronavirus pandemic in India’s countryside.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__17/2020-08-13T033419Z_1_LYNXNPEG7C05M_RTROPTP_3_HEALTH-CORONAVIRUS-INDIA-DOCTOR_1599014685677_1599014701856.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__17/2020-08-13T033419Z_1_LYNXNPEG7C05M_RTROPTP_3_HEALTH-CORONAVIRUS-INDIA-DOCTOR_1599014685677_1599014701856.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Coronavirus Want to meet your friends during the pandemic Here are five precautions you must take to stay safe</title><link href="/Coronavirus-Want-to-meet-your-friends-during-the-pandemic-Here-are-five-precautions-you-must-take-to-stay-safe/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coronavirus Want to meet your friends during the pandemic Here are five precautions you must take to stay safe" /><published>2020-09-03T17:00:20+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T17:00:20+05:30</updated><id>/Coronavirus-Want-to-meet-your-friends-during-the-pandemic-Here-are-five-precautions-you-must-take-to-stay-safe</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Coronavirus-Want-to-meet-your-friends-during-the-pandemic-Here-are-five-precautions-you-must-take-to-stay-safe/">&lt;p&gt;As we enter the ninth month of the year, the number of coronavirus cases across the world continue to increase at an alarming rate, crossing the 25 million mark. The pandemic is not only ravaging the health of the people around the globe, but it has also cornered us and distanced us from our normal lives. For the last eight months, people have majorly relied on virtual gatherings, video calls and socially distanced visits in the most extreme scenarios. However, as the lockdown restrictions are slowly being lifted in countries across the world in a bid to save the economy from nose-diving, people are beginning to step out of their houses to meet their friends and family members.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">As we enter the ninth month of the year, the number of coronavirus cases across the world continue to increase at an alarming rate, crossing the 25 million mark. The pandemic is not only ravaging the health of the people around the globe, but it has also cornered us and distanced us from our normal lives. For the last eight months, people have majorly relied on virtual gatherings, video calls and socially distanced visits in the most extreme scenarios. However, as the lockdown restrictions are slowly being lifted in countries across the world in a bid to save the economy from nose-diving, people are beginning to step out of their houses to meet their friends and family members.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__17/77871852.cms" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__17/77871852.cms" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">T Cell Immunity Test To Detect COVID 19 Exposure Infection Developed By Indian Doctors</title><link href="/T-Cell-Immunity-Test-To-Detect-COVID-19-Exposure-Infection-Developed-By-Indian-Doctors/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="T Cell Immunity Test To Detect COVID 19 Exposure Infection Developed By Indian Doctors" /><published>2020-09-03T16:57:13+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T16:57:13+05:30</updated><id>/-T-Cell-Immunity-Test-To-Detect-COVID-19-Exposure-Infection-Developed-By-Indian-Doctors</id><content type="html" xml:base="/T-Cell-Immunity-Test-To-Detect-COVID-19-Exposure-Infection-Developed-By-Indian-Doctors/">&lt;p&gt;Bengaluru: Doctors here claim to have developed a new test to examine specific ‘T’ cell immunity for COVID-19. Said to be India’s first-ever test to assess specific ‘T’ cell immune responses to stimulation by SARS CoV-2 proteins, it could help to better triage patients and set a framework for a sensible vaccination programme, TimesNow quoted doctors as saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doctors who jointly developed the test, said they are in the process of applying for a patent for this assay, the report added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does ‘T’ cell immunity work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COVID-19 affects people in different ways (mild to severe) and immunity plays an important role in the body’s response to the infection. It is now understood that apart from antibody response, a strong ‘T’ cell response can help in giving protective immunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antibody tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Antibody responses are not produced by all patients who contract COVID-19 and do not persist beyond 8 weeks in most people. The use of serological tests alone for screening will underestimate the number of people who have specific viral immunity. This test could complement serological surveys and provide a better picture of the prevalence of the disease and residual immunity,” said the report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have devised a novel, simple, in-tube assay for the assessment of specific T cell immune responses to stimulation by SARS CoV-2 proteins. Traditional tests for T cell immunity require complex processing to separate different cells from blood samples and use technology that is not readily available. This test can be done with a small sample of whole blood. Our solution simplifies the testing process which can be done at smaller labs without specialised equipment. The blood doesn’t require any special treatment. The results can be obtained in 24 hours, by measuring chemicals called cytokines. A positive reading indicates good specific cellular immunity,” Dr Sonal Asthana and Dr Vishnu Kurpad, two doctors involved in making the test were quoted as saying in a press release.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Bengaluru: Doctors here claim to have developed a new test to examine specific ‘T’ cell immunity for COVID-19. Said to be India’s first-ever test to assess specific ‘T’ cell immune responses to stimulation by SARS CoV-2 proteins, it could help to better triage patients and set a framework for a sensible vaccination programme, TimesNow quoted doctors as saying.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/862906-corona-positive-case.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/862906-corona-positive-case.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Avoid False Hope On COVID 19 Vaccine Health Experts Write To PM Modi</title><link href="/Avoid-False-Hope-On-COVID-19-Vaccine-Health-Experts-Write-To-PM-Modi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Avoid False Hope On COVID 19 Vaccine Health Experts Write To PM Modi" /><published>2020-09-03T16:57:08+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T16:57:08+05:30</updated><id>/-Avoid-False-Hope-On-COVID-19-Vaccine-Health-Experts-Write-To-PM-Modi</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Avoid-False-Hope-On-COVID-19-Vaccine-Health-Experts-Write-To-PM-Modi/">&lt;p&gt;The Joint Task Force of public health experts on Monday, August 31, wrote to Prime Minister Narendra Modi, stating that the vaccine for the contagious COVID-19 “would not be available in near future.” The experts added that the focus should be on preventing deaths and not containing the virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statement issued by the experts of the Indian Public Health Association, the Indian Association of Preventive and Social Medicine and the Indian Association of Epidemiologists said, “While being optimistic, the prevention and control strategy should also prepare for the worst. Vaccines do not have any role in current ongoing coronavirus pandemic control in India.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It must be assumed that an effective vaccine would not be available in the near future. We must avoid a false sense of hope that this panacea is just around the corner,” it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The petitioners of the joint statement include the former and present professors of All India Institute for Medical Sciences, Banaras Hindu University, Jawaharlal Nehru University, and Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research along with former advisors to the Ministry of Health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experts stated that the pandemic is a global health issue and should be handled with “empathy and meaningful community engagement.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We strongly and unequivocally advocate for a public health approach for the novel coronavirus pandemic control, with the maximum possible good being done for the largest possible numbers,” they added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Vaccines with proven efficacy and safety, as and when available, should be administered according to the WHO’s ‘strategic allocation’ approach or a multi-tiered risk-based approach,” the statement further said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experts also suggested stopping the ongoing practice of blocking residences of individuals who have tested positive. They further proposed the plan of resuming educational institutions in a graded manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lockdown as a strategy for control should be discontinued,” the statement said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cluster restrictions should be considered only in areas with no community transmission. Even cluster restrictions should be imposed after weighing the impact of the same on the livelihood of the target population,” it added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experts further said that the system of placing the inter-state travelers under quarantine should be stopped and instead, effective strategies like home isolation measures should be followed. They also listed out some action plans that can be considered by the government to curb the spread of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, COVID-19 cases continue to rise with India becoming the first country in the world to report 80,000 active cases in a single day. The country also witnessed a surge in fatality rates with 28,859 deaths recorded in August which is a 50 per cent rise from the past month’s record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also Read: Haryana: ‘Pick Up &amp;amp; Drop’ Facility, ‘Tokens Of Appreciation’ For Plasma Donors In Gurugram&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">The Joint Task Force of public health experts on Monday, August 31, wrote to Prime Minister Narendra Modi, stating that the vaccine for the contagious COVID-19 “would not be available in near future.” The experts added that the focus should be on preventing deaths and not containing the virus.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/RDESController" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/RDESController" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Way towards safer online communication</title><link href="/Way-towards-safer-online-communication/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Way towards safer online communication" /><published>2020-09-03T16:33:25+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T16:33:25+05:30</updated><id>/Way-towards-safer-online-communication</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Way-towards-safer-online-communication/">&lt;p&gt;Quantum communication is rapidly gaining popularity due to its high security and technological maturity. However, most implementations are limited to just two communicating parties (users). Quantum communication networks aim to connect a multitude of users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quantum communication networks present a revolutionary step in the field of quantum communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists at the University of Bristol have created a unique prototype understood to be the largest-ever quantum network of its kind. It could secure people’s online communication, particularly in these internet-led times, accelerated by the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prototype has been developed using a technique that controls the laws of physics. The method makes messages completely safe from interception while also overcoming significant challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead author Dr. Siddarth Joshi, who headed the project at the university’s Quantum Engineering Technology (QET) Labs, said: “This represents a massive breakthrough and makes the quantum internet a much more realistic proposition. Until now, building a quantum network has entailed huge cost, time, and resource and often compromises on its security, which defeats the whole purpose.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our solution is scalable, relatively cheap, and, most important of all, impregnable. That means it’s an exciting game-changer and paves the way for much more rapid development and widespread rollout of this technology.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group’s quantum technique applies a magical principle, called entanglement, which Albert Einstein depicted as ‘creepy action at a distance.’ It exploits the power of two distinct particles placed in separate locations, possibly a large number of miles apart, to emulate one another simultaneously. This process presents far more prominent open doors for quantum computers, sensors, and information processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Joshi said, “Instead of having to replicate the whole communication system, this latest methodology, called multiplexing, splits the light particles, emitted by a single system so that they can be received by multiple users efficiently.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using just eight receiver boxes, scientists created a network for eight users. As the user numbers grow, the logistics become increasingly unviable – for instance, 100 users would take 9,900 receiver boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists connected receiver boxes at different locations using optical fibers. The aim was to determine its functionality across the distance. Scientists tested the ability to transmit messages via quantum communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite being completely secure, the technique can move quickly and easily without requiring maximum hardware. It also features traffic management, delivering better network control, which allows, for instance, individual users to be prioritized with a faster connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research received funding from the Quantum Communications Hubs of the Engineering and Physical Science Research Council (EPSRC), Ministry of Science and Education (MSE) of Croatia, and the Austrian Research Promotion Agency (FFG).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaborating institutions with the University of Bristol are the University of Leeds, Croatia’s Ruder Boskovic Institute (RBI) in Zagreb, Austria’s Institute for Quantum Optics and Quantum Information (IQOQI) in Vienna, and China’s National University of Defence Technology (NUDT) in Changsha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journal Reference:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="SCIENCE" /><summary type="html">Quantum communication is rapidly gaining popularity due to its high security and technological maturity. However, most implementations are limited to just two communicating parties (users). Quantum communication networks aim to connect a multitude of users.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/quantum-physics-experiment.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/quantum-physics-experiment.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NASA Seeks Next Class of Flight Directors for Human Spaceflight Missions</title><link href="/NASA-Seeks-Next-Class-of-Flight-Directors-for-Human-Spaceflight-Missions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NASA Seeks Next Class of Flight Directors for Human Spaceflight Missions" /><published>2020-09-03T16:33:21+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T16:33:21+05:30</updated><id>/NASA-Seeks-Next-Class-of-Flight-Directors-for-Human-Spaceflight-Missions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/NASA-Seeks-Next-Class-of-Flight-Directors-for-Human-Spaceflight-Missions/">&lt;p&gt;NASA is looking for leaders for one of the best jobs on Earth for human spaceflight – including missions to the Moon – the position of flight director in mission control at the agency’s Johnson Space Center in Houston.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA will accept applications for new flight directors Thursday, Sept. 3, through Thursday, Sept. 10. U.S. citizens can apply at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.usajobs.gov/GetJob/ViewDetails/577699400&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those chosen as NASA flight directors will lead human spaceflight missions to the International Space Station, as American astronauts once again are launching on American rockets and spacecraft from American soil to the orbiting laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For almost 20 years, humans have lived and worked continuously aboard the station, advancing scientific knowledge and demonstrating new technologies, making research breakthroughs not possible on Earth that will enable long-duration human and robotic exploration into deep space. Flight directors also will lead upcoming Artemis missions to the Moon, and eventually the first human missions to Mars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flight directors are responsible for leading teams of flight controllers, research and engineering experts, and support personnel around the world, and making the real-time decisions critical to keeping NASA astronauts safe in space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“NASA flight directors need a unique mixture of confidence and humility, innovation and organization,” said Holly Ridings, chief flight director at Johnson. “The situations you have to deal with are occasionally very tough, and the stakes are always very high. But if you are able to handle that responsibility, there is nothing like knowing that you played a key role in the historic work that NASA does on a day-to-day basis.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be considered, flight director candidates must be U.S. citizens with a bachelor’s degree from an accredited institution in engineering, biological science, physical science, computer science, or mathematics. They also will need substantial related, progressively responsible professional experience, including time-critical decision-making experience in high-stress, high-risk environments. Many flight directors have previously been NASA flight controllers, though it is not a prerequisite to apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA will announce selections later this fall. The new flight directors then will receive extensive training on flight control and spacecraft systems, as well as operational leadership and risk management.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="SCIENCE" /><summary type="html">NASA is looking for leaders for one of the best jobs on Earth for human spaceflight – including missions to the Moon – the position of flight director in mission control at the agency’s Johnson Space Center in Houston.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/NASA.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/NASA.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Scientists study if meteorite impacts help create life on Earth and beyond</title><link href="/Scientists-study-if-meteorite-impacts-help-create-life-on-Earth-and-beyond/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scientists study if meteorite impacts help create life on Earth and beyond" /><published>2020-09-03T16:33:15+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T16:33:15+05:30</updated><id>/Scientists-study-if-meteorite-impacts-help-create-life-on-Earth-and-beyond</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Scientists-study-if-meteorite-impacts-help-create-life-on-Earth-and-beyond/">&lt;p&gt;A new study, posits that impact craters should absolutely be considered by space agencies like NASA and ESA as top exploration targets, not just for their invaluable post-impact geological records, but also – and perhaps more importantly – as prime locations for seeking potential habitats for extraterrestrial life. The study has been published today in Astrobiology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are a lot of hypotheses for where life started on Earth and where we should look for life on Mars, but we are actually overlooking a major geological force and a key habitat in understanding the origin of life and that’s meteorite impacts and their resulting craters,” said Osinski, Director of Western’s Institute for Earth and Space Exploration (Western Space). Leading an international team with investigators from the University of Edinburgh, Georgetown University, and the University of Southern California, this new study is grounded in Osinski’s extensive fieldwork and laboratory studies of meteorite impacts over the past two decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you ask anyone to imagine what happens when you have kilometre-size chunks of rock hitting the Earth, it’s typically destructive. It’s an extinction event like the one that killed the dinosaurs,” said Osinski. “What we’re trying to do here is turn that idea upon its head and say yes, the impact is initially destructive, but it also delivers the building blocks for life and creates new habitats for life. They [impact craters] essentially create an oasis for life,” added Osinski.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Osinski and collaborators propose that given the pervasive nature of impact events and their increased frequency during the first 500 million years of Solar System history that meteorite impact craters may represent the most likely sites where life originated on Earth. Unfortunately, says Osinski, we’ll never really know. “I put my money on meteorite impacts as the place where life could have originated on Earth, but we’ll never know,” said Osinski, also Professor in Western’s Department of Earth Sciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unfortunately, due to billions of years of erosion, plate tectonics, and volcanism, we’ve lost the vast majority of the ancient rock record on Earth. So we’re never going to know exactly where or even when, to be honest, life originated on Earth,” added Osinski. But maybe it’s not too late for the Red Planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By exploring Mars with rovers like Perseverance and ExoMars, Osinski believes planetary scientists might eventually figure out the origin of life – and they just might – as long as they are looking in the right place. “There are other impact craters on Mars that may have been better to explore with these ideas in mind. But Perseverance is going to land in Jezero Crater and there is evidence of minerals such as clays formed through hydrothermal activity,” said Osinski.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a good place to start to explore the role of meteorite impacts in the origin of life, as long as they look out for the habitats, nutrients, and building blocks for life that we outlined in our study,” added said Osinski. To date, 200 impact craters have been investigated and confirmed on Earth using fieldwork, geophysics, satellite data, and various laboratory analysis techniques in pioneering laboratories at Western and others around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Osinski and his team have collected and posted relevant data for all 200 craters as part of Western’s Impact Earth initiative. (ANI)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="SCIENCE" /><summary type="html">A new study, posits that impact craters should absolutely be considered by space agencies like NASA and ESA as top exploration targets, not just for their invaluable post-impact geological records, but also – and perhaps more importantly – as prime locations for seeking potential habitats for extraterrestrial life. The study has been published today in Astrobiology.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/03_09_2020_03_41_40_6222931.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/03_09_2020_03_41_40_6222931.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Elon Musk says there is a good chance you ll die on Mars during a virtual summit</title><link href="/Elon-Musk-says-there-is-a-good-chance-you-ll-die-on-Mars-during-a-virtual-summit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elon Musk says there is a good chance you ll die on Mars during a virtual summit" /><published>2020-09-03T16:33:08+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T16:33:08+05:30</updated><id>/Elon-Musk-says-there-is-a-good-chance-you-ll-die-on-Mars-during-a-virtual-summit</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Elon-Musk-says-there-is-a-good-chance-you-ll-die-on-Mars-during-a-virtual-summit/">&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk aims to one-day colonize Mars and, according to the billionaire, getting there is not the issue – it is surviving on the Red Planet that will be challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SpaceX CEO shared progress on the firm’s Starship rocket during the virtual Humans to Mars Summit, saying the craft ‘is making progresses,’ but also raised concerns about building a base on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musk suggested constructing a self-sustaining city will be ‘difficult’ and there will be a number of dangers settlers may face while developing the galactic civilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘I want to emphasize, this is a very hard and dangerous and difficult thing,’ Musk said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Not for the faint of heart. Good chance you’ll die. And it’s going to be tough, tough going, but it’ll be pretty glorious if it works out.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scroll down for video&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk aims to one-day colonize Mars and, according to the billionaire, getting there is not the issue – it is surviving on the Red Planet that will be challenging. The SpaceX CEO shared progress on the firm’s Starship rocket during the virtual Humans to Mars Summit, saying the craft ‘is making progresses,’ but also raised concerns about building a base on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musk has had his heart set on colonizing Mars for years and has not been shy about how he plans to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to turning this dream into a reality will be SpaceX’s massive Starship rocket, which is has been undergoing tests and construction at the firm’s Boca Chica facility in Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on his projections, SpaceX would need to build 1,000 rockets over a nine-year period in order to take one million people to Mars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘We’re making good progress,’ Musk said, as reported on by CNBC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musk suggested constructing a self-sustaining city will be ‘difficult’ and there will be a number of dangers settlers may face while developing the galactic civilization. ‘I want to emphasize, this is a very hard and dangerous and difficult thing,’ Musk said. ‘Not for the faint of heart. Good chance you’ll die’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to turning this dream into a reality will be SpaceX’s massive Starship rocket, which is has been undergoing tests and construction at the firm’s Boca Chica facility in Texas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘The thing that really impedes progress on Starship is the production system.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘A year ago there was nothing there and now we’ve got quite a lot of production capability. So we’re rapidly making more and more ships.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SpaceX has ramped up productions at Boca Chica in a bid to get the Starship off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The firm conducted the first ‘hop’ of the rocket last month, which saw the vehicle soar nearly 500 feet in the air and land safely back on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musk unveiled the first Starship prototype in 2019, with the main objective of sending humans to Mars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CEO had hoped the rocket would be soaring in low orbit by March of this year and have people inside by the end of 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the Starship program has seen a number of bumps since 2019, which Musk touched on in the Monday interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SpaceX has ramped up productions at Boca Chica (pictured) in a bid to get the Starship off the ground&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘A year ago there was nothing there and now we’ve got quite a lot of production capability. So we’re rapidly making more and more ships,’ said Musk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘I hope we do a lot of flights,’ Musk said. ‘The first ones might not work. This is uncharted territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Nobody has ever made a fully reusable orbital rocket. So just having that at all is pretty significant.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there has been numerous setbacks, Musk is now aiming for the rocket’s first orbital test flight in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team is gearing up to add the nose to the rocket, which will being the rocket to around 164 feet tall, and is set to begin construction of the first Super Heavy booster prototype ‘this week.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Super Heavy is the large bottom half of Starship rocket, which has most of the engines and is used during the beginning of a launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said on Monday that engineers have tweaked the design of the Super Heavy booster by increasing the thrust of its Raptor engines, allowing SpaceX to remove several Raptors from the design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team is gearing up to add the nose to the rocket, which will being the rocket to around 164 feet tall, and is set to begin construction of the first Super Heavy booster prototype ‘this week.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musk has shared that an operational Starship could carry more than 220,000 pounds of cargo to low Earth obit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said on Monday that engineers have tweaked the design of the Super Heavy booster by increasing the thrust of its Raptor engines, allowing SpaceX to remove several Raptors from the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘So it might be 28 engines,’ Musk said. ‘That’s still a lot of engines. We’ll also end up cranking up the thrust on the engines.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An outer ring of engines on the Super Heavy booster will have fixed nozzles, while an inner group of eight Raptors will vector their thrust to steer the rocket during takeoff and landing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="SCIENCE" /><summary type="html">Elon Musk aims to one-day colonize Mars and, according to the billionaire, getting there is not the issue – it is surviving on the Red Planet that will be challenging.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/32699638-0-image-a-29_1599064586139.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/32699638-0-image-a-29_1599064586139.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Pune Scientists Have Found a Far Away Remote Galaxy Which Even NASA s Hubble Missed</title><link href="/Pune-Scientists-Have-Found-a-Far-Away-Remote-Galaxy-Which-Even-NASA-s-Hubble-Missed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pune Scientists Have Found a Far Away Remote Galaxy Which Even NASA s Hubble Missed" /><published>2020-09-03T16:32:53+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T16:32:53+05:30</updated><id>/Pune-Scientists-Have-Found-a-Far-Away-Remote-Galaxy-Which-Even-NASA-s-Hubble-Missed</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Pune-Scientists-Have-Found-a-Far-Away-Remote-Galaxy-Which-Even-NASA-s-Hubble-Missed/">&lt;p&gt;In a landmark achievement in Space missions, a team of scientists from Pune’s Inter-University Centre for Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics (IUCAA) have discovered one of the farthest galaxies in the universe, officials said here on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The galaxy, called AUDFs01 was discovered by a team of astronomers led by IUCAA’s Kanak Saha, announced Union Minister of State Department of Space Jitendra Singh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The galaxy was discovered by India’s first Multi-Wavelength Space Observatory ‘AstroSat’, which detected extreme-UV light from a galaxy located at an astronomical distance of 9.30 billion light-years from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the second achievement for Maharashtra in the past fortnight and comes after two students of IIT-Bombay discovered a SUV-sized asteroid that zoomed past just 2,950 km above Earth’s surface on August 16. The students are Kunal Deshmukh from Pune and Kritti Sharma from Panchkula, Haryana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance and uniqueness of this original discovery can be made out from the fact that it has been reported in the leading international journal Nature Astronomy published from Britain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India’s AstroSat/UVIT was able to achieve this unique feat because the background noise in the UVIT detector is much less than one on the Hubble Space Telescope of US based NASA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Singh lauded India’s Space Scientists for once again proving to the world that India’s capability in Space technology has risen to a distinguished level from where our scientists are now offering cues and giving leads to the Space scientists in other parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IUCAA Director Somak Ray Chaudhury said: “This discovery is a very important clue to how the dark ages of the Universe ended and there was light in the Universe. We need to know when this started, but it has been very hard to find the earliest sources of light.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A noteworthy aspect is that AstroSat, which made this discovery, was launched by the Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) on September 28, 2015 during the first term of the Modi government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was developed by a team led by Shyam Tandon, Ex Emeritus Professor, IUCAA with the full support of ISRO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Tandon, the excellent spatial resolution and high sensitivity is a tribute to the hard work of the UVIT core team of scientists for over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="SCIENCE" /><summary type="html">In a landmark achievement in Space missions, a team of scientists from Pune’s Inter-University Centre for Astronomy &amp;amp; Astrophysics (IUCAA) have discovered one of the farthest galaxies in the universe, officials said here on Tuesday.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/Space.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/Space.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ISRO s AstroSat detects galaxy that is one of the earliest sources of UV light in space Technology News Firstpost</title><link href="/ISRO-s-AstroSat-detects-galaxy-that-is-one-of-the-earliest-sources-of-UV-light-in-space-Technology-News-Firstpost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ISRO s AstroSat detects galaxy that is one of the earliest sources of UV light in space Technology News Firstpost" /><published>2020-09-03T16:32:51+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-03T16:32:51+05:30</updated><id>/ISRO-s-AstroSat-detects-galaxy-that-is-one-of-the-earliest-sources-of-UV-light-in-space-Technology-News-Firstpost</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ISRO-s-AstroSat-detects-galaxy-that-is-one-of-the-earliest-sources-of-UV-light-in-space-Technology-News-Firstpost/">&lt;p&gt;tech2 News Staff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An international team of astronomers detected extreme-Ultraviolet (UV) light originating from a galaxy called AUDFs01 that is 9.3 billion light-years away from Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three subdivisions of ultraviolet radiation: near-ultraviolet (NUV), middle ultraviolet (MUV), far-ultraviolet (FUV), and extreme ultraviolet (EUV).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team that made this discovery includes scientists from India, Switzerland, France, The USA, Japan and The Netherlands and is being led by Dr Kanak Saha, Associate Professor at the Inter-University Centre for Astronomy and Astrophysics (IUCAA), Pune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The galaxy AUDFs01 is located in the Hubble eXtreme Deep Field (XDF). The XDF was assembled by combining 10 years of photographs captured of a patch of sky at the centre of the original Hubble Ultra Deep Field by the Hubble Telescope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since EUV can only be observed from space, the team made use of the Indian Space Research Organisation’s AstroSat to detect it pouring out of the galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AstroSat is India’s first mission that focuses solely on astronomy and is a multi-wavelength satellite. At any given point, it has five X-ray and ultraviolet telescopes working in tandem. It was first launched in 2015 and is supposed to have a mission life of five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using one of the six payloads onboard the satellite, the UVIT- the observation showed that the galaxy AUDFs01 is the first example of a galaxy with clumpy morphology and leaking ionizing radiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Somak Raychaudhury, Director of IUCAA, said in a statement “This is a very important clue to how the dark ages of the Universe ended and there was light in the Universe. We need to know when this started, but it has been very hard to find the earliest sources of light.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a report by The Print, after the team made this observation, they analysed the data for two years to ensure they had made no mistakes since the Hubble telescope had not been able to detect it. They wanted to be certain that the emission was indeed originating from the AUDFs01.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“AstroSat/UVIT was able to achieve this unique feat because the background noise in the UVIT detector is much less than the ones on Hubble Space Telescope”, said Saha in a statement released by ISRO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We knew it would be an uphill task to convince the international community that UVIT has recorded extreme-UV emission from this galaxy when more powerful HST has not,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of this study have been published in the journal Nature Astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA congratulates researchers on their exciting discovery. Science is collaborative effort around the world &amp;amp; discoveries like these help further humankind’s understanding of where we come from, where are we going, &amp;amp; are we alone: NASA Public Affairs Officer, Felicia Chou to ANI https://t.co/7uK1ompJiA — ANI (@ANI) September 1, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA sends its congratulations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA’s Public Affairs Officer Felicia Chou told ANI that said that “NASA congratulates the researchers on their exciting discovery” and the American space agency believes that this will further mankind’s understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said, “Science is a collaborative effort around the world, and discoveries like these help further humankind’s understanding of where we come from, where are we going, and are we alone.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="SCIENCE" /><summary type="html">tech2 News Staff</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/Astrosat_DefenseUpdate.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/03-09-2020__16/Astrosat_DefenseUpdate.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>