<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-14T11:52:27+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Flipkart Big Saving Days sale starts on Sept 18 Deals to look out for</title><link href="/Flipkart-Big-Saving-Days-sale-starts-on-Sept-18-Deals-to-look-out-for/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flipkart Big Saving Days sale starts on Sept 18 Deals to look out for" /><published>2020-09-14T10:57:02+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:57:02+05:30</updated><id>/Flipkart-Big-Saving-Days-sale-starts-on-Sept-18-Deals-to-look-out-for</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Flipkart-Big-Saving-Days-sale-starts-on-Sept-18-Deals-to-look-out-for/">&lt;p&gt;Flipkart Big Saving Days sale begins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another month and Flipkart brings another sale for its consumers. Starting September 18 Flipkart will be hosting Big Saving Days sale and offer discounts across various categories. The Flipkart Big Saving Days sale ends on September 20. During the sale, the e-commerce giant will be offering discounts and offers on electronics including smartphones, TVs, accessories, tablets, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Big Saving Days sale, Flipkart has partnered with the State Bank of India and get a 10 percent instant discount with SBI credit card and EMI transactions. Additionally, Flipkart will also be offering a chance for consumers to pre-book whatever they want to shop during the Big Saving days sale at just Re 1. It must be noted that the Re 1 pre-book offer will be valid between September 15 and September 16 only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The e-commerce giant is yet to reveal the deals but it does confirm that during Big Saving Days there will be discount offers on smartphones and tablets. Flipkart will also be offering complete appliance protection to consumers purchasing TVs and appliances. In addition, it will also offer no-cost EMI and exchange offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flipkart has also revealed that there will be more than three crore electronics and accessories on sale during Big Saving Days and all these products will be available with no-cost EMI and exchange offers. There will offer on accessories as well including wireless mouse, keyboards, power banks, cables, headphones, among others. Additionally, there could be some new launches on the platform during the sale as well besides discount offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Express Tech is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@expresstechie) and stay updated with the latest tech news&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flipkart hosts Big Saving Days sale every few months. During the last Big Saving Days sale, the e-commerce giant sold several Apple products like iPhone XR, iPhone SE (2020), and other Android smartphones at lower prices. Other products like laptops, wireless accessories, and more were also available on sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 The Indian Express is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@indianexpress) and stay updated with the latest headlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">Flipkart Big Saving Days sale begins</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/flipkart-1-1200.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/flipkart-1-1200.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Beware of SIM Swap Frauds That Can Steal Your Money This Pune CA Lost Rs 2 2 Lakh</title><link href="/Beware-of-SIM-Swap-Frauds-That-Can-Steal-Your-Money-This-Pune-CA-Lost-Rs-2-2-Lakh/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beware of SIM Swap Frauds That Can Steal Your Money This Pune CA Lost Rs 2 2 Lakh" /><published>2020-09-14T10:55:56+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:55:56+05:30</updated><id>/Beware-of-SIM-Swap-Frauds-That-Can-Steal-Your-Money-This-Pune-CA-Lost-Rs-2-2-Lakh</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Beware-of-SIM-Swap-Frauds-That-Can-Steal-Your-Money-This-Pune-CA-Lost-Rs-2-2-Lakh/">&lt;p&gt;In a new case of SIM card swapping fraud, scammers reportedly duped a Pune-based chartered accountant of Rs 2.2 lakh from her bank account. The phishing fraud is said to have happened on May 28, when the victim, whose name was not revealed in the report, received a call from scammers that pretended to be engaged with her telecom operator. During the conversation, they seemingly convinced her that she was still using a 3G SIM card, which required urgent upgrade to 4G or risked being blocked immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report by ET Telecom states that after receiving the call, the 39-year-old was duped into believing that the callers were legitimate. The scammers made the victim reveal certain key details about her phone number, following which they reportedly sent a 20-digit code to her phone number and asked her to click on it. Soon after this, the victim’s original SIM card was automatically deactivated, and the scammers took control of her number on a cloned SIM card that they now possessed, with her number registered on it. They then used it to siphon off funds worth Rs 2.2 lakh from her account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report reveals that the victim then received alerts of transactions being made from her bank account, following which she alerted her bank and blocked access to her account – but not before facing a significant loss already. An FIR on the matter was then lodged with the police department at Pune’s Alankar Police Station. According to the report, the police are still investigating the case of fraud, and the clear suspicion behind this scam is one of SIM card swapping fraud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIM swapping frauds are among the most common form of phishing frauds that occur on a regular basis. To stay safe from such incidents, users are requested to not share any sensitive details over phone, unless they specifically opt for phone banking services via authorised contact hotlines of banks. It is always advised that users remain constantly vigilant about sharing any form of technical details about their particulars, and any SIM upgrade activities should only be performed by a user in person by visiting the stores of their telecom operators.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">In a new case of SIM card swapping fraud, scammers reportedly duped a Pune-based chartered accountant of Rs 2.2 lakh from her bank account. The phishing fraud is said to have happened on May 28, when the victim, whose name was not revealed in the report, received a call from scammers that pretended to be engaged with her telecom operator. During the conversation, they seemingly convinced her that she was still using a 3G SIM card, which required urgent upgrade to 4G or risked being blocked immediately.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/1599994608_sim-card-swap-fraud-phishing-attack.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/1599994608_sim-card-swap-fraud-phishing-attack.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple iPhone Makers May Be Gainers In 6 6 Billion India Plan Report</title><link href="/Apple-iPhone-Makers-May-Be-Gainers-In-6-6-Billion-India-Plan-Report/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple iPhone Makers May Be Gainers In 6 6 Billion India Plan Report" /><published>2020-09-14T10:53:58+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:53:58+05:30</updated><id>/Apple-iPhone-Makers-May-Be-Gainers-In-6-6-Billion-India-Plan-Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Apple-iPhone-Makers-May-Be-Gainers-In-6-6-Billion-India-Plan-Report/">&lt;p&gt;India is betting that many global brands will be keen to reduce their dependence on China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple Inc.’s major iPhone assemblers are among the companies expected to win approval to participate in a $6.6 billion stimulus program to bring manufacturing to India, according to people familiar with the matter, a potentially seismic shift as the world’s most valuable company diversifies beyond China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a cabinet meeting on Wednesday, the government is expected to approve a plan aimed at bringing $150 billion in mobile-phone production over the next five years, said people, asking not to be identified because the matter is private. Among the dozen phone makers already cleared by a high-powered government committee are Apple’s primary supplier Foxconn Technology Group, which had submitted two applications, and peers Wistron Corporation and Pegatron Corporation, the people said. The three companies make virtually every iPhone sold globally in sprawling factories currently located mainly in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Production Linked Incentive program, or PLI as it’s called, manufacturing incentives will rise each year in an ongoing effort to entice the world’s biggest smartphone brands to make their products in India and export to the world. Besides the Apple contractors, Samsung Electronics is the only other applicant for the five slots allotted to foreign companies. China’s largest phone makers Huawei Technologies and BBK Group, which manufactures brands such as Oppo and Vivo, are conspicuous by their absence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amid rising trade and political tensions between the U.S. and China, India is betting that many global brands will be keen to reduce their dependence on China. If successful, the program could set in motion a shift in electronics manufacturing in the next five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s a thoughtful move by the government aimed at wooing Apple to bring significant iPhone manufacturing to India because, when the iPhone maker shifts, an entire ecosystem follows,” said Hari Om Rai, chairman and founder of Lava International Ltd., India’s largest homegrown phone maker. “The next five years will be dramatic, and India could become the new China in phone manufacturing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lava, based in the New Delhi suburbs, is among the Indian phone makers applying for manufacturing incentives, along with Karbonn Mobiles and Dixon Technologies India Ltd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To receive the incentives, foreign manufacturers including Foxconn, Wistron and Samsung must commit to specific investment and production targets of devices that sell for at least Rs 15,000 ($200); Indian phone makers will have no such restrictions. Last month, Ravi Shankar Prasad, minister for electronics and information technology, told reporters that Apple accounts for 37 per cent and Samsung 22 per cent of global sales revenue share from mobile phones. The incentive scheme would “increase their manufacturing base manifold in the country,” the ministry said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple did not respond to requests for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pegatron, the second-largest iPhone assembler after Foxconn with a number of factories in China, said in July that it would set up a plant in India. Apple accounts for more than half of Pegatron’s business. If approved, Pegatron’s first India factory would be eligible for PLI, the people said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next five years, India could attract an additional 10 per cent of global handset production, Credit Suisse said in a recent note. And though the country is the world’s second-largest handset market with plenty of room for domestic sales growth, the government’s clear aim is to eventually become a global manufacturing colossus to rival China. Almost two-thirds of the stimulus program is targeted at the export market, the people said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pankaj Mohindroo, chairman of India Cellular and Electronics Association, a trade group that represents leading phone makers including Apple, Oppo and Xiaomi, said incoming handset makers will be accompanied by a host of smaller sub-assemblers and component makers, expanding the sector to seven times its current size in the next five or so years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“India’s incentive scheme will be a game-changer that will make the country No. 1 mobile in mobile manufacturing, or at least a close No. 2 by 2025,” Mr Mohindroo said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Except for the headline, this story has not been edited by NDTV staff and is published from a syndicated feed.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">India is betting that many global brands will be keen to reduce their dependence on China.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/hshutsi_apple-bloomberg_625x300_14_July_20.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/hshutsi_apple-bloomberg_625x300_14_July_20.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Microsoft Says Its Buyout Offer for TikTok Rejected as Deadline Looms for Chinese owned App</title><link href="/Microsoft-Says-Its-Buyout-Offer-for-TikTok-Rejected-as-Deadline-Looms-for-Chinese-owned-App/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microsoft Says Its Buyout Offer for TikTok Rejected as Deadline Looms for Chinese owned App" /><published>2020-09-14T10:50:43+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:50:43+05:30</updated><id>/Microsoft-Says-Its-Buyout-Offer-for-TikTok-Rejected-as-Deadline-Looms-for-Chinese-owned-App</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Microsoft-Says-Its-Buyout-Offer-for-TikTok-Rejected-as-Deadline-Looms-for-Chinese-owned-App/">&lt;p&gt;US tech giant Microsoft has said its offer to buy TikTok was rejected, as a deadline looms for the Chinese-owned video app to sell or shut down its US operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TikTok has been at the center of a diplomatic storm between Washington and Beijing, and President Donald Trump gave Americans a deadline to stop doing business with TikTok’s Chinese parent company ByteDance – effectively compelling a sale of the app to a US company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump claims that TikTok could be used by China to track the locations of federal employees, build dossiers on people for blackmail and conduct corporate espionage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“ByteDance let us know today they would not be selling TikTok’s US operations to Microsoft,” the US tech giant said in a statement referring to TikTok’s owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are confident our proposal would have been good for TikTok’s users, while protecting national security interests,” the statement added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following Trump’s executive order, Microsoft and Oracle were possible suitors to take over TikTok operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft said that it would have “made significant changes to ensure the service met the highest standards for security, privacy, online safety, and combatting disinformation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal and New York Times reported that Oracle had won the bidding war, citing people familiar with the deal, although the company did not immediately confirm the matter to AFP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oracle bid would next need approval from the White House and Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, a source told the Journal, with both parties under the belief it would meet US data security concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TikTok has filed a lawsuit challenging the crackdown by the US government, contending that Trump’s order was a misuse of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act because the platform is not “an unusual and extraordinary threat.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloaded 175 million times in the US, TikTok is used by as many as a billion people worldwide to make quirky, short-form videos on their cellphones. It has repeatedly denied sharing data with Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">US tech giant Microsoft has said its offer to buy TikTok was rejected, as a deadline looms for the Chinese-owned video app to sell or shut down its US operations.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/1600049394_tiktok.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/1600049394_tiktok.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Oil reserves in the United States increased from August 28 to September 4 by 2 033 thousand barrels gasoline</title><link href="/Oil-reserves-in-the-United-States-increased-from-August-28-to-September-4-by-2-033-thousand-barrels-gasoline/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oil reserves in the United States increased from August 28 to September 4 by 2 033 thousand barrels gasoline" /><published>2020-09-14T10:49:40+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:49:40+05:30</updated><id>/Oil-reserves-in-the-United-States-increased-from-August-28-to-September-4-by-2-033-thousand-barrels-gasoline</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Oil-reserves-in-the-United-States-increased-from-August-28-to-September-4-by-2-033-thousand-barrels-gasoline/">&lt;p&gt;Commercial oil reserves in the US last week rose by 2,033 thousand barrels – up to 500.434 million barrels, according to a weekly report from the US Department of Energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gasoline inventories fell by 2,954,000 barrels to 231.905 million barrels, Bloomberg reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commercial stocks of distillates decreased by 1,675 thousand barrels, reaching 175.845 million barrels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts interviewed by Bloomberg expected a decrease in oil reserves by 3,000 thousand barrels, a decrease in gasoline reserves by 2,800 thousand barrels and a decrease in distillate stocks by 1,000 thousand barrels.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Commercial oil reserves in the US last week rose by 2,033 thousand barrels – up to 500.434 million barrels, according to a weekly report from the US Department of Energy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/zapasy-nefti-v-ssha-vyrosli-za-period-s-28-avgusta-po-4-sentjabrja-na-2033-tys-barrelej-benzina-upali-na-2954-tys-barrelej-17569e7.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/zapasy-nefti-v-ssha-vyrosli-za-period-s-28-avgusta-po-4-sentjabrja-na-2033-tys-barrelej-benzina-upali-na-2954-tys-barrelej-17569e7.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hospitals turn to robots to clear backlog of elective surgeries amid covid 19</title><link href="/Hospitals-turn-to-robots-to-clear-backlog-of-elective-surgeries-amid-covid-19/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hospitals turn to robots to clear backlog of elective surgeries amid covid 19" /><published>2020-09-14T10:48:35+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:48:35+05:30</updated><id>/Hospitals-turn-to-robots-to-clear-backlog-of-elective-surgeries-amid-covid-19</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Hospitals-turn-to-robots-to-clear-backlog-of-elective-surgeries-amid-covid-19/">&lt;p&gt;Leading hospitals in India including Tata Memorial, Apollo Hospitals, Rajiv Gandhi Cancer Institute and Manipal Hospitals are turning to robots to clear the backlog of elective surgeries that had to be put on hold after the covid-19 outbreak to reduce the risk of exposure to patients and doctors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though RAS (robotic assisted surgeries) has been around for many years, the usage has been sporadic. Post covid-19, the fear of crowded spaces and higher risk of infection due to prolonged stays in hospitals is making patients seek out robotic surgeries as an alternative to traditional open surgeries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After the pandemic, we have been seeing an increase in demand for robotic surgery as the procedure allows for social distancing with lesser people around the patient and robot. The infection rates are lower as compared to laparoscopy and open surgeries,” said Amol Kumar Patil, consultant, Robotic Surgery &amp;amp; Urology, Apollo Hospitals, Navi Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March, the ministry of health and family welfare issued an advisory, urging hospitals across the country to put all non-essential elective surgeries on hold. This led to a backlog of surgeries. CovidSurg Collaborative, an international research consortium, has estimated that 5,05,800 elective surgeries including 51,100 cancer surgeries and 27,700 obstetric surgeries were delayed or cancelled in India due to the imposition of lockdown and fear of infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is a sense of fear among patients to get treatment at hospitals. They are resisting treatment that involves any physical contact with surgeons and that requires longer hospital stays after surgery,” said Avanish Saklani, professor robotic/colorectal MS, FRCS, Tata Memorial Hospital, Mumbai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional surgeries involve a large team of doctors that have to operate for long hours and use hundreds instruments for the completion of one surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Due to the invasive cutting of the wound and excessive bleeding, the patient might develop post-surgery infections leading to higher risk of contracting the virus,” said Somashekhar S P, chairman &amp;amp; HOD Surgical Oncology, MHEPL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somashekhar explains, to avoid further backlog of surgeries, SAGE and Associations of Robotic consortium discussed new methods of conducting surgeries in the new covid-19 era. They compared traditional methods of surgery to robotic-assisted surgery and found that robotics had several benefits that were proving to be beneficial during covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, RAS involves just 4 instruments and a very small team of medical professionals in the operating room. The procedure is also less painful and causes less blood loss as the wound is just few millimetres in the subcuticular. Patients recover faster from the surgery, leading to early discharge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somasekar points out, robotic surgeries are also more convenient for doctors and allows them to perform many surgeries in a single day without feeling fatigued. The surgeries are performed by robotic arms are controlled by a doctor sitting at a remote console with access to 12 times magnified 3D view of the surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“During the initial days of the lockdown, people were avoiding surgeries, but now it is picking pace. As of now, 60% of the surgeries we are doing is through robotics,” said Sudhir Kumar Rawal, director – Surgical Oncology, Rajiv Gandhi Cancer Institute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to Mint Newsletters * Enter a valid email * Thank you for subscribing to our newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share Via&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here to read the Mint ePapermint is now on Telegram. Join mint channel in your Telegram and stay updated&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Leading hospitals in India including Tata Memorial, Apollo Hospitals, Rajiv Gandhi Cancer Institute and Manipal Hospitals are turning to robots to clear the backlog of elective surgeries that had to be put on hold after the covid-19 outbreak to reduce the risk of exposure to patients and doctors.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/108940e2-8603-11ea-adce-7b536c7ec0a3_1588097728466_1599914276741.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/108940e2-8603-11ea-adce-7b536c7ec0a3_1588097728466_1599914276741.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I was infected with coronavirus in March six months on I m still unwell</title><link href="/I-was-infected-with-coronavirus-in-March-six-months-on-I-m-still-unwell/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I was infected with coronavirus in March six months on I m still unwell" /><published>2020-09-14T10:48:10+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:48:10+05:30</updated><id>/I-was-infected-with-coronavirus-in-March-six-months-on-I-m-still-unwell</id><content type="html" xml:base="/I-was-infected-with-coronavirus-in-March-six-months-on-I-m-still-unwell/">&lt;p&gt;Charlie Russell, 27, is one of an estimated 600,000 people with post-Covid illness, a condition that may give an insight into ME&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s day 182 after being infected by Covid-19, and Charlie Russell is not doing the things that other 27-year-olds are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s not running 5km three times a week like he used to. He’s not going to the pub. He’s not working. And he’s not getting better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I had known that I’d be this ill, I would have taken everything a lot more seriously back in March,” Russell said. “But all that we heard back then was that if you were infected and you were a young person, you’d most likely not have any symptoms at all. Or you’d be ill for a couple of weeks and that would be it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Russell has suffered from chest pains, excruciating migraines, severe breathlessness, dizziness and exhaustion, one of the legions of “long Covid” sufferers who have experienced long-term symptoms from the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Record numbers of people in their 20s are testing positive for covid-19, according to the latest figures from Public Health England, which showed 3,366 had the virus in the first week of September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is higher than the 3,325 cases at the end of April, although those tests were mostly conducted on people in hospitals. Although people under 40 face a much lower risk of dying from the illness, 20-somethings like Russell are catching covid-19 in far higher numbers than other age groups: 20- to 29-year-olds make up nearly 28% of all new infections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few will need hospital treatment, but long-Covid support groups and medical experts fear that a significant minority will end up with a severely debilitating condition that scientists do not yet understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ve got this terrific emphasis at the moment on the idea that younger people will be OK and the main reason they shouldn’t go out is because they might infect their grannies,” said Charles Shepherd, medical adviser to the ME Association which supports people with myalgic encephalomyelitis or chronic fatigue syndrome. The association has seen substantial numbers of long-Covid patients turning to it for support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is a risk that if younger people catch the disease, they may not end up in hospital but they could have an illness that leaves them exhausted with post-Covid syndrome. It’s not going to happen to the majority, but there is a real risk for a significant minority,” Shepherd said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 600,000 people have some sort of post-Covid illness, according to Tim Spector, professor of genetic epidemiology at King’s College London, who says that around 12% of sufferers report symptoms to the Covid Tracker app for longer than 30 days. One in 200 says the effects last for more than 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russell, who is a photographer specialising in theatre, has not worked since he fell ill. He is precise about the date: 14 March. “I’ve had plenty of time to look back and think, what was I doing then? And how I wished I hadn’t been doing that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His illness lasted two weeks and he felt better not long afterwards, then experienced terrifying chest pains “like someone was sitting on me”. But hospital doctors and his GP said tests showed there were no problems – a common experience of long-Covid patients, according to Frances Simpson, a founder of the support group Long Covid SOS, who says many struggle to have their symptoms taken seriously by the medical profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russell was luckier than most – he changed GP, and the new doctor ordered an antibody test which confirmed he had had the virus. He is now one of 500 patients taking part in the Coverscan clinical trial into the impact of Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When people refuse to wear masks or to even obey the most basic of social distance rules, it’s very, very frustrating,” Russell said. “I just want to shake them and say ‘I’ve been living with this for six months’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think a lot of young people – and it’s human nature – think that if something doesn’t affect you directly, it almost doesn’t exist. Friends of mine who are still going out to the pubs, still going out to dinners and not really taking it that seriously. I do worry for them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russell was in good condition before the virus hit, with his regular 5km runs timed at about 23 minutes. Now he struggles to climb stairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long Covid SOS and other groups say that their members receive little help and there is little recognition of the condition. They want the government to formally recognise the long -term impact of the virus, provide financial support for those unable to work because of long Covid and establish multidisciplinary clinics to help assess and treat patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research has only recently begun into the long-term effects of Covid-19, but Shepherd said the working theory was that the coronavirus had disrupted people’s immune systems, causing a cytokine storm, or an overreaction of the body’s protective system, which is thought to also be a factor in ME and chronic fatigue syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Several studies in the last two or three years show that immune system dysfunction is probably involved in ME,” he said. The immune system seems to continue to activate on a low level, trying to fight off a virus that is no longer there. That reaction may then affect the central nervous system and the hypothalamus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If post-Covid fatigue and ME are linked, research may provide solutions to both conditions. It has been difficult to study ME since most people with the condition have lived with it for months – if a virus was involved, it has left little trace by the time researchers meet their patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the first time you can follow people almost from day one. Researchers are building large cohorts, they have got blood samples, and they can follow patients almost from the point of infection to when they develop post-viral fatigue. We’ve never had the opportunity to do that before.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Charlie Russell, 27, is one of an estimated 600,000 people with post-Covid illness, a condition that may give an insight into ME</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/2400.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/2400.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Covid 19 Masks could boost immunity slow infections study finds Kashmir Today</title><link href="/Covid-19-Masks-could-boost-immunity-slow-infections-study-finds-Kashmir-Today/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Covid 19 Masks could boost immunity slow infections study finds Kashmir Today" /><published>2020-09-14T10:45:34+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:45:34+05:30</updated><id>/Covid-19-Masks-could-boost-immunity-slow-infections-study-finds-Kashmir-Today</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Covid-19-Masks-could-boost-immunity-slow-infections-study-finds-Kashmir-Today/">&lt;p&gt;Experts from California university said face masks may provide a vaccine-like effect by generating immunity and slowing the spread of Covid-19 infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists are comparing face masks to a process called variolation wherein healthy people are exposed to material from the scabs of infected patients in order to increase immunity. Variolation was followed before a vaccine for smallpox was discovered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a commentary in the New England Journal of Medicine, Monica Gandhi and George W Rutherford of University of California in San Francisco said using masks in the Covid era could achieve similar results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gandhi and Rutherford concluded that face masks could reduce the viral inoculum (infecting amount of the virus). This they inferred based on long-standing theory that the severity of the disease is proportionate to the viral inoculum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Photo: AFP)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Since masks filter out some virus-containing droplets (with filtering capacity determined by mask type), masking might reduce the inoculum that an exposed person inhales,” the pair wrote in the journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, an experiment conducted on hamsters supported this theory and showed with simulated masking the animals were less likely to get infected, or were either asymptomatic or had milder symptoms than unmasked hamsters. “Universal masking seems to reduce the rate of new infections; we hypothesise that by reducing the rate of new viral infections, it would also decrease the proportion of infected people who remain asymptomatic,” Gandhi and Rutherford wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The duo also referred to an outbreak on a closed Argentinian cruise ship where passengers were provided with surgical masks and staff with N95 masks. The rate of asymptomatic infection was 81 per cent on testing compared with 20 per cent in earlier cruise ship outbreaks without universal masking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr S K Sarin, director of Institute of Liver and Biliary Sciences, said this paper explained how 29 per cent of Delhi were antibody-positive but have never had infection. “Mask may allow a very miniscule amount of virus to enter and provide a vaccine-like effect, leading to antibody formation without true infection,” said Sarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Agencies&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Experts from California university said face masks may provide a vaccine-like effect by generating immunity and slowing the spread of Covid-19 infection.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/Screenshot_20200401-062832_1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/Screenshot_20200401-062832_1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bharat Biotech s Covaxin succeeds in challenge trials on Rhesus monkeys</title><link href="/Bharat-Biotech-s-Covaxin-succeeds-in-challenge-trials-on-Rhesus-monkeys/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bharat Biotech s Covaxin succeeds in challenge trials on Rhesus monkeys" /><published>2020-09-14T10:44:56+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:44:56+05:30</updated><id>/Bharat-Biotech-s-Covaxin-succeeds-in-challenge-trials-on-Rhesus-monkeys</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Bharat-Biotech-s-Covaxin-succeeds-in-challenge-trials-on-Rhesus-monkeys/">&lt;p&gt;Hyderabad-based has released the data from the animal trials of its vaccine candidate, which showed that Covaxin was able to generate ‘robust immune responses’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The firm said that the vaccine prevented infection and disease in the primates upon high amounts of exposure to live virus Sars-CoV-2. This is called a challenge trial where a participant is exposed deliberately to the pathogen after being given the vaccine shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company tweeted “ proudly announces the animal study results of Covaxin–-these results demonstrate the protective efficacy in a live viral challenge model.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The indigenously-developed vaccine by and the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR), the country’s apex health research organisation. It is now undergoing trials at 12 sites across India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALSO READ: Halting Oxford’s Covid-19 vaccine trial is not a setback; it shows prudence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bharat Biotech noted on its website that the vaccine was given (as a two dose vaccination regimen) to 20 rhesus macaques who were divided into four groups. One group was given placebo, while three groups were immunised with three different vaccine candidates at zero and 14-days. “All the macaques were exposed to viral challenge 14 days after the second dose,” the company said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results showed protective efficacy, increasing Sars-CoV-2 specific IgG and neutralising antibodies reducing the replication of the virus in the nasal cavity, throat and lung tissues of the monkeys. Bharat Biotech also noted that no evidence of pneumonia was observed in the vaccinated groups unlike the placebo group. “Adverse events were not seen in animals immunized with a two-dose vaccination regimen,” it added.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Hyderabad-based has released the data from the animal trials of its vaccine candidate, which showed that Covaxin was able to generate ‘robust immune responses’.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/1593809007-1781.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/1593809007-1781.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Motorola launches Moto E7 Plus with Snapdragon 460 SoC 5000mAh battery</title><link href="/Motorola-launches-Moto-E7-Plus-with-Snapdragon-460-SoC-5000mAh-battery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Motorola launches Moto E7 Plus with Snapdragon 460 SoC 5000mAh battery" /><published>2020-09-14T10:42:17+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-14T10:42:17+05:30</updated><id>/Motorola-launches-Moto-E7-Plus-with-Snapdragon-460-SoC-5000mAh-battery</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Motorola-launches-Moto-E7-Plus-with-Snapdragon-460-SoC-5000mAh-battery/">&lt;p&gt;Motorola has lately been giving a tough competition to Chinese smartphone brands. And that may or may not be about the specifications but it is definitely about the number of smartphone launches it seems to have strategised. After the Moto G9 Plus, Motorola has launched a budget smartphone called the Moto E7 Plus. It has launched the new smartphone in Brazil but E7 Plus release could widen to more markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moto E7 Plus Price&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Moto E7 Plus price is not official yet. Motorola has listed the smartphone on its Brazil website with all the specifications but maybe the price is not something it wants to announce yet. The smartphone will come in Amber Bronze and Navy Blue colours, the website has revealed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moto E7 Plus Specifications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering it is a budget smartphone, Motorola has gone for hardware that respects that price bracket. The Moto E7 Plus has a 6.5-inch HD+ screen with a small notch on the top. The notch carries the front camera that is an 8-megapixel shooter. Powering it is an octa-core Qualcomm Snapdragon 460 processor paired with 4GB of RAM and 64GB of onboard storage, which is expandable further. It runs Android 10 with a few customisations from Motorola. There is a 5000mAh battery under the hood with 10W charging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cameras at the back include a 48-megapixel snapper with an f1.7 aperture and a 2-megapixel additional shooter for portrait modes. You also get an LED flash on the back. The Motorola’s batwing logo at the back mounts the physical fingerprint sensor as well. For connectivity, you have Wi-Fi, Bluetooth, GPS, 4G VoLTE, a 3.5mm headphone jack, and a Micro USB port. The Moto E7 Plus weighs 200 grams and measures in at 165.2x75.7x9.2mm. You also have a gyroscope, an accelerometer, and a proximity sensor among others on the Moto E7 Plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Moto E7 Plus seems a good rival to smartphones such as Oppo A53 as they both share the processor. This processor has not been reviewed by us so we cannot tell how good it is. But considering Qualcomm’s Snapdragon 4-series, it should be able to handle everyday tasks and moderate gaming. Moreover, a lot of customers will go for the stock Android-like experience that Motorola phones are known for. Apart from Nokia, Motorola devices are the ones that let you have an interface that is similar to Google Pixel’s.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Motorola has lately been giving a tough competition to Chinese smartphone brands. And that may or may not be about the specifications but it is definitely about the number of smartphone launches it seems to have strategised. After the Moto G9 Plus, Motorola has launched a budget smartphone called the Moto E7 Plus. It has launched the new smartphone in Brazil but E7 Plus release could widen to more markets.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/moto_e7_plus-647x363.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/14-09-2020/moto_e7_plus-647x363.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>