<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-24T16:48:46+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Chocolate Is Good for the Heart Chocolate Helps Keep the Heart s Blood Vessels Healthy</title><link href="/Chocolate-Is-Good-for-the-Heart-Chocolate-Helps-Keep-the-Heart-s-Blood-Vessels-Healthy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chocolate Is Good for the Heart Chocolate Helps Keep the Heart s Blood Vessels Healthy" /><published>2020-07-24T16:20:44+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T16:20:44+05:30</updated><id>/Chocolate-Is-Good-for-the-Heart-Chocolate-Helps-Keep-the-Heart-s-Blood-Vessels-Healthy-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Chocolate-Is-Good-for-the-Heart-Chocolate-Helps-Keep-the-Heart-s-Blood-Vessels-Healthy/">&lt;p&gt;Eating chocolate at least once a week is linked with a reduced risk of heart disease, according to research published today in the European Journal of Preventive Cardiology, a journal of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our study suggests that chocolate helps keep the heart’s blood vessels healthy,” said study author Dr. Chayakrit Krittanawong of Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the past, clinical studies have shown that chocolate is beneficial for both blood pressure and the lining of blood vessels,” he continued. “I wanted to see if it affects the blood vessels supplying the heart (the coronary arteries) or not. And if it does, is it beneficial or harmful?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers conducted a combined analysis of studies from the past five decades examining the association between chocolate consumption and coronary artery disease (the blockage of the coronary arteries). The analysis included six studies with a total of 336,289 participants who reported their chocolate consumption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a median follow-up of nearly nine years, 14,043 participants developed coronary artery disease and 4,667 had a heart attack (when coronary artery disease progresses and the flow of blood to the heart is suddenly blocked).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared with consuming chocolate less than once a week, eating chocolate more than once a week was associated with an 8% decreased risk of coronary artery disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Krittanawong said: “Chocolate contains heart-healthy nutrients such as flavonoids, methylxanthines, polyphenols and stearic acid which may reduce inflammation and increase good cholesterol (high-density lipoprotein or HDL cholesterol).”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He noted that the study did not examine whether any particular type of chocolate is more beneficial and whether there is an ideal portion size. “Chocolate appears promising for prevention of coronary artery disease, but more research is needed to pinpoint how much and what kind of chocolate could be recommended,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s not clear how much chocolate is optimal, Dr. Krittanawong warned against overeating. He said: “Moderate amounts of chocolate seem to protect the coronary arteries but it’s likely that large quantities do not. The calories, sugar, milk, and fat in commercially available products need to be considered, particularly in diabetics and obese people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference: “Association between chocolate consumption and risk of coronary artery disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis” 22 July 2020, European Journal of Preventive Cardiology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DOI: 10.1177/2047487320936787&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Eating chocolate at least once a week is linked with a reduced risk of heart disease, according to research published today in the European Journal of Preventive Cardiology, a journal of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://scitechdaily.com/images/Chocolate-Brownies.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://scitechdaily.com/images/Chocolate-Brownies.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cough Droplets Can Travel Up to 13 Feet Travel of droplets fluctuates with the climate social distancing and not using a masks is ineffective</title><link href="/Cough-Droplets-Can-Travel-Up-to-13-Feet-Travel-of-droplets-fluctuates-with-the-climate-social-distancing-and-not-using-a-masks-is-ineffective/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cough Droplets Can Travel Up to 13 Feet Travel of droplets fluctuates with the climate social distancing and not using a masks is ineffective" /><published>2020-07-24T16:19:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T16:19:00+05:30</updated><id>/Cough-Droplets-Can-Travel-Up-to-13-Feet-Travel-of-droplets-fluctuates-with-the-climate-social-distancing-and-not-using-a-masks-is-ineffective</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Cough-Droplets-Can-Travel-Up-to-13-Feet-Travel-of-droplets-fluctuates-with-the-climate-social-distancing-and-not-using-a-masks-is-ineffective/">&lt;p&gt;In cold and damp environments, fine droplets coming out of the mouth through coughs and sneezes can go long distances. In hot and dry climates, where these droplets cover a distance of only 6 to 8 feet, in cold and damp environments, these droplets can go up to 13 feet. Then even if there is no wind during this…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-During the weather changes on droplets coming out of the mouth through breath while coughing and sneezing was done in America. The main objective of doing this research is to know the possibility of spreading any respiratory disease according to the weather. This research has recently been published in General ‘Physics of Fluids’. The special thing is that scientists of Indian origin are doing this research done in America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why antibodies once made in the body will not protect against corona throughout life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first model in itself that is based on the collagen rate theory of chemical reactions and has been done keeping in mind the speed of propagation of droplets. So that it can be accurately ascertained what is the time and speed of spread of these droplets from an infected person to a healthy person in a season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cold and damp environment spreads more Corona infection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The origin of this chemical process depends on the speed with which the two molecules collide with each other. The sooner these molecules collide with each other, the faster the reaction will be seen. Similarly, the more people who come in contact with droplets released from the body of an infected person, the faster the infection will spread. This is to say the study’s author and Abhishek Saha of the University of California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handmade Face Mask For Covid-19: Method of making and storing hygienic masks of cotton at home&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– The researcher says that the distance the droplets will travel from the infected person depends to a large extent on the weather. Droplets released from the infected person’s body through cough and sneezing can go up to 8 to 13 feet. Wind speeds have not been added to this speed of droplets. That is, if these droplets meet with the wind, then their journey may be longer. At the same time until these droplets are evaporated by air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again the importance of masks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– This study once proved the usefulness of the mask. That is, if both the healthy person and the infected person have not worn the mask, then there will be no benefit of social distancing. Because even in social distancing, people are able to stand at a distance of more than 4 to 6 feet. In such a situation, we can all understand how important it is for all people to wear masks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pulse Oximeter for COVID-19 Patient: This small device has a big hand in reducing the risk of death from Kovid-19&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">In cold and damp environments, fine droplets coming out of the mouth through coughs and sneezes can go long distances. In hot and dry climates, where these droplets cover a distance of only 6 to 8 feet, in cold and damp environments, these droplets can go up to 13 feet. Then even if there is no wind during this…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://static.langimg.com/thumb/msid-77104564,width-630,height-472,resizemode-75/pic.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://static.langimg.com/thumb/msid-77104564,width-630,height-472,resizemode-75/pic.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cinnamon may help control blood sugar and progression of diabetes Study</title><link href="/Cinnamon-may-help-control-blood-sugar-and-progression-of-diabetes-Study/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cinnamon may help control blood sugar and progression of diabetes Study" /><published>2020-07-24T16:18:45+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T16:18:45+05:30</updated><id>/Cinnamon-may-help-control-blood-sugar-and-progression-of-diabetes-Study</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Cinnamon-may-help-control-blood-sugar-and-progression-of-diabetes-Study/">&lt;p&gt;Earlier studies have shown that cinnamon, a commonly used spice provides many health benefits, including the ability to lower blood sugar and help manage diabetes.Cinnamon contains bioactive components that can help lower blood sugar levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incidence of type II diabetes is increasing across the world. Dietary modifications help the patients to control blood sugar. Traditional herbs and spices are commonly used for control of blood sugar among which cinnamon (Ròu Guì; Cinnamomum cassia) has the greatest effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With increasing number of patients of diabetes, Identifying strategies to prevent the progression from prediabetes to type 2 diabetes has become challenging, yet it is important to find measures to control blood sugar in patients with Prediabetes or overt diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our 12-week study showed beneficial effects of adding cinnamon to the diet on keeping blood sugar levels stable in participants with prediabetes,” said the study’s corresponding author, Giulio R. Romeo, M.D., of Joslin Diabetes Center in Boston, Mass. “These findings provide the rationale for longer and larger studies to address if cinnamon can reduce the risk of developing type 2 diabetes over time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The randomized clinical trial investigated the effects of cinnamon supplementation in 51 participants with prediabetes. Participants were given a 500 mg cinnamon capsule or placebo three times a day for 12 weeks. The researchers found that cinnamon supplements lowered abnormal fasting glucose levels and improved the body’s response to eating a meal with carbohydrates, which are hallmarks of prediabetes. Cinnamon was well tolerated and was not associated with specific side effects or adverse events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further reference log on to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The manuscript, “Influence of Cinnamon on Glycemic Control in Subjects with Prediabetes: A Randomized Controlled Trial,” was published online.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Earlier studies have shown that cinnamon, a commonly used spice provides many health benefits, including the ability to lower blood sugar and help manage diabetes.Cinnamon contains bioactive components that can help lower blood sugar levels.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://medicaldialogues.in/h-upload/2020/06/13/130347-diabetes.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://medicaldialogues.in/h-upload/2020/06/13/130347-diabetes.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Home made face masks likely need multiple layers to prevent spread of coronavirus study says</title><link href="/Home-made-face-masks-likely-need-multiple-layers-to-prevent-spread-of-coronavirus-study-says/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home made face masks likely need multiple layers to prevent spread of coronavirus study says" /><published>2020-07-24T15:39:55+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T15:39:55+05:30</updated><id>/Home-made-face-masks-likely-need-multiple-layers-to-prevent-spread-of-coronavirus-study-says</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Home-made-face-masks-likely-need-multiple-layers-to-prevent-spread-of-coronavirus-study-says/">&lt;p&gt;For sale masks are seen displayed on a clothesline in the front yard of a house in Los Angeles on July 20, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A home-made cloth face mask likely needs two or three layers to be effective in preventing the spread of the coronavirus, according to an observational study published Thursday in the medical journal Thorax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of New South Wales in Australia looked at the effectiveness of single and double-layer cloth face coverings at reducing the spread of respiratory droplets that pass when an infected person speaks, coughs or sneezes. They then compared those results with that of a three-ply surgical face mask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers used LED lighting and a high-speed camera to film the dispersal of airborne droplets produced by a healthy person with no respiratory infection. The video for speaking was captured at 850 frames per second, while coughing and sneezing was framed 1,000 frames per second due to the higher expulsion speeds, they said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A three-ply surgical face mask was the most effective at reducing airborne droplet dispersal, the researchers found after reviewing the footage. The single-layer covering reduced the droplet spread from speaking, though the double layer covering was better in reducing droplets from coughing and sneezing, according to the researchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A cloth face covering with at least two layers is preferable to a single-layer one,” Prateek Bahl, School of Mechanical and Manufacturing Engineering, UNSW Sydney, Australia, and a lead author of the study, wrote in the findings. “Guidelines on home-made cloth masks should stipulate multiple layers.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be sure, the researchers said a single-layer face covering is better than no face covering at all. Additionally, several other factors determine the efficacy of cloth masks such as type of material, the number of layers, the arrangement of different layers and frequency of washing, they said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single-layer face covering was made from a folded piece of cotton T-shirt and hair ties. The double-layer covering was made using the sewing method as shown by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. The researchers used tissue paper to simulate the mucus membrane of the nasal cavity and induce a sneeze, according to the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study comes as the Trump administration pushes for the public to adopt face coverings in an attempt to curb the spread of the coronavirus. The United States has the worst outbreak in the world with 4 million cases and at least 143,820 deaths, according to data compiled by Johns Hopkins University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Donald Trump’s response to the pandemic has also come under increasing scrutiny. In recent weeks, Trump has downplayed the threat of the virus, tying the surge in new cases to an increase in testing. However, public health officials and infectious disease experts dispute those claims, saying the rate of cases that test positive in the U.S., hospitalizations and deaths remain high in some states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trump endorsed masks for the first time this week after resisting them for months. The CDC began recommending face masks for the general public in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the day, Adm. Brett Giroir, an assistant secretary for health at the Department of Health and Human Services, told reporters that 90% of the public or more need to wear face coverings in order to curb the spread of the virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If we close the indoor bars, reduce the occupancy of restaurants, have face coverings and hygiene, this is essentially equivalent to shutting down the entire economy, which means shutting down elective surgeries and everything else that goes with that,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">For sale masks are seen displayed on a clothesline in the front yard of a house in Los Angeles on July 20, 2020.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106629937-1595529587021-gettyimages-1227710014-AFP_1VI4DO.jpeg?v=1595529667" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106629937-1595529587021-gettyimages-1227710014-AFP_1VI4DO.jpeg?v=1595529667" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet Dr Sarah Gilbert one of the scientists leading the race to find a Covid 19 vaccine</title><link href="/Meet-Dr-Sarah-Gilbert-one-of-the-scientists-leading-the-race-to-find-a-Covid-19-vaccine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Dr Sarah Gilbert one of the scientists leading the race to find a Covid 19 vaccine" /><published>2020-07-24T15:28:35+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T15:28:35+05:30</updated><id>/Meet-Dr-Sarah-Gilbert-one-of-the-scientists-leading-the-race-to-find-a-Covid-19-vaccine</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Meet-Dr-Sarah-Gilbert-one-of-the-scientists-leading-the-race-to-find-a-Covid-19-vaccine/">&lt;p&gt;Professor Sarah Gilbert, who is leading development of a coronavirus vaccine at Oxford University, in Oxford, April 24, 2020. (Mary Turner/The New York Times) Professor Sarah Gilbert, who is leading development of a coronavirus vaccine at Oxford University, in Oxford, April 24, 2020. (Mary Turner/The New York Times)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, there was positive news on the Oxford vaccine candidate, one of a clutch of frontrunner candidates to protect the world from the SARS-CoV-2 virus that had, until Friday (July 24) morning, infected nearly 15.5 million people and killed over 630,000 worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading its development is a British scientist who plays the oboe, cycles to work, and is the mother of triplets. Dr Sarah Gilbert was famous in the scientific community as a brilliant vaccinologist; with the success in early trials, she — and ChAdOx1 nCoV-19, the vaccine candidate her team is working on — has been spotlighted as never before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gilbert and co-authors published the results of the early trials in the medical journal, The Lancet, on July 20, titled “Safety and immunogenicity of the ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccine against SARS-CoV-2: a preliminary report of a phase 1/2, single-blind, randomised controlled trial”. They wrote: “ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 showed an acceptable safety profile, and homologous boosting increased antibody responses.” Which means that the vaccine candidate had induced an immune response (which is what vaccines are supposed to do), and was safe for people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Don’t miss from Explained&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;How ‘corona’ of the virus changes into a hairpin shape — and why&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Dr Gilbert’s work in the field of vaccine development?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Gilbert is one of the leading vaccinologists in the world. She is professor of vaccinology at Oxford University’s Jenner Institute, a prestigious vaccine research centre, and one of the two founders of its spin-out company, Vaccitech, which develops immunotherapy products to treat and prevent infectious disease and cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more than 15 years, Dr Gilbert has been making and testing vaccines that trigger T cells — a type of white blood cells — to respond to antigens from malaria, influenza, and tuberculosis, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her work also includes developing vaccines for influenza and emerging diseases such as Lassa, Nipah, CCHF, and Middle East Respiratory Syndrome (MERS). MERS, which appeared in 2014, too, is caused by a coronavirus. “A vaccine against MERS has been tested in clinical trials in the UK, and is now in trials in Saudi Arabia, where the virus is endemic,” says Gilbert’s page on the Jenner Institute website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vaccine for MERS involved using the adenovirus (which causes common colds) from a chimpanzee embedded with the genetic material of the MERS virus. For the Covid-19 vaccine, the Oxford scientists used the adenovirus of a chimpanzee embedded with the genetic material from the spike protein, which the coronavirus uses to pierce the cell. In tests till now, bodies of participants have responded as if they were infected with the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 Express Explained is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@ieexplained) and stay updated with the latest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samples from the coronavirus vaccine trials, from various parts of the country, are handled inside the Oxford Vaccine Group laboratory in Oxford, Samples from the coronavirus vaccine trials, from various parts of the country, are handled inside the Oxford Vaccine Group laboratory in Oxford, England Thursday June 25, 2020. (John Cairns, University of Oxford via AP)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is known about the acclaimed scientist’s life away from her work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Gilbert has not given many interviews since the publication of the results of the early phase trials. Earlier profiles of the scientist in the UK media have said that as a child in Northamptonshire’s Kettering High School for Girls, she was quiet, polite, and studious, getting a lot of ‘A’s in studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gilbert belongs to a family of musicians, and her mother, Hazel, was part of the town’s operatic society. By the age of 17, however, Gilbert was sure that she wanted to be a medical researcher. After obtaining a degree in biology at the University of East Anglia and a PhD in biochemistry from the University of Hull, Dr Gilbert worked at a number of biotechnology companies, among them Delta, where she learnt about making medicines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Profiles on Prof Gilbert have noted that she became a vaccine specialist rather by accident. In 1994, when she entered Oxford University to join Professor Adrian Hill’s lab in a senior postdoc position, it was to work on human genetics. “That highlighted the role of a particular type of immune response in protection against malaria, and so the next thing to move on to was to make a vaccine that would work through that type of immune response — and that’s how I got into vaccines,” she told UK’s The Telegraph newspaper in an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2007, Dr Gilbert, who had become a reader at Oxford University three years previously, had won a project grant from the Wellcome Trust, and had begun work on an influenza vaccine. She has developed two vaccines for the disease so far, and has said that her ultimate aim is to be able to develop her team of scientists to be the leaders in vaccine research in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A doctor takes blood samples for use in a coronavirus vaccine trial in Oxford, England, Thursday June 25, 2020. (John Cairns, University of Oxford via AP) A doctor takes blood samples for use in a coronavirus vaccine trial in Oxford, England, Thursday June 25, 2020. (John Cairns, University of Oxford via AP)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people are fascinated with Dr Gilbert’s success in balancing the extra demands that women with a career in science face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to UNESCO, women make up less than 30 per cent of the world’s researchers. In science, technology, engineering and mathematics, women also “publish less, are paid less for their research and do not progress as far as men in their careers”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the website of the Nuffeld Department of Medicine (of which Jenner Institute, where she works, is a part), Dr Gilbert has been quoted as saying: “Work life balance is very difficult, and impossible to manage unless you have good support. Because I had triplets in 1998, nursery fees would have cost more than my entire income as a post-doctoral scientist, so my partner has had to sacrifice his own career in order to look after our children.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She described how 18 weeks of paid maternity leave with three premature babies to care for and work to be completed, was tough: “If there is a three-year grant and a woman wants a year-long maternity leave, it can disrupt the progress of the project. The situation becomes worse if more than one person is away simultaneously.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Gilbert’s advice to women: “One of the good things about being a scientist is that the hours are not fixed, so there is a fair amount of flexibility for working mothers. Having said that, there are also times when things (such as overseas conferences and important meetings) are fixed and you have to make sacrifices. It is exceptionally hard work. It’s important to plan ahead, and make sure you have people who are willing to cover for you at home while you work. That might be your partner or relatives, or you may be able to buy in help.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her own children “seem to have survived unscathed, but none of them wants to be scientists”, she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big question: Will there be a vaccine this year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Gilbert is cautiously hopeful. In an interview to the BBC, she said, “Nobody can be absolutely sure that it is possible. That’s why we have to do trials. I think the prospects are very good but it is not completely certain.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 The Indian Express is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@indianexpress) and stay updated with the latest headlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the latest Explained News, download Indian Express App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© The Indian Express (P) Ltd&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Professor Sarah Gilbert, who is leading development of a coronavirus vaccine at Oxford University, in Oxford, April 24, 2020. (Mary Turner/The New York Times) Professor Sarah Gilbert, who is leading development of a coronavirus vaccine at Oxford University, in Oxford, April 24, 2020. (Mary Turner/The New York Times)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.indianexpress.com/2020/07/Dr-Sarah-Gilbert-7.jpg?w=759" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.indianexpress.com/2020/07/Dr-Sarah-Gilbert-7.jpg?w=759" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Tale Of Three Potential Vaccines How They Stack Up In The Race For Coronavirus Prevention</title><link href="/A-Tale-Of-Three-Potential-Vaccines-How-They-Stack-Up-In-The-Race-For-Coronavirus-Prevention/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Tale Of Three Potential Vaccines How They Stack Up In The Race For Coronavirus Prevention" /><published>2020-07-24T15:24:57+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T15:24:57+05:30</updated><id>/A-Tale-Of-Three-Potential-Vaccines-How-They-Stack-Up-In-The-Race-For-Coronavirus-Prevention</id><content type="html" xml:base="/A-Tale-Of-Three-Potential-Vaccines-How-They-Stack-Up-In-The-Race-For-Coronavirus-Prevention/">&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of May, Oxford had already made the announcement of phase 2/3 human trials. These phases will involve testing of a much larger group of people and, more importantly, across a wider age group, to include children and elderly people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trials have already begun in Brazil and South Africa. Testing of 30,000 patients is expected in the US as well. With the vaccine raising hope, the UK, the US, and others including Serum Institute of India (world’s largest vaccine producer by volume) have already entered into commitments with Oxford University and AstraZeneca to have more than 2 billion vaccine doses supplied to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BNT162&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pfizer announced its five-point plan to battle Covid-19 on 13 March. Chairman and chief executive officer (CEO) Dr Albert Bourla called for collaboration in the fight against the virus and announced that his company was up to the task – “Pfizer is working to advance our own potential antiviral therapies and is engaged with BioNTech on a potential mRNA coronavirus vaccine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three days later, Pfizer and BioNTech made it official that the two companies would jointly develop BioNTech’s mRNA-based vaccine candidate BNT162. This collaboration was natural since both Pfizer and BioNTech had been involved in joint research and development work for a couple of years already to develop mRNA-based vaccines for prevention of influenza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BNT162 Covid-19 vaccine programme had multiple mRNA candidates. Progress was noted with antiviral activity recorded against SARS-CoV-2 in preclinical screening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 22 April, the phase 1/2 clinical trial for the vaccine – with its four mRNA candidates – received a nod from the German regulatory authority, the Paul-Ehrlich-Institut. The trial kicked off immediately after that in Germany and, after approvals, a week later in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preliminary data for a sub-group of 45 people arrived on 1 July. In an encouraging development, one of the four vaccine candidates, BNT162b1, was able to stimulate antibody responses at or above the levels observed in Covid-19-recovered plasma patients. Based on this data, the potential vaccines BNT162b1 and BNT162b2 were put on fast track by the US Food and Drug Administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preliminary data from the phase 1/2 trial for 60 people in Germany backed up the US data, demonstrating the ability of BNT162b1 to elicit high SARS-CoV-2 neutralising titers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, T cell responses were observed for the first time for any Pfizer-BioNTech candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the back of the good results, both the UK and the US entered into agreements with Pfizer and BioNTech to procure an initial 30 million and 100 million doses of their vaccine respectively after the necessary approvals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more data trickles in from the phase 1/2 trials, the collaborators get to pick their lead vaccine candidate and decide on the dose level to be administered to a much larger group – possibly involving up to 30,000 volunteers – in succeeding trials, slated to get underway in July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efforts have been on to ramp up manufacturing capabilities to enhance the production capacity. The Pfizer-BioNTech combine is currently expecting to manufacture “up to 100 million doses by the end of 2020 and potentially more than 1.3 billion doses by the end of 2021”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mRNA-1273&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The American biotechnology company Moderna in collaboration with the National Institutes of Health finalised the sequence for their vaccine candidate mRNA-1273 two days after the genetic sequence of the novel coronavirus was made known by China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an astounding achievement, the company took just 25 days from sequence selection to vaccine manufacture. To draw a comparison, it took 20 months to develop a vaccine for the coronavirus that caused the Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome (SARS) in 2002-03 – merely for testing in humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pace of vaccine development was quick, but news of funding began to come in quickly too. For instance, in the third week of January, the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations was roped in to fund the manufacture of Moderna’s vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority (BARDA) within the US Department of Health and Human Services came on board with a commitment of up to $483 million to push along the development of the potential vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, Moderna also struck a deal with Swiss company Lonza to enable manufacturing of up to one billion shots at the dose level of 50 µg per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases conducted the phase 1 trial in the US. On 24 February, the first batch of mRNA-1273 was released for testing. The first of the 45 patients were given a shot on 16 March. Simultaneously, work was underway to manufacture more doses for potential future trials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 12 May, Moderna received the ‘fast track’ designation from the US FDA for its potential vaccine. Positive preliminary results emerged from phase 1 almost a week later, with the mRNA-1273 eliciting neutralising antibody titer levels in the eight initial participants – four of whom received a 25 µg dose while the other four received a 100 µg dose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phase 2 study, with 600 healthy volunteers in two age groups of 18-55 years and 55 years and above, got underway towards the end of May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 14 July, the interim analysis of Moderna’s phase 1 study was published in The New England Journal of Medicine. The early results of the study showed rapid and strong immune responses against SARS-CoV-2 across all dose levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderna has already advanced the late-stage development of its Covid-19 vaccine. Its phase 3 study protocol has been made known too and, according to the company, reviewed by the US FDA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The randomized, 1:1 placebo-controlled trial is expected to include approximately 30,000 participants at the 100 µg dose level in the U.S,” revealed the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 100 µg, Moderna expects to deliver around 500 million doses per year, and “possibly up to 1 billion doses per year, beginning in 2021”, according to the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Road Ahead&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title of a 14 July editorial in The New England Journal of Medicine, “The COVID-19 Vaccine-Development Multiverse”, captures faithfully this exceptionally diverse vaccine work in progress simultaneously across the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A vaccine usually takes 10 years to develop, according to the UK-based health research foundation Wellcome Trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of this fact, the speed in the case of Covid-19 vaccine is clearly unprecedented, indicating a departure from the old paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Towards the end of May, Oxford had already made the announcement of phase 2/3 human trials. These phases will involve testing of a much larger group of people and, more importantly, across a wider age group, to include children and elderly people.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.assettype.com/swarajya%2F2020-07%2Fe58ac9fb-0581-489c-9ffc-a93fcf841dd8%2FEdX5_0UWoAIphN0.jpg?w=1200&amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;ogImage=true" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.assettype.com/swarajya%2F2020-07%2Fe58ac9fb-0581-489c-9ffc-a93fcf841dd8%2FEdX5_0UWoAIphN0.jpg?w=1200&amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;ogImage=true" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Asus ROG Phone 3 goes official comes w Stadia Pro</title><link href="/Asus-ROG-Phone-3-goes-official-comes-w-Stadia-Pro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Asus ROG Phone 3 goes official comes w Stadia Pro" /><published>2020-07-24T04:53:23+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T04:53:23+05:30</updated><id>/Asus-ROG-Phone-3-goes-official-comes-w-Stadia-Pro</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Asus-ROG-Phone-3-goes-official-comes-w-Stadia-Pro/">&lt;p&gt;Asus helped kick off the gaming phone market with its ROG series, and with its third generation, the product continues to become more and more polished. Here’s what you need to know about Asus ROG Phone 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available starting later this month, the ROG Phone 3 continues with the basic ideas of the original. That includes an unorthodox design aimed toward gamers, special attachments, and some of the best specs on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running through the spec list, Asus ROG Phone 3 offers up a Snapdragon 865+ processor, up to 512GB of UFS 3.1 storage, up to 16GB of LPDDR5 RAM, and a huge 6,000 mAh battery. The display measures in at 6.59 inches with FHD resolution and a 144Hz refresh rate. The OLED panel is capable of displaying HDR and can also hit 1,000 nits of brightness. The rear camera array consists of a 64MP primary camera, 13MP ultrawide, and 5MP macro. There’s also a 24MP selfie shooter tucked into the bezel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asus ROG Phone 3 also has a slew of new accessories to go with it. That includes the Strix XG16 portable display. The 15.6-inch panel is powered by the ROG Phone 3 (or a laptop) and has a 144Hz display for gaming on a bigger display while on the go. Asus is also revealing the ROG FALCHION minimalist mechanical keyboard, the ROG KUNAI 3 gamepad that essentially turns the phone into a Nintendo Switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing with the accessories, there are a couple of specialized cases, as well as a desktop dock. There’s also a new TwinView Dock that adds a second, identical display and the ROG Clip, a game controller clip that works with Xbox, PlayStation, and Stadia controllers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asus has also partnered with Google to give every ROG Phone 3 buyer 3 months of Stadia Pro for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ROG Phone 3 is launching in several regions around the globe with multiple variants. The ROG Phone 3 Strix Edition will be available in Europe with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage for €799 while the top end 16GB/512GB variant will cost €1,099. In India, pricing starts at ₹49,999 for the 8GB/128GB model.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><category term="featured" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">Asus helped kick off the gaming phone market with its ROG series, and with its third generation, the product continues to become more and more polished. Here’s what you need to know about Asus ROG Phone 3.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2020/07/asus_rog_phone_3_1.jpg?quality=82&amp;strip=all" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://9to5google.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2020/07/asus_rog_phone_3_1.jpg?quality=82&amp;strip=all" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Are the Earth s magnetic poles about to swap places</title><link href="/Are-the-Earth-s-magnetic-poles-about-to-swap-places/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are the Earth s magnetic poles about to swap places" /><published>2020-07-24T04:52:11+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T04:52:11+05:30</updated><id>/Are-the-Earth-s-magnetic-poles-about-to-swap-places-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Are-the-Earth-s-magnetic-poles-about-to-swap-places/">&lt;p&gt;EarthSky’s yearly crowd-funding campaign is in progress. In 2020, we are donating 8.5% to No Kids Hungry. Please donate to help us keep going, and help feed a kid!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Yael Annemiek Engbers, University of Liverpool and Andrew Biggin, University of Liverpool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep inside the Earth, liquid iron is flowing and generating the Earth’s magnetic field, which protects our atmosphere and satellites against harmful radiation from the sun. This field changes over time, and also behaves differently in different parts of the world. The field can even change polarity completely, with the magnetic north and south poles switching places. This is called a reversal and last happened 780,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between South America and southern Africa, there is an enigmatic magnetic region called the South Atlantic Anomaly, where the field is a lot weaker than we would expect. Weak and unstable fields are thought to precede magnetic reversals, so some have argued this feature may be evidence that we are facing one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now our new study, published June 12, 2020, in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, has uncovered how long the field in the South Atlantic has been acting up – and sheds light on whether it is something to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weak magnetic fields make us more prone to magnetic storms that have the potential to knock out electronic infrastructure, including power grids. The magnetic field of the South Atlantic Anomaly is already so weak that it can adversely affect satellites and their technology when they fly past it. The strange region is thought to be related to a patch of magnetic field that is pointing a different direction to the rest at the top of the planet’s liquid outer core at a depth of 1,795 miles (2,889 km) within the Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This “reverse flux patch” itself has grown over the last 250 years. But we don’t know whether it is simply a one-off product of the chaotic motions of the outer core fluid or rather the latest in a series of anomalies within this particular region over long time frames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it is a non-recurring feature, then its current location is not significant – it could happen anywhere, perhaps randomly. But if this is the case, the question of whether its increasing size and depth could mark the start of a new reversal remains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it is the latest in a string of features reoccurring over millions of years, however, then this would make a reversal less likely. But it would require a specific explanation for what was causing the magnetic field to act strangely in this particular place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volcanic rocks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out, we travelled to Saint Helena – an island in the middle of the South Atlantic Ocean. This island, where Napoleon was exiled to and eventually died in 1821, is made of volcanic rocks. These originate from two separate volcanoes and were erupted from between eight million and 11.5 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When volcanic rocks cool down, small grains of iron-oxide in them get magnetized and therefore save the direction and strength of the Earth’s magnetic field at that time and place. We collected some of those rocks and brought them back to our lab in Liverpool, where we carried out experiments to find out what the magnetic field was like at the time of eruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our results showed us that the field at Saint Helena had very different directions throughout the time of eruption, showing us that the field in this region was much less stable than in other places. It therefore challenges the idea that the abnormality has only been around for only a few centuries. Instead, the whole region has likely been unstable on a timescale of millions of years. This implies the current situation is not as rare as some scientists had assumed, making it less likely that it represents the start of a reversal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A window into Earth’s interior&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what could explain the odd magnetic region? The liquid outer core that is generating it moves (by convection) at such high speeds that changes can occur on very short, human timescales. The outer core interacts with a layer called the mantle on top of it, which moves far slower. That means the mantle is unlikely to have changed very much in the last ten million years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From seismic waves passing through the Earth, we have some insight into the structure of the mantle. Underneath Africa there is a large feature in the lowermost mantle where the waves move extra slow through the Earth – meaning there’s most likely an unusually warm region of the lowermost mantle. This possibly causes a different interaction with the outer core at that specific location, which could explain the strange behavior of the magnetic field in the South Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of the inside of the Earth is the inner core, which is a solid ball the size of Pluto beneath the outer core. This solid feature is slowly growing, but not at the same rate everywhere. There is a possibility that it is growing faster on one side, causing a flow inside the outer core that is reaching the outer boundary with the rocky mantle just under the Atlantic hemisphere. This may be causing irregular behavior of the magnetic field on the long timescales we found on Saint Helena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are still many questions about the exact cause of the irregular behavior in the South Atlantic, this study shows us that it has been around for millions of years and is most likely a result of geophysical interactions in the Earth’s mysterious interior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yael Annemiek Engbers, Ph.D. candidate, University of Liverpool and Andrew Biggin, Professor of Palaeomagnetism, University of Liverpool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is republished from The Conversation under a Creative Commons license. Read the original article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: Is Earth facing a magnetic pole reversal soon? Hear from the authors of a new study, on a strange anomaly that might be a clue.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">EarthSky’s yearly crowd-funding campaign is in progress. In 2020, we are donating 8.5% to No Kids Hungry. Please donate to help us keep going, and help feed a kid!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://earthsky.org/upl/2020/07/magnetic-poles-300x237.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://earthsky.org/upl/2020/07/magnetic-poles-300x237.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best and worse case scenarios for global warming are unlikely says comprehensive new study</title><link href="/Best-and-worse-case-scenarios-for-global-warming-are-unlikely-says-comprehensive-new-study/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best and worse case scenarios for global warming are unlikely says comprehensive new study" /><published>2020-07-24T04:52:10+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T04:52:10+05:30</updated><id>/Best-and-worse-case-scenarios-for-global-warming-are-unlikely-says-comprehensive-new-study</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Best-and-worse-case-scenarios-for-global-warming-are-unlikely-says-comprehensive-new-study/">&lt;p&gt;The best and worst-case scenarios of global warming are unlikely to occur, according to a comprehensive new study on climate probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A prediction of 1.5-4.5C warming if atmospheric levels of carbon dioxide are doubled has been the international standard since 1979.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a new study authored by a 25-strong team of international climate scientists over four years suggests it is “extremely unlikely” that warming would stay below 2C above pre-industrial levels, and puts minimum warming at 2.3C. The likelihood of staying between 1.5C and 2C is 5 per cent, the authors say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study maintains the top temperature at 4.5C, but says some recent predictions that warming above that will be reached are also “unlikely”, with a 6-18 per cent chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A less cautious analysis by the experts puts likely warming at an even narrower range of 2.6-3.9C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A doubling of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere is predicted to happen within the next 60-80 years if current emissions are maintained. That timeline will be extended by climate action such as that agreed in the Paris Accord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One of the most worrying aspects of climate change is that it is very much a roll of the dice,” said Zeke Hausfather, one of the co-authors. “What we’ve found is that the odds of getting a one or a six is a lot less likely than we previously thought.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team behind the study have a range of expertise, and used more methods to compile their evidence than any previous study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That included looking at temperature records since the industrial revolution, estimates of prehistoric temperatures, satellite records and climate models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study is likely to now inform the next assessment by the UN’s Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change next year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">The best and worst-case scenarios of global warming are unlikely to occur, according to a comprehensive new study on climate probabilities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/content/dam/news/2020/01/16/TELEMMGLPICT000221490201_trans_NvBQzQNjv4BqpVlberWd9EgFPZtcLiMQfyf2A9a6I9YchsjMeADBa08.jpeg?impolicy=logo-overlay" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/content/dam/news/2020/01/16/TELEMMGLPICT000221490201_trans_NvBQzQNjv4BqpVlberWd9EgFPZtcLiMQfyf2A9a6I9YchsjMeADBa08.jpeg?impolicy=logo-overlay" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title><link href="/powerful-things-markdown-editor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor" /><published>2020-07-24T02:25:54+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-24T02:25:54+05:30</updated><id>/powerful-things-markdown-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="/powerful-things-markdown-editor/">&lt;p&gt;There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;special-formatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;strike through&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;==highlight==&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reference-lists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quick brown jumped over the lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-html&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="tutorial" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>