<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-04T16:18:47+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Wait What Handgrip Can Detect People at High Diabetes Risk</title><link href="/Wait-What-Handgrip-Can-Detect-People-at-High-Diabetes-Risk/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wait What Handgrip Can Detect People at High Diabetes Risk" /><published>2020-09-04T15:06:56+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:06:56+05:30</updated><id>/Wait-What-Handgrip-Can-Detect-People-at-High-Diabetes-Risk-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Wait-What-Handgrip-Can-Detect-People-at-High-Diabetes-Risk/">&lt;p&gt;A study that measured the muscular handgrip strength of 776 men and women without a history of diabetes over a 20-year period has found that a simple test such as the strength of handgrip could be used as a quick, low-cost screening tool to help identify patients at risk of developing type 2 diabetes. Also Read - Are You Suffering From Diabetes? Here’s How You Can Cut Your Risk of Developing Heart Attack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 779 study subjects, the risk of type 2 diabetes was reduced by around 50 per cent for every unit increase in handgrip strength value, said scientists at the universities of Bristol and Eastern Finland in a paper published in the journal Annals of Medicine. Also Read - Antibiotics May up Heart Disease Risk in People With Diabetes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduced muscular strength, which can be measured by handgrip strength, has consistently been linked to early death, cardiovascular disease and disability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until recently, there was inconsistent evidence on the relationship between handgrip strength and type 2 diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a recent literature review of 10 published studies on the topic, the same researchers demonstrated that people with higher values of handgrip strength had a 27 per cent reduced risk of developing diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, while findings from this review suggested handgrip strength could potentially be used to predict type 2 diabetes, researchers needed to test this formally using individual patient data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the latest study, the researchers from Bristol Medical School and Eastern Finland’s Institute of Public Health and Clinical Nutrition followed 776 men and women aged 60-72 years without a history of diabetes over a 20-year period and measured the power of their hand grip strength using a handgrip dynamometer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patients were asked to squeeze the handles of the dynamometer with their dominant hand with maximum isometric effort and maintain this for five seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results demonstrated that the risk of type 2 diabetes was reduced by about 50 per cent for every unit increase in handgrip strength value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This association persisted even after taking into account several established factors that can affect type 2 diabetes, such as age, family history of diabetes, physical activity, smoking, hypertension, waist circumference and fasting plasma glucose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When information on handgrip strength was added to these established factors which are already known to predict type 2 diabetes, the prediction of type 2 diabetes improved further, the researchers noted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Assessment of handgrip is simple, inexpensive and does not require very skilled expertise and resources and could potentially be used in the early identification of individuals at high risk of future type 2 diabetes,” said lead study author Setor Kunutsor from Bristol’s Musculoskeletal Research Unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Importantly, the findings suggested women are more likely to benefit from the use of this potential screening tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We propose larger studies to replicate these findings in other populations and specifically in men and women,” said Professor Jari Laukkanen from the University of Eastern Finland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April this year, a study in the American Journal of Preventive Medicine said that hand grip can help doctors perform time-efficient screening tools for diabetes. The study identified the levels of handgrip strength/weakness that correlate with type 2 diabetes in otherwise healthy men and women, according to their body weights and ages.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">A study that measured the muscular handgrip strength of 776 men and women without a history of diabetes over a 20-year period has found that a simple test such as the strength of handgrip could be used as a quick, low-cost screening tool to help identify patients at risk of developing type 2 diabetes. Also Read - Are You Suffering From Diabetes? Here’s How You Can Cut Your Risk of Developing Heart Attack</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/Handgrip.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/Handgrip.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">US Boston Dynamics Team Builds dog like Robot To Attend To COVID 19 Patients</title><link href="/US-Boston-Dynamics-Team-Builds-dog-like-Robot-To-Attend-To-COVID-19-Patients/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="US Boston Dynamics Team Builds dog like Robot To Attend To COVID 19 Patients" /><published>2020-09-04T15:06:51+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:06:51+05:30</updated><id>/US-Boston-Dynamics-Team-Builds-dog-like-Robot-To-Attend-To-COVID-19-Patients</id><content type="html" xml:base="/US-Boston-Dynamics-Team-Builds-dog-like-Robot-To-Attend-To-COVID-19-Patients/">&lt;p&gt;Researchers from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Brigham and Women’s Hospital in Boston have created dog-like robots to attend to the COVID-19 patients and take a test while the medics remotely provide consultations. According to the press release issued by the MIT news office, these newly created mobile systems by Boston Dynamics could reduce health care workers’ exposure to COVID-19. The dog robot is controlled with the use of a handheld device and can perform tasks such as carrying tables for medications and checking symptoms in coronavirus patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In robotics, one of our goals is to use automation and robotic technology to remove people from dangerous jobs,” an MIT postdoc, Hanwei Huang said in the release. “We thought it should be possible for us to use a robot to remove the health care worker from the risk of directly exposing themselves to the patient.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least four cameras are installed in the dog-like robot by the researchers at Boston Dynamics that can measure skin temperature, breathing rate, pulse rate, and blood oxygen saturation like the pulse oximeter in the patients. It can perform these tasks while social distancing at 2 meters apart from the patient. “We are thrilled to have forged this industry-academia partnership in which scientists with engineering and robotics expertise worked with clinical teams at the hospital. It introduces sophisticated technologies to the bedside,” MIT assistant professor of mechanical engineering, a gastroenterologist at Brigham and Women’s Hospital, and the senior author of study Giovanni Traverso said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read: Scientists Develope Microrobots That Can Enter Human Veins ‘someday’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read: Ariane 5 Completes Tripple Launch With Robotic Space Tug And Two Communication Satellites&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humanoid robot ‘Atlas’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boston Dynamics is known for designing the AI humanoid robots, as earlier, AI and machine learning researcher Lex Fridman shared footage of a man-like robot that had gymnastic skills and could ace the bodyweight exercise challenges. The robotics design company’s human-like machine displayed versatility bound on a platform, doing push-ups, squats, and running, imitating the natural human body movements in the supervision of a scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Named as ‘Atlas’, the world’s most dynamic humanoid robot has been designed to push the limits of whole-body mobility according to the designers at Boston Dynamics. With advanced control-systems world’s most compact mobile hydraulics, the aim of the machine is to deliver “impressive” feats of human human-level behaviour. In the video, one can see the “outstanding” performance of the AI machine that’s “human agile” to avoid obstacles, assess the terrain, help with navigation, and manipulate objects. The tech-man stands about 5′ 9″ tall weigh approximately 80 kg, and has 28 hydraulic joints, according to the company’s specifications of the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read: Robots Tested On Ability To Clean Tokyo Station&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read: Japanese Baseball Team Inducts Dancing Robots To Replace Human Fans In Stadiums Amid COVID&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Image Credit: MIT website)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Researchers from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and Brigham and Women’s Hospital in Boston have created dog-like robots to attend to the COVID-19 patients and take a test while the medics remotely provide consultations. According to the press release issued by the MIT news office, these newly created mobile systems by Boston Dynamics could reduce health care workers’ exposure to COVID-19. The dog robot is controlled with the use of a handheld device and can perform tasks such as carrying tables for medications and checking symptoms in coronavirus patients.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/sfsta52z6bwwl84m_1599054570.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/sfsta52z6bwwl84m_1599054570.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sunbathe to Lower COVID 19 Risk Researchers Find Link Between Coronavirus Infection and Vitamin D Deficiency</title><link href="/Sunbathe-to-Lower-COVID-19-Risk-Researchers-Find-Link-Between-Coronavirus-Infection-and-Vitamin-D-Deficiency/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sunbathe to Lower COVID 19 Risk Researchers Find Link Between Coronavirus Infection and Vitamin D Deficiency" /><published>2020-09-04T15:04:50+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:04:50+05:30</updated><id>/Sunbathe-to-Lower-COVID-19-Risk-Researchers-Find-Link-Between-Coronavirus-Infection-and-Vitamin-D-Deficiency</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Sunbathe-to-Lower-COVID-19-Risk-Researchers-Find-Link-Between-Coronavirus-Infection-and-Vitamin-D-Deficiency/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;styles__noscript__2rw2y&quot; src=&quot;https://s.w-x.co/util/image/w/in-sunbath.jpg?v=at&amp;amp;w=485&amp;amp;h=273&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s.w-x.co/util/image/w/in-sunbath.jpg?v=at&amp;amp;w=485&amp;amp;h=273 400w, https://s.w-x.co/util/image/w/in-sunbath.jpg?v=ap&amp;amp;w=980&amp;amp;h=551 800w&quot; /&gt; Representational image (N Kanaka/TOI, BCCL, Visakapatnam)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deficiency of vitamin D increases one’s likelihood of getting infected with the novel coronavirus, researchers at the University of Chicago Medicine in the US have found through a retrospective study of COVID-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research team looked at 489 UChicago Medicine patients whose vitamin D levels were measured within a year before being tested for COVID-19. Subsequently, they found that individuals who had untreated vitamin D deficiency were almost twice as likely to test positive for COVID-19 as compared to patients who had sufficient levels of the vitamin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Vitamin D is important to the function of the immune system and vitamin D supplements have previously been shown to lower the risk of viral respiratory tract infections,” said Dr. David Meltzer, Chief of Hospital Medicine at UChicago Medicine and lead author of the study. “Our statistical analysis suggests this may be true for the COVID-19 infection.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitamin D not only supports lung function and cardiovascular health, but it also helps promote healthy bones and teeth and supports immune, brain, and nervous system health. And while showering in sufficient sunlight is the best way to get your body to produce vitamin D, this vital nutrient can also be obtained from food sources such as egg yolks, cheese, fortified cereals and juices, mushrooms, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, Meltzer and his team have emphasised the importance of experimental studies to determine whether vitamin D supplementation can reduce the risk as well as the severity of COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Understanding whether treating Vitamin D deficiency changes COVID-19 risk could be of great importance locally, nationally, and globally. Vitamin D is inexpensive, generally very safe to take, and can be widely scaled,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having highlighted the need for studies to understand what strategies for vitamin D supplementation may be most appropriate in specific populations, the research team has also initiated several clinical trials at UChicago Medicine along with local partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study, named Association of Vitamin D Status and Other Clinical Characteristics With COVID-19 Test Results , was published on September 3 in JAMA Network Open , and it can be accessed here .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For weather, science &amp;amp; COVID-19 updates on the go, download The Weather Channel App (on Android and iOS store). It’s free!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Representational image (N Kanaka/TOI, BCCL, Visakapatnam)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/in-sunbath.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/in-sunbath.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Social media affecting your mental health These safety tips will help you</title><link href="/Social-media-affecting-your-mental-health-These-safety-tips-will-help-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social media affecting your mental health These safety tips will help you" /><published>2020-09-04T15:04:44+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:04:44+05:30</updated><id>/Social-media-affecting-your-mental-health-These-safety-tips-will-help-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Social-media-affecting-your-mental-health-These-safety-tips-will-help-you/">&lt;p&gt;Source: Pixabay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our dependency on social media has increased multifold, especially post the coronavirus-led lockdown. We all know the benefits as well as the several drawbacks of social media, including how it impacts one’s health. So, how do you find social media wellness? That is the question digital marketer and businesswoman Bailey Parnell answers in her TED Talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bailey commences her talk by explaining how social media can be the hub of negativity and insecurity. Excess social media use has been linked with high levels of anxiety and depression, many studies have found. Parnell explains, “Let me introduce you to four of the most common stressors on social media, that if go unchecked have potential to become full-blown mental health issues. Number one: the Highlight Reel…We struggle with insecurity because we compare our behind-the-scenes with everyone else’s highlight reels. When your highlights do well, you encounter the second stressor on social media. Which is number two: Social Currency,” she explains, with respect to the system of likes, shares and comments. Number three, she reveals, is F.O.M.O or the ‘fear of missing out’, which “is an actual social anxiety from the fear that you are missing a potential connection, event, or opportunity.” And last, and perhaps the worst stressor on social media is online harassment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She says, “Social media is neither good nor bad. It’s just the most recent tool we use to do what we have always done: tell stories and communicate with each other…When we talk about this dark side of social media, what we really talk about is the dark side of people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Read&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Taking a break from social media? Keep these things in mind&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parnell advocates practising what she calls “safe social”. She explains, “Recognising a problem is the first step to fixing it…You know the power of suggestion when someone tells you about something and you start seeing it everywhere. That’s why awareness is critical.” She adds, “The second thing you are going to do is audit your social media diet. The same way we monitor what goes into our mouth, monitor whatever goes into your head and heart.” Next is step three, which is, “create a better online experience.” And finally, what you need to do is “model good behaviour.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, she says, “Is social media hurting your mental health? The answer is: it doesn’t have to. Social media can tear you down, yes, or it can lift you up, where you leave feeling better off, or have an actual laugh-out-loud.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;For more lifestyle news, follow us: Twitter: lifestyle_ie&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Facebook: IE Lifestyle&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Instagram: ie_lifestyle&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 The Indian Express is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@indianexpress) and stay updated with the latest headlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the latest Lifestyle News, download Indian Express App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© IE Online Media Services Pvt Ltd&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Source: Pixabay</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/social-media-1200.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/social-media-1200.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ZenFone Max Pro M1 users facing Widevine L1 issue to visit service center</title><link href="/ZenFone-Max-Pro-M1-users-facing-Widevine-L1-issue-to-visit-service-center/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ZenFone Max Pro M1 users facing Widevine L1 issue to visit service center" /><published>2020-09-04T15:03:42+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:03:42+05:30</updated><id>/ZenFone-Max-Pro-M1-users-facing-Widevine-L1-issue-to-visit-service-center</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ZenFone-Max-Pro-M1-users-facing-Widevine-L1-issue-to-visit-service-center/">&lt;p&gt;Asus ZenFone Max Pro M1 came out in 2018 with Android 8.1 Oreo out-of-the-box. It has already received the Android 9 Pie update but there is no sign of Android 10. Also, users have been facing an issue with the Widevine certification level since a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The August 2019 security update downgraded the Widevine cetification level on the ZenFone Max Pro M1 from L3 to L1. Since then, the issue is persistent and Asus has not been able to fix it even after acknowledging the issue and claiming to fix it in a future update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was reported back in September 2019 that the update version 16.2017.1908.058 brought Widevine L1 back. However, some users are still facing the issue after one whole year while waiting for the Android 10 update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Android 10 beta update did bring Widevine L1 back on the smartphone but there is no news on when the stable version will be released. While the Android 10 beta 3 update is also out for the device, general users cannot rely on beta updates because they are unstable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, some new development has taken place in terms of the Widevine L1 issue. A user reported on the ZenTalk community that even after upgrading to or downgrading from the Android 10 beta ROM, the Widevine level on their ZenFone Max Pro M1 remained L3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A ZenTalk moderator replied to the user stating that they will have to visit the Asus service center for better assistance. While the issue is software related, it is unclear why the moderator suggested to take the device to service center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, we suggest you to please visit the nearest ASUS service center for better assistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is highly disappointing for users as the issue can be resolved by software updates. However, it was recently reported that the OEM is planning to end support for the ZenFone Max Pro M1 and it might not get the Android 10 stable update as well. More on that here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, Asus provides the ZenFone Max Pro M1 owners with the much awaited OS update while fixing all the underlying bugs and issues. That said, you can check out our dedicated Asus section for more such stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PiunikaWeb started as purely an investigative tech journalism website with main focus on ‘breaking’ or ‘exclusive’ news. In no time, our stories got picked up by the likes of Forbes, Foxnews, Gizmodo, TechCrunch, Engadget, The Verge, Macrumors, and many others. Want to know more about us? Head here.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Asus ZenFone Max Pro M1 came out in 2018 with Android 8.1 Oreo out-of-the-box. It has already received the Android 9 Pie update but there is no sign of Android 10. Also, users have been facing an issue with the Widevine certification level since a long time.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/zenfone-max-pro-m1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/zenfone-max-pro-m1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Xiaomi Mi 10 Ultra brushes aside the competition in the August AnTuTu flagship smartphone performance chart with the iQOO 5 and ROG Phone 3 also scoring well</title><link href="/Xiaomi-Mi-10-Ultra-brushes-aside-the-competition-in-the-August-AnTuTu-flagship-smartphone-performance-chart-with-the-iQOO-5-and-ROG-Phone-3-also-scoring-well/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Xiaomi Mi 10 Ultra brushes aside the competition in the August AnTuTu flagship smartphone performance chart with the iQOO 5 and ROG Phone 3 also scoring well" /><published>2020-09-04T15:03:25+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:03:25+05:30</updated><id>/Xiaomi-Mi-10-Ultra-brushes-aside-the-competition-in-the-August-AnTuTu-flagship-smartphone-performance-chart-with-the-iQOO-5-and-ROG-Phone-3-also-scoring-well</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Xiaomi-Mi-10-Ultra-brushes-aside-the-competition-in-the-August-AnTuTu-flagship-smartphone-performance-chart-with-the-iQOO-5-and-ROG-Phone-3-also-scoring-well/">&lt;p&gt;AnTuTu has published its flagship smartphone performance chart for August and top position has been snatched up by the Xiaomi Mi 10 Ultra. The chart has thoroughly been shaken up lately thanks to some powerful new releases, including the iQOO 5 and the Asus ROG Phone 3 with its Qualcomm Snapdragon 865 Plus processor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reviews , News , CPU , GPU , Articles , Columns , Other “or” search relation. 5G , Accessory , AMD , Android , Apple , ARM , Audio , Bay Trail , Business , Cannon Lake , Charts , Chinese Tech , Chromebook , Coffee Lake , Comet Lake , Console , Convertible / 2-in-1 , Cryptocurrency , Cyberlaw , Deal , Desktop , Fail , Foldable , Gadget , Galaxy Note , Galaxy S , Gamecheck , Gaming , Geforce , Google Nexus / Pixel , How To , Ice Lake , Internet of Things (IoT) , iOS , iPad Pro , iPhone , Kaby Lake , Lakefield , Laptop , Launch , Linux / Unix , MacBook , Mini PC , Monitor , MSI , OnePlus , Opinion , Phablet , Project Athena , Renoir , Review Snippet , Rocket Lake , Rumor , Ryzen (Zen) , Security , Smart Home , Smartphone , Smartwatch , Software , Storage , Tablet , ThinkPad , Thunderbolt , Tiger Lake , Touchscreen , Ultrabook , Virtual Reality (VR) / Augmented Reality (AR) , Wearable , Whiskey Lake , Windows , Workstation , XPS , Zen 3 (Vermeer) Ticker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Xiaomi Mi 10 Ultra has stormed to the top of the AnTuTu flagship smartphone performance chart for August thanks to the combination of its powerful key components: Snapdragon 865 chip, LPDDR5 RAM (16 GB in this case), and UFS 3.1 storage (512 GB configuration). With MIUI 12 onboard and all the performance-tweaking software you could shake a stick at, it hardly seems surprising to find the Mi 10 Ultra at the head of this list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too far behind the Mi 10 Ultra’s impressive average score of 646,730 points is a fellow Snapdragon 865-wielding smartphone in the form of the iQOO 5. The 12 GB + 256 GB variant holds second position in the table and is surprisingly priced considering its specs: 4,598 yuan (US$673) was the price tag upon launch in China last month. Buyers of this iQOO 5 device can also expect to find a 120 Hz refresh rate display and 55 W fast-charging technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New in third place is the Asus ROG Phone 3 with its current world-class Qualcomm Snapdragon 865 Plus SoC. In fact, Snapdragon 865 processors and this one Plus variant dominate the chart without a look in for any rivals. Also leapfrogging the previous flagship smartphone performance champion (the OPPO Find X2 Pro) are the Tencent Black Shark 3 and the Vivo X50 Pro+ devices.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">AnTuTu has published its flagship smartphone performance chart for August and top position has been snatched up by the Xiaomi Mi 10 Ultra. The chart has thoroughly been shaken up lately thanks to some powerful new releases, including the iQOO 5 and the Asus ROG Phone 3 with its Qualcomm Snapdragon 865 Plus processor.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/10_ultra.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/10_ultra.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Twitter adds descriptions to trending topics to explain why they are popular</title><link href="/Twitter-adds-descriptions-to-trending-topics-to-explain-why-they-are-popular/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twitter adds descriptions to trending topics to explain why they are popular" /><published>2020-09-04T15:03:12+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:03:12+05:30</updated><id>/Twitter-adds-descriptions-to-trending-topics-to-explain-why-they-are-popular</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Twitter-adds-descriptions-to-trending-topics-to-explain-why-they-are-popular/">&lt;p&gt;Twitter updated its trending topics section to help users better understand why a term is popular in a bid to combat bots and conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The social media platform is pinning tweets to the top of topic threads that represented the trend well and gave added context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the coming weeks Twitter will start adding short descriptions to topics that are trending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A combination of human curators and algorithms will determine if a tweet is reflective of a trend, while making sure it’s not spam or abusive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scroll down for video&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter has begun pinning tweets to the top of trending threads to give better context to the story. A combination of human curators and algorithms will determine if a tweet is reflective of a trend, while making sure it’s not spam or abusive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘It should be easier to understand what’s being said immediately,’ the company said Tuesday in a blog post announcing the update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Throughout Twitter, we’ve been working to bring people more context on what’s happening with labels on Tweets and accounts as well as curated pages (aka Moments) and related articles on trends.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderators and algorithms will be now tasked with weeding out bots and tweets that are trying to game the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter is also blocking tweets from the conspiracy group QAnon from trending topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the coming weeks, Twitter will be adding short descriptions to some trending topics. ‘It should be easier to understand what’s being said immediately,’ the company said in a blog post announcing the update&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter hopes adding context to its Trending Topics module will help combat bots and conspiracy theories gaining traction in the section. QAnon made Wayfair trend in July with a conspiracy theory that the furniture company was engaged in child trafficking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July, QAnon made Wayfair trend with a conspiracy theory that the furniture company was involved in child trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, Russian bots got a conspiracy theory that former members of Hillary Clinton’s staff were rigging the Iowa caucuses to the top of Twitter’s trending list, according to The New York Times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophisticated botware was also responsible for tweets trending in 2018 that defended Saudi Arabia after the disappearance of journalist Jamal Khashoggi, NBC News reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July, President Donald Trump claimed Twitter’s trending topics section was ‘illegal’ because it made him look bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘So disgusting to watch Twitter’s so-called ‘Trending’, where sooo many trends are about me, and never a good one,’ Trump tweeted on July 27.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some critics - including some Twitter employees - have encouraged the company remove its trending topics section altogether. Others have suggested it turn it off until after the November 2020 presidential election&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘They look for anything they can find, make it as bad as possible, and blow it up, trying to make it trend. Really ridiculous, illegal, and, of course, very unfair!’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook removed its trending topic tab in 2018 after criticism it was promoting misinformation and biased content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It now has a dedicated news section that is curated by staffers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some critics - even some Twitter employees - have encouraged the company to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others think it should just shut the module off until after the November presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pinned tweets can now be seen on Twitter for iOS and Android and the company plans to add them to Twitter.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic descriptions will be written by Twitter’s curation team, and ‘will provide straightforward, clearly sourced context around why something is trending,’ the company said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both updates will be available on Twitter in the US, UK, France, Australia, India and more than a dozen other countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company admitted there was still room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘To be clear, we know there is more work to do to improve trends and the context updates we’re announcing today are just a small step in the right direction,’ it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘There is more we can do to help people understand why something is trending and to provide transparency around how something trends.’&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Twitter updated its trending topics section to help users better understand why a term is popular in a bid to combat bots and conspiracy theories.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/32697884-0-image-a-4_1599061626714.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/32697884-0-image-a-4_1599061626714.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AI researchers use heartbeat detection to identify deepfake videos</title><link href="/AI-researchers-use-heartbeat-detection-to-identify-deepfake-videos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI researchers use heartbeat detection to identify deepfake videos" /><published>2020-09-04T15:02:54+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:02:54+05:30</updated><id>/AI-researchers-use-heartbeat-detection-to-identify-deepfake-videos</id><content type="html" xml:base="/AI-researchers-use-heartbeat-detection-to-identify-deepfake-videos/">&lt;p&gt;Facebook and Twitter earlier this week took down social media accounts associated with the Internet Research Agency, the Russian troll farm that interfered in the U.S. presidential election four years ago, that had been spreading misinformation to up to 126 million Facebook users. Today, Facebook rolled out measures aimed at curbing disinformation ahead of Election Day in November. Deepfakes can make epic memes or put Nicholas Cage in every movie, but they can also undermine elections. As threats of election interference mount, two teams of AI researchers have recently introduced novel approaches to identifying deepfakes by watching for evidence of heartbeats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing deepfake detection models focus on traditional media forensics methods, like tracking unnatural eyelid movements or distortions at the edge of the face. The first study for detection of unique GAN fingerprints was introduced in 2018. But photoplethysmography (PPG) translates visual cues such as how blood flow causes slight changes in skin color into a human heartbeat. Remote PPG applications are being explored in areas like health care, but PPG is also being used to identify deepfakes because generative models are not currently known to be able to mimic human blood movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In work released last week, Binghamton University and Intel researchers introduced AI that goes beyond deepfake detection to recognize which deepfake model made a doctored video. The researchers found that deepfake model videos leave behind unique biological and generative noise signals — what they call “deepfake heartbeats.” The detection approach looks for residual biological signals from 32 different spots in a person’s face, which the researchers call PPG cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We propose a deepfake source detector that predicts the source generative model for any given video. To our knowledge, our approach is the first to conduct a deeper analysis for source detection that interprets residuals of generative models for deepfake videos,” the paper reads. “Our key finding emerges from the fact that we can interpret these biological signals as fake heartbeats that contain a signature transformation of the residuals per model. Thus, it gives rise to a new exploration of these biological signals for not only determining the authenticity of a video, but also classifying its source model that generates the video.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In experiments with deepfake video data sets, the PPG cell approach detected deepfakes with 97.3% accuracy and identified generative deepfake models from the popular deepfake data set FaceForensics++ with 93.4% accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers’ paper, “How Do the Hearts of Deep Fakes Beat? Deep Fake Source Detection via Interpreting Residuals with Biological Signals,” was published last week and accepted for publication by the International Joint Conference on Biometrics, which will take place later this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another recent work, AI researchers from Alibaba Group, Kyushu University, Nanyang Technological University, and Tianjin University introduced DeepRhythm, a deepfake detection model that recognizes human heartbeats from visual PPG. The authors said DeepRhythm differs from previously existing models for identifying live people in a video because it attempts to recognize rhythm patterns, “since fake videos may still have the heart rhythms, but their patterns are diminished by deepfake methods and are different from the real ones.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DeepRhythm incorporates a heart rhythm motion amplification module and learnable spatial-temporal attention mechanism at various stages of the network model. Researchers say DeepRhythm outperforms numerous state-of-the-art deepfake methods when using FaceForensics++ as a benchmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Experimental results on FaceForensics++ and Deepfake Detection Challenge-preview data set demonstrate that our method not only outperforms state-of-the-art methods but is robust to various degradations,” the team wrote. The paper, titled “DeepRhythm: Exposing DeepFakes with Attentional Visual Heartbeat Rhythms,” was published in June and revised last week, and it was accepted for publication by the ACM Multimedia conference set to take place in October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both groups of researchers say they want to explore ways to combine PPG systems with existing video authentication methods in future work. This would allow them to achieve more accurate or robust ways of identifying deepfake videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, Microsoft introduced the Video Authentication deepfake detection service for Azure. As part of its launch, Video Authentication is being made available to news media and political campaigns through the AI Foundation’s Reality Defender program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As concerns about election interference kick into high gear, at present, doctored videos and falsehoods spread by President Trump and his team appear to pose bigger threats than deepfakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, White House director of social media Dan Scavino shared a video that Twitter labeled as “manipulated media.” The original video showed Harry Belafonte asleep in a news interview, while in the doctored version it was Democratic presidential candidate Joe Biden who appeared to be asleep. A CBS Sacramento anchor joined in calling the video a fake on Monday, and Twitter has removed the video due to a report filed by the copyright owner. But the doctored video has been viewed more than a million times.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Facebook and Twitter earlier this week took down social media accounts associated with the Internet Research Agency, the Russian troll farm that interfered in the U.S. presidential election four years ago, that had been spreading misinformation to up to 126 million Facebook users. Today, Facebook rolled out measures aimed at curbing disinformation ahead of Election Day in November. Deepfakes can make epic memes or put Nicholas Cage in every movie, but they can also undermine elections. As threats of election interference mount, two teams of AI researchers have recently introduced novel approaches to identifying deepfakes by watching for evidence of heartbeats.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/ppg-cells.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/ppg-cells.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">POCO X3 NFC hands on video leaks revealing the entire design</title><link href="/POCO-X3-NFC-hands-on-video-leaks-revealing-the-entire-design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="POCO X3 NFC hands on video leaks revealing the entire design" /><published>2020-09-04T15:02:21+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:02:21+05:30</updated><id>/POCO-X3-NFC-hands-on-video-leaks-revealing-the-entire-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="/POCO-X3-NFC-hands-on-video-leaks-revealing-the-entire-design/">&lt;p&gt;POCO announced recently that the POCO X3 NFC will be launched on September 7. Ahead of the launch, a YouTuber has given us a hands-on review video of the device. The video bares all there is to know concerning the design and features of the device. Well, before it was pulled down. However, there are still images of the device grabbed from the video online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real-life design of the X3 NFC as spotted on the video by Spanish channel Tecvideos is the same with the renders of the device which appeared online earlier today. From the pictures, we can grab that the OCO X3 NFC won’t be a rebadged Xiaomi phone unlike its predecessor that was a rebranded Redmi phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone will feature a Qua-camera setup design in an X-formation along with the LED flash. At the front, the X3 NFC will pack a central hole-punch design which houses a 20MP selfie camera. The screen is a 6.67-inch LCD panel with FHD+ resolution and up to 120Hz refresh rate. There is a Corning Gorilla Glass 5 panel on top the display for protection. The phone also features a side-mounted fingerprint sensor embedded with the power button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Snapdragon 732G chipset is expected to power the model paired with 6GB RAM. There is 64GB of internal storage onboard the phone. The main camera is given as a 64MP sensor with f/1.79 aperture and support for 4K video recording at 30 fps. The phone also packs up to 5100mAh battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 of 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The POCO X3 NFC is expected to be priced around PHP10,990 ($225). It is also said to have a “Premium Version” that may likely retail for up to PHP12,990 ($265).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UP NEXT: Xiaomi Mi 10 Ultra beats Huawei P40 Pro in Camera Performance with a DxOMark score of 130&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALWAYS BE THE FIRST TO KNOW - FOLLOW US!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">POCO announced recently that the POCO X3 NFC will be launched on September 7. Ahead of the launch, a YouTuber has given us a hands-on review video of the device. The video bares all there is to know concerning the design and features of the device. Well, before it was pulled down. However, there are still images of the device grabbed from the video online.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/POCO-X3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/POCO-X3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">OnePlus 8T Specifications Leaked May Feature 120Hz AMOLED Display and Quad Rear Cameras</title><link href="/OnePlus-8T-Specifications-Leaked-May-Feature-120Hz-AMOLED-Display-and-Quad-Rear-Cameras/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OnePlus 8T Specifications Leaked May Feature 120Hz AMOLED Display and Quad Rear Cameras" /><published>2020-09-04T15:02:19+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-04T15:02:19+05:30</updated><id>/OnePlus-8T-Specifications-Leaked-May-Feature-120Hz-AMOLED-Display-and-Quad-Rear-Cameras</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OnePlus-8T-Specifications-Leaked-May-Feature-120Hz-AMOLED-Display-and-Quad-Rear-Cameras/">&lt;p&gt;OnePlus 8T specifications have leaked online just days after its alleged render surfaced in the latest Android 11 Developer Preview for the OnePlus 8 and OnePlus 8 Pro. The new OnePlus phone that is speculated to be in the works with the codename Kebab is expected to carry a 120Hz display. The OnePlus 8T is also rumoured to feature quad rear cameras, highlighted by a 48-megapixel primary shooter. OnePlus hasn’t provided any details about the new smartphone. Nevertheless, considering the company’s recent record of launching two flagship series in a year, the OnePlus 8T is likely to be the next model on its roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Citing a person familiar with the development, Android Central reports that the OnePlus 8T may come with a 120Hz AMOLED display. This is unlike the OnePlus 8 that features a display with a 90Hz refresh rate but is in line with the OnePlus 8 Pro that also features a 120Hz panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of optics, the report suggests that the OnePlus 8T may come with a quad rear camera setup that could house a 48-megapixel primary sensor, paired with a 16-megapixel wide-angle shooter. The camera setup is also expected to have a 5-megapixel sensor with a macro lens and a 2-megapixel sensor with a portrait lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presence of the 48-megapixel sensor makes the OnePlus 8T similar to the OnePlus 8 that also has a 48-megapixel primary sensor. However, Android Central says that the OnePlus 8T will come with a newer imaging sensor over what was featured on the earlier smartphone. Thus, you can expect some changes in the overall experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OnePlus 8T is also expected to run on Android 11 with OxygenOS 11 out-of-the-box. The phone is speculated to be powered by an Qualcomm Snapdragon 865+ SoC, paired with 8GB RAM and 128GB of onboard storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OnePlus isn’t likely to bring any major changes to the design of the OnePlus 8T when comparing with the OnePlus 8, as suggested by the recently surfaced render. The new model is likely to be accompanied by the OnePlus 8T Pro that could come with a 64-megapixel primary camera sensor. Both new OnePlus phones are also likely to have 65W fast charging support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OnePlus 8T launch may take place either by the end of September or in the first week of October. This matches the launch of the OnePlus 7T series that took place on September 26 last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is Nord the iPhone SE of the OnePlus world? We discussed this on Orbital, our weekly technology podcast, which you can subscribe to via Apple Podcasts, Google Podcasts, or RSS, download the episode, or just hit the play button below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">OnePlus 8T specifications have leaked online just days after its alleged render surfaced in the latest Android 11 Developer Preview for the OnePlus 8 and OnePlus 8 Pro. The new OnePlus phone that is speculated to be in the works with the codename Kebab is expected to carry a 120Hz display. The OnePlus 8T is also rumoured to feature quad rear cameras, highlighted by a 48-megapixel primary shooter. OnePlus hasn’t provided any details about the new smartphone. Nevertheless, considering the company’s recent record of launching two flagship series in a year, the OnePlus 8T is likely to be the next model on its roadmap.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/oneplus_8_first_impressions_front_1591361887033.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/04-09-2020__15/oneplus_8_first_impressions_front_1591361887033.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>