<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-23T22:39:25+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Your Next Smartphone Will Be a Lot Harder to Scratch</title><link href="/Your-Next-Smartphone-Will-Be-a-Lot-Harder-to-Scratch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your Next Smartphone Will Be a Lot Harder to Scratch" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/Your-Next-Smartphone-Will-Be-a-Lot-Harder-to-Scratch</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Your-Next-Smartphone-Will-Be-a-Lot-Harder-to-Scratch/">&lt;p&gt;It takes about two years for Corning to develop each new generation of Gorilla Glass, the resilient material that graces a critical mass of iPhone and Android devices. That process has for several update cycles focused on protecting screens against drops, fending off shatters and cracks by boosting what’s known as compressive strength. The newly announced Gorilla Glass Victus, though, gives equal weight to preventing scratches. That’s harder than it sounds, and more useful than you’d think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that Gorilla Glass has dismissed scratches entirely. But the last time Corning prioritized it as a threat was in Gorilla Glass 3, which came out all of seven years ago. Since then, smartphones have gotten much better about bouncing back from sidewalk run-ins, but handle an inadvertent key dig about the same as they did when the iPhone 5S came out. Enter Victus, which promises double the scratch resistance of 2018’s Gorilla Glass 6. It performs better in a drop test too, surviving a 2-meter fall compared to its predecessor’s 1.6m durability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scratch That Itch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to “why now” is pretty straightforward; customers started asking for it more vocally. But why it became as much of a priority as drop survivability is a more interesting question. “What we think is happening is people are keeping their phones longer,” says John Bayne, who leads Corning’s Gorilla Glass business. “Phones that aren’t breaking in a drop event are coming up with a scratch on it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s true: Apple disclosed last year that iPhone customers are upgrading less frequently. If you’re holding onto your phone for three years, that’s more time to pick up nicks and dings along the way, especially if the display survives a fall that a few years ago would have required a full screen replacement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also the fact that making glass that’s both scratch and drop resistant is, well, hard. The manufacture of glass is often a game of compromise, which you can see most clearly in the quest for durable foldable phones: the stronger it is, the less it can bend. In this case, getting those two properties to play nice is less a direct contradiction than it is a process of reinvention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The glass chemistries that people have been using to improve the compressive stress profiles aren’t necessarily the best for scratch performance,” says John Mauro, a professor of materials science and engineering at Penn State University who had previously spent 18 years at Corning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Corning, that meant starting Victus almost from … scratch. (Sorry.) Glass starts with silicon dioxide, but from there it’s open season on the periodic table of elements. “It’s really an infinite palette of options,” says Bayne. “We start with thousands of compositions, and we do a lot of computer monitoring simulation, get down to a couple dozen candidates, do some lab melts, then two or three manufacturing trials to get that ultimate glass.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The part of that journey that makes glass strong is a so-called ion exchange process, in which potassium ions shove aside smaller sodium ions; think of it like replacing the billiard balls in a rack with slightly larger tennis balls. The rack is suddenly harder to move. For seven years, Corning has been focused on squeezing more tennis balls into that rack. Victus required a different tack. “That whole science for drop, sometimes the moves that you make at the molecular level are a little bit different than you would for scratch,” says Bayne. “Our technologists were really trading off composition elements of the glass and how we ion exchange it to show a meaningful improvement.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">It takes about two years for Corning to develop each new generation of Gorilla Glass, the resilient material that graces a critical mass of iPhone and Android devices. That process has for several update cycles focused on protecting screens against drops, fending off shatters and cracks by boosting what’s known as compressive strength. The newly announced Gorilla Glass Victus, though, gives equal weight to preventing scratches. That’s harder than it sounds, and more useful than you’d think.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://media.wired.com/photos/5f18846459ee66a80b965c52/191:100/w_1280,c_limit/Gear-Glass-Knoop-Scratch-Test-2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://media.wired.com/photos/5f18846459ee66a80b965c52/191:100/w_1280,c_limit/Gear-Glass-Knoop-Scratch-Test-2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Are the Earth s magnetic poles about to swap places</title><link href="/Are-the-Earth-s-magnetic-poles-about-to-swap-places/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are the Earth s magnetic poles about to swap places" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/Are-the-Earth-s-magnetic-poles-about-to-swap-places-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Are-the-Earth-s-magnetic-poles-about-to-swap-places/">&lt;p&gt;EarthSky’s yearly crowd-funding campaign is in progress. In 2020, we are donating 8.5% to No Kids Hungry. Please donate to help us keep going, and help feed a kid!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Yael Annemiek Engbers, University of Liverpool and Andrew Biggin, University of Liverpool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep inside the Earth, liquid iron is flowing and generating the Earth’s magnetic field, which protects our atmosphere and satellites against harmful radiation from the sun. This field changes over time, and also behaves differently in different parts of the world. The field can even change polarity completely, with the magnetic north and south poles switching places. This is called a reversal and last happened 780,000 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between South America and southern Africa, there is an enigmatic magnetic region called the South Atlantic Anomaly, where the field is a lot weaker than we would expect. Weak and unstable fields are thought to precede magnetic reversals, so some have argued this feature may be evidence that we are facing one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now our new study, published June 12, 2020, in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, has uncovered how long the field in the South Atlantic has been acting up – and sheds light on whether it is something to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weak magnetic fields make us more prone to magnetic storms that have the potential to knock out electronic infrastructure, including power grids. The magnetic field of the South Atlantic Anomaly is already so weak that it can adversely affect satellites and their technology when they fly past it. The strange region is thought to be related to a patch of magnetic field that is pointing a different direction to the rest at the top of the planet’s liquid outer core at a depth of 1,795 miles (2,889 km) within the Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This “reverse flux patch” itself has grown over the last 250 years. But we don’t know whether it is simply a one-off product of the chaotic motions of the outer core fluid or rather the latest in a series of anomalies within this particular region over long time frames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it is a non-recurring feature, then its current location is not significant – it could happen anywhere, perhaps randomly. But if this is the case, the question of whether its increasing size and depth could mark the start of a new reversal remains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it is the latest in a string of features reoccurring over millions of years, however, then this would make a reversal less likely. But it would require a specific explanation for what was causing the magnetic field to act strangely in this particular place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Volcanic rocks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out, we travelled to Saint Helena – an island in the middle of the South Atlantic Ocean. This island, where Napoleon was exiled to and eventually died in 1821, is made of volcanic rocks. These originate from two separate volcanoes and were erupted from between eight million and 11.5 million years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When volcanic rocks cool down, small grains of iron-oxide in them get magnetized and therefore save the direction and strength of the Earth’s magnetic field at that time and place. We collected some of those rocks and brought them back to our lab in Liverpool, where we carried out experiments to find out what the magnetic field was like at the time of eruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our results showed us that the field at Saint Helena had very different directions throughout the time of eruption, showing us that the field in this region was much less stable than in other places. It therefore challenges the idea that the abnormality has only been around for only a few centuries. Instead, the whole region has likely been unstable on a timescale of millions of years. This implies the current situation is not as rare as some scientists had assumed, making it less likely that it represents the start of a reversal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A window into Earth’s interior&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what could explain the odd magnetic region? The liquid outer core that is generating it moves (by convection) at such high speeds that changes can occur on very short, human timescales. The outer core interacts with a layer called the mantle on top of it, which moves far slower. That means the mantle is unlikely to have changed very much in the last ten million years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From seismic waves passing through the Earth, we have some insight into the structure of the mantle. Underneath Africa there is a large feature in the lowermost mantle where the waves move extra slow through the Earth – meaning there’s most likely an unusually warm region of the lowermost mantle. This possibly causes a different interaction with the outer core at that specific location, which could explain the strange behavior of the magnetic field in the South Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of the inside of the Earth is the inner core, which is a solid ball the size of Pluto beneath the outer core. This solid feature is slowly growing, but not at the same rate everywhere. There is a possibility that it is growing faster on one side, causing a flow inside the outer core that is reaching the outer boundary with the rocky mantle just under the Atlantic hemisphere. This may be causing irregular behavior of the magnetic field on the long timescales we found on Saint Helena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are still many questions about the exact cause of the irregular behavior in the South Atlantic, this study shows us that it has been around for millions of years and is most likely a result of geophysical interactions in the Earth’s mysterious interior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yael Annemiek Engbers, Ph.D. candidate, University of Liverpool and Andrew Biggin, Professor of Palaeomagnetism, University of Liverpool&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is republished from The Conversation under a Creative Commons license. Read the original article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: Is Earth facing a magnetic pole reversal soon? Hear from the authors of a new study, on a strange anomaly that might be a clue.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">EarthSky’s yearly crowd-funding campaign is in progress. In 2020, we are donating 8.5% to No Kids Hungry. Please donate to help us keep going, and help feed a kid!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://earthsky.org/upl/2020/07/magnetic-poles-300x237.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://earthsky.org/upl/2020/07/magnetic-poles-300x237.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best and worse case scenarios for global warming are unlikely says comprehensive new study</title><link href="/Best-and-worse-case-scenarios-for-global-warming-are-unlikely-says-comprehensive-new-study/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best and worse case scenarios for global warming are unlikely says comprehensive new study" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/Best-and-worse-case-scenarios-for-global-warming-are-unlikely-says-comprehensive-new-study</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Best-and-worse-case-scenarios-for-global-warming-are-unlikely-says-comprehensive-new-study/">&lt;p&gt;The best and worst-case scenarios of global warming are unlikely to occur, according to a comprehensive new study on climate probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A prediction of 1.5-4.5C warming if atmospheric levels of carbon dioxide are doubled has been the international standard since 1979.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a new study authored by a 25-strong team of international climate scientists over four years suggests it is “extremely unlikely” that warming would stay below 2C above pre-industrial levels, and puts minimum warming at 2.3C. The likelihood of staying between 1.5C and 2C is 5 per cent, the authors say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study maintains the top temperature at 4.5C, but says some recent predictions that warming above that will be reached are also “unlikely”, with a 6-18 per cent chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A less cautious analysis by the experts puts likely warming at an even narrower range of 2.6-3.9C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A doubling of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere is predicted to happen within the next 60-80 years if current emissions are maintained. That timeline will be extended by climate action such as that agreed in the Paris Accord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One of the most worrying aspects of climate change is that it is very much a roll of the dice,” said Zeke Hausfather, one of the co-authors. “What we’ve found is that the odds of getting a one or a six is a lot less likely than we previously thought.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team behind the study have a range of expertise, and used more methods to compile their evidence than any previous study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That included looking at temperature records since the industrial revolution, estimates of prehistoric temperatures, satellite records and climate models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study is likely to now inform the next assessment by the UN’s Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change next year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">The best and worst-case scenarios of global warming are unlikely to occur, according to a comprehensive new study on climate probabilities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/content/dam/news/2020/01/16/TELEMMGLPICT000221490201_trans_NvBQzQNjv4BqpVlberWd9EgFPZtcLiMQfyf2A9a6I9YchsjMeADBa08.jpeg?impolicy=logo-overlay" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/content/dam/news/2020/01/16/TELEMMGLPICT000221490201_trans_NvBQzQNjv4BqpVlberWd9EgFPZtcLiMQfyf2A9a6I9YchsjMeADBa08.jpeg?impolicy=logo-overlay" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">China Is Ready for a Space War</title><link href="/China-Is-Ready-for-a-Space-War/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="China Is Ready for a Space War" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/China-Is-Ready-for-a-Space-War</id><content type="html" xml:base="/China-Is-Ready-for-a-Space-War/">&lt;p&gt;On this day in 1969, Americans Neil Armstrong and Edwin “Buzz” Aldrin became the first humans to walk on the moon. They were the first of a select group of Americans to be the only humans to do so. Fast forward to more recent times: in May, the world saw America return to launching American’s to space with the SpaceX launch to the International Space Station. Now, in just ten days, NASA will launch its Perseverance rover to Mars, the latest in a fleet of American vehicles on the red planet. The historic anniversary of Apollo 11 and NASA current activities remind us of both America’s dominant history as well as its current dynamism in space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under NASA Administrator Jim Bridenstine’s strong leadership, NASA’s long-awaited Commercial Crew Program (CCP) has come to fruition with the May 30 launch of two NASA astronauts to the station and subsequent successful docking—signifying America’s return to putting people into space under its own flag, and not relying on the services of others—especially countries like Russia that are strategic competitors. Moreover, this return occurs with an embrace of the dynamism of the free market. NASA is getting out of the business of putting astronauts and material into low-Earth orbit. Not only can NASA buy these services at competitive market rates from American firms, stimulating a new sector of the U.S. economy, it can now focus on its greater national priority—expanding U.S. access to deeper space—the Moon, Mars, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This represents the next generational leap for NASA—Apollo took Americans to the moon, and the space shuttle cemented American leadership in building the International Space Station—but NASA was stuck in low-earth orbit. By transitioning the earth to orbit taxi/freight business to American commercial launchers, it can now take Americans to the Moon, Mars and beyond. This major shift in NASA’s operations gets lost in media commentary, coming at the same time that China’s space program has made great strides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese announcements come frequently—plans for Chinese landers, Chinese crew on the Moon, new Chinese space launchers, Chinese plans for a space station, and an upcoming Chinese launch to Mars. It all sounds impressive—but let’s remember, as NASA has learned, it is easier to announce plans than it is to accomplish them. In considering most of China’s ambitious plans, it’s worth noting that NASA’s already done all of that—most of it decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China on the moon? Let’s look back forty years—NASA put Americans on the Moon in six crewed missions between 1969 and 1972; and is sending Americans back by 2024, with a sustained American presence on the moon through the Artemis program by 2028. Overall, more than fifty missions to the Moon have failed, including recently by an Israeli company. While talking about the Moon is easy, getting to the Moon is hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China plans for space launch? Setting aside its long history, America has revolutionized space launch in recent years through both commercial and government launchers, with SpaceX (and others working on it) re-taking the low-earth orbit launch market and building the world’s current heaviest launcher, the Falcon Heavy, and NASA building the Space Launch System which will be the heaviest still when it launches with a third more lift capability in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Chinese space station? Over twenty years, NASA evolved the U.S. space station Freedom into a U.S.-led international coalition for the $100 billion International Space Station with Russia, Japan, Canada and eleven members of the European Space Agency. The United States shouldered over half of the overall cost of building it, including thirty-six space shuttle missions. It has been continuously manned for almost twenty years (it will be twenty years in November 2020)—with 151 Americans (three times more than the next highest nation, Russia with about fifty).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Chinese Mars mission? NASA has had eight successful Mars landers/rovers (Viking I/II, Pathfinder, Spirit/Opportunity, Phoenix, Curiosity and InSight) and launched at least six successful Mars orbiters, including some which have returned exquisite science about the planet—the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO) includes the HiRISE (The High Resolution Imaging Science Experiment at the University of Arizona—the powerful HIRISE camera takes pictures that cover vast areas of Martian terrain while being able to see features as small as a kitchen table. Only two nations—the United States and the former USSR—have successfully landed a spacecraft on Mars (and the Soviet lander, Mars 3, failed twenty seconds after landing), and only four have successfully put spacecraft in orbit: the United States, the former USSR, European Space Agency and India. More than twenty-eight missions to Mars have failed—and China will try again this year, after having last tried to reach Mars in 2011. Since then, with three rovers (Spirit, Opportunity, and Curiosity) and one planned for launch in July (Perseverance), Mars has been an American frontier. Getting to Mars is hard, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA runs the most comprehensive space exploration program of the solar system, with more missions than the rest of Earth combined. For a quick survey of the solar system, NASA’s Mariner 10 and MESSENGER spacecraft are the only missions to have explored Mercury but the European Space Agency’s BepiColumbo is on its way. The United States and USSR both sent missions to explore Venus in the 1960s, 1970s, and 1980s, followed by the European Space Agency and Japan in the 2000s. Mars has largely been an American frontier not only for its rovers but for its orbiters as well, including the Odyssey, Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter, Mars Orbiter Mission, and MAVEN. America collaborative projects, Mars Express and Trace Gas Orbiter, have been successful too. Others are launching to Mars this year, with the UAE, India, and China sending missions that could join the Americans there. The only ten missions to Jupiter and Saturn have been U.S. missions, although some required the participation of the European Space Agency, and America is the only nation to send missions to Uranus and Neptune (Voyager 2) and Pluto (New Horizons).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As China is making new developments in space, NASA’s dominance in that region makes it the envy of the planet. In addition to its impressive history, NASA is currently running more than eighty-five active missions to explore the solar system, the Commercial Crew Program is now coming to fruition, it is returning Americans to the moon, and developing the hardware go to Mars. This is happening in addition to NASA’s contributions to the U.S. economy, and to education in America, both of which help make the case for continued investment in NASA and to maintain NASA’s lead over China and other strategic competitors. As China continues its progress, Americans need to remember their country’s historical, current and future dominance in space. This context is important for recalling, especially when it comes to China, that it is easier to plan a mission than it is to achieve the mission’s end goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shay Stautz ran for AZ Congressional District 2 in 2019–2020, and was the federal advocate for the University of Arizona (2006–2017), and holds an MA in National Security Studies from Georgetown University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: Reuters&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">On this day in 1969, Americans Neil Armstrong and Edwin “Buzz” Aldrin became the first humans to walk on the moon. They were the first of a select group of Americans to be the only humans to do so. Fast forward to more recent times: in May, the world saw America return to launching American’s to space with the SpaceX launch to the International Space Station. Now, in just ten days, NASA will launch its Perseverance rover to Mars, the latest in a fleet of American vehicles on the red planet. The historic anniversary of Apollo 11 and NASA current activities remind us of both America’s dominant history as well as its current dynamism in space.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://nationalinterest.org/sites/default/files/main_images/2020-06-23T000000Z_616050115_RC2REH98AOOB_RTRMADP_3_SPACE-EXPLORATION-CHINA-SATELLITE.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://nationalinterest.org/sites/default/files/main_images/2020-06-23T000000Z_616050115_RC2REH98AOOB_RTRMADP_3_SPACE-EXPLORATION-CHINA-SATELLITE.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">China launches ambitious Mars mission</title><link href="/China-launches-ambitious-Mars-mission/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="China launches ambitious Mars mission" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/China-launches-ambitious-Mars-mission</id><content type="html" xml:base="/China-launches-ambitious-Mars-mission/">&lt;p&gt;A powerful Long March 5 rocket blasted off Thursday carrying a Chinese orbiter, lander and rover on a seven-month voyage to Mars, the second of three high-stakes missions to the red planet and one that, if successful, will put China on the front lines of interplanetary exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China did not announce the launch date or time in advance, but a notice to mariners warned of an impending flight and sure enough, the Long March 5 roared to life and streaked away from the Wenchang Satellite Launch Center on Hainan Island southwest of Hong Kong at 12:41 a.m. EDT (12:41 p.m. local time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China Xinhua News announced the launch a few minutes later on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China Thursday launched its first #Mars probe on a Long March-5 rocket from the Wenchang Spacecraft Launch Site on the coast of southern China’s island province of Hainan pic.twitter.com/qTSqHUVzab — China Xinhua News (@XHNews) July 23, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation later confirmed a successful launch and said the Tianwen-1 spacecraft had been placed on the planned trajectory to Mars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get Breaking News Delivered to Your Inbox&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA Administrator Jim Bridenstine tweeted his best wishes to China:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With today’s launch, China is on its way to join the community of international scientific explorers at Mars. The United States, Europe, Russia, India, and soon the UAE will welcome you to Mars to embark on an exciting year of scientific discovery. Safe travels Tianwen-1! — Jim Bridenstine (@JimBridenstine) July 23, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight comes on the heels of the successful launch of a United Arab Emirates Mars orbiter, called Hope, from Japan on Sunday. Next up will be the launch of NASA’s $2.4 billion Perseverance Mars rover from Cape Canaveral on July 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three missions are taking advantage of a relatively short Mars launch opportunity that comes around once every 26 months when Earth and Mars are in favorable positions to permit direct flights by existing rockets. All three spacecraft are expected to reach their target next February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA’s Perseverance rover got its name from a Virginia seventh grader who won a NASA contest open to school kids across the nation. Hope refers to the UAE’s drive to develop a high-tech “knowledge-based” economy while inspiring the youth of the Middle East to pursue careers in math and science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tianwen-1’s name comes from an ancient Chinese poem and means, appropriately enough, “questions to heaven.” If all goes well, the 11,000-pound Tianwen-1 spacecraft will brake into orbit around Mars next February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Long March 5 rocket blasts off from the Wenchang Satellite Launch Center on Hainan Island Thursday carrying China’s Mars-bound Tianwen-1 spacecraft on July 23, 2020. China Xinhua News&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The orbiter is equipped with seven instruments, including high- and medium-resolution cameras; a ground-penetrating radar; a mineralogy spectrometer; a magnetometer; and two charged particle detectors. Its planned orbit around the martian poles will carry it within about 165 miles of the surface and as far away as 7,450 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After mapping the world below for several months, the orbiter will release a landing craft that will descend to a rocket-powered touchdown on a broad, 2,000-mile-wide plain known as Utopia Planitia, the same general region where NASA’s Viking 1 lander touched down in 1976.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 530-pound six-wheel rover will ride down atop the lander and then roll off extendable ramps to the surface. The rover is equipped with six instruments, including a multi-spectral camera, a terrain camera, a ground-penetrating radar, magnetic field detector, meteorology sensors and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rover is designed to receive commands and beam back data to Earth using the Tianwen-1 orbiter as a relay station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A successful landing would put China among elite company,” Mason Peck, an aerospace engineer at Cornell University, told the journal Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An artist’s impression of the Tianwen-1 lander and rover on the surface of Mars. China Global Television Network&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China has successfully sent two rovers to the moon, including one that landed on the never-before-visited far side. An attempt to send an orbiter to Mars in 2011, hitchhiking on a Russian rocket, ended in failure when the Zenit booster malfunctioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The all-Chinese Tianwen-1 mission is the nation’s most ambitious attempt yet at interplanetary exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Tianwen-1 is going to orbit, land and release a rover all on the very first try, and coordinate observations with an orbiter,” mission managers wrote in the journal Nature Astronomy. “No planetary missions have ever been implemented in this way. If successful, it would signify a major technical breakthrough.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solar-powered rover is designed to operate for at least 90 days while the design life of the orbiter is a full martian year, the equivalent of two Earth years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NASA has successfully landed eight spacecraft on the martian surface: two Vikings in 1976; the Mars Pathfinder rover in 1997; the twin Mars Exploration Rovers, Spirit and Opportunity, in 2004; the stationary Phoenix lander in 2008; the nuclear-powered Curiosity rover in 2012; and the stationary InSight lander in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;InSight and Curiosity are still operational, as are three NASA orbiters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perseverance, which is a near twin of Curiosity and four times heavier than its Chinese cousin, is the most advanced rover of them all. It is equipped with state-of-the-art cameras and instruments to search for signs of past or even present microbial life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also will deploy a small experimental helicopter — a first on Mars — and collect rock and soil samples for eventual return to Earth by a joint NASA-European Space Agency mission at the end of the decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chinese say they’re also planning a Mars sample return mission around 2030.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">A powerful Long March 5 rocket blasted off Thursday carrying a Chinese orbiter, lander and rover on a seven-month voyage to Mars, the second of three high-stakes missions to the red planet and one that, if successful, will put China on the front lines of interplanetary exploration.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cbsnews1.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2020/07/23/4839e4d8-5e3e-4be2-bc54-406e977fca10/thumbnail/1200x630/dfa592c809601d3cac5310ba88b58530/china-mars-launch-072320.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://cbsnews1.cbsistatic.com/hub/i/r/2020/07/23/4839e4d8-5e3e-4be2-bc54-406e977fca10/thumbnail/1200x630/dfa592c809601d3cac5310ba88b58530/china-mars-launch-072320.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Discovering how genetic dark matter plays a role in mental illness is just the tip of the iceberg for human health</title><link href="/Discovering-how-genetic-dark-matter-plays-a-role-in-mental-illness-is-just-the-tip-of-the-iceberg-for-human-health/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Discovering how genetic dark matter plays a role in mental illness is just the tip of the iceberg for human health" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/Discovering-how-genetic-dark-matter-plays-a-role-in-mental-illness-is-just-the-tip-of-the-iceberg-for-human-health</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Discovering-how-genetic-dark-matter-plays-a-role-in-mental-illness-is-just-the-tip-of-the-iceberg-for-human-health/">&lt;p&gt;Each cell in our bodies holds two metres of DNA that contains the six billion bits of the DNA code necessary for making a healthy human body. This is known as the human genome. It is now accepted that what makes people different, and contributes to their susceptibility to ill health, are the 6-10 million DNA differences in the human genome known to exist within the general population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A surprising fact is that only 1.7% of these 6 billion bits of code represent the genes that make proteins. Proteins are the physical building blocks of our bodies and are essential to keep us healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though huge strides have been made in mapping the DNA differences associated with mental health conditions such as depression, schizophrenia and chronic anxiety thanks to the sequencing of the human genome, what surprised many was the discovery that over 98% of these DNA changes lay within the dark and mysterious remainder of the human genome that did not make protein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This part of the genome had been largely dismissed as the “junk” genome but, because of its importance to health, is now known as “the non-coding genome”. Critically, we don’t yet fully understand what type of information is contained in the non-coding genome that is so essential for human health and how DNA differences change this information result in ill-health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Useful junk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand how the non-coding genome supports health it may be helpful to think of the human body as a vast and extremely complex community of different cells. Which means the identity of a cell, and its ability to communicate effectively with other cells, is essential for normal human development and health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this assumption, many scientists have suggested that although genes contain the information to make cells, the information required to allow these cells to communicate and organise into tissues resides in the non-coding genome. Incredibly, recent estimates suggest that the human non-coding genome contains over five times more information critical to health than that which is contained within genes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now know that much of the information in the non-coding genome is in the form of “gene switch” sequences (also known as promoters and enhancers) that control the levels that genes are turned on in specific cells and in response to specific signals. It is highly likely that these switches, by responding to signals travelling between cells, are responsible for coordinating the cell-to-cell interactions required to form the structure and function of organs such as the brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, identifying these switches and their function in specific cells has been challenging. Being able to easily identify and understand these gene switches, and the effects of ill-health-inducing DNA differences on their activity, will be critical to fully understanding the genetic basis of mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alcohol and anxiety&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been known for some time that a number of genes are responsible for regulating behaviours such as alcohol intake and mood. Disappointingly, analysis of these genes in the human population has failed to identify changes in the DNA of these genes that were strongly associated with disorders such as alcohol abuse and chronic anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in collaboration with Andrew McIntosh at the University of Edinburgh, our research looked to determine what controlled the very specific expression of neuropeptides (chemical signals) in parts of the brain where they are essential to controlling normal mood and alcohol intake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We noticed that the specific cell types in which many of these genes were switched on were shared by many different species. For example, the gene that produces the alcohol intake and mood-controlling galanin peptide was turned on in very specific regions of the hypothalamus and amygdala – parts of the brain that control appetite and mood in mice, rats and humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reasoned that the sequences of the gene switches that controlled this expression would also be very similar between these species. So we used powerful computers that lined up the DNA sequences of more than 100 vertebrate species and found that a non-protein-coding DNA sequence, next to the galanin gene, had changed very little through evolution, suggesting its importance for survival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using CRISPR genome editing, a process that allows us to make targeted deletions in the DNA of mice, we deleted this sequence from the mouse genome and found that the galanin gene was switched off in these mice. Surprisingly, we also found that mice lacking this switch drank less ethanol and that male mice had reduced fear. The most important observation was that the switch contained DNA differences in the human population that altered its activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our research showed that one of the differences could be linked to alcohol abuse and anxiety in men in the UK Biobank human genetic cohort which mirrored our observations in mice. This study was recently published in the academic journal Molecular Psychiatry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that our ability to quickly and accurately identify the functional components of the non-coding human genome, and how they can go wrong to contribute to susceptibility to mental health conditions, is just the tip of the iceberg in terms of human health. Which means the same principles used in our studies can be applied for other diseases such as cancer, cardiovascular disease, Type 2 diabetes and susceptibility to Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is even evidence that the activity of these gene switches can be affected by life events such as childhood deprivation known to affect disease susceptibility through an epigenetic process known as DNA-methylation – epigenetics being the study of biological mechanisms that switch genes on and off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has never been a more exciting time to be in genetics and it is hoped that the exploration of the “dark matter” of the non-coding genome will bring tremendous benefits in terms of being able to diagnose susceptibilities to mental health disorders and other conditions and help us develop new, more personalised treatments.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Each cell in our bodies holds two metres of DNA that contains the six billion bits of the DNA code necessary for making a healthy human body. This is known as the human genome. It is now accepted that what makes people different, and contributes to their susceptibility to ill health, are the 6-10 million DNA differences in the human genome known to exist within the general population.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.theconversation.com/files/348879/original/file-20200722-24-1bu07ru.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;rect=4%2C74%2C994%2C497&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.theconversation.com/files/348879/original/file-20200722-24-1bu07ru.jpg?ixlib=rb-1.1.0&amp;rect=4%2C74%2C994%2C497&amp;q=45&amp;auto=format&amp;w=1356&amp;h=668&amp;fit=crop" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Much Will the Planet Warm if Carbon Dioxide Levels Double</title><link href="/How-Much-Will-the-Planet-Warm-if-Carbon-Dioxide-Levels-Double/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Much Will the Planet Warm if Carbon Dioxide Levels Double" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/How-Much-Will-the-Planet-Warm-if-Carbon-Dioxide-Levels-Double-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/How-Much-Will-the-Planet-Warm-if-Carbon-Dioxide-Levels-Double/">&lt;p&gt;How much, exactly, will greenhouse gases heat the planet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more than 40 years, scientists have expressed the answer as a range of possible temperature increases, between 1.5 and 4.5 degrees Celsius, that will result from carbon dioxide levels doubling from preindustrial times. Now, a team of researchers has sharply narrowed the range of temperatures, tightening it to between 2.6 and 4.1 degrees Celsius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steven Sherwood, a climate scientist at the University of New South Wales in Sydney, Australia, and an author of the new report said that the group’s research suggested that these temperature shifts, which are referred to as “climate sensitivity” because they reflect how sensitive the planet is to rising carbon dioxide levels, are now unlikely below the low end of the range. The research also suggests that the “alarmingly high sensitivities” of 5 degrees Celsius or higher are less likely, though they are “not impossible,” Dr. Sherwood said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What remains, however, is still an array of effects that mean worldwide disaster if emissions are not sharply reduced in coming years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Masahiro Watanabe, a professor in the atmosphere and ocean research institute at the University of Tokyo and an author of the report, said that determining an accurate range of temperatures was critically important for international efforts to address global warming, like the Paris climate agreement, and for mitigating the effects of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">How much, exactly, will greenhouse gases heat the planet?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/07/22/climate/22CLI-GLOBALTEMPS-sub/22CLI-GLOBALTEMPS-sub-facebookJumbo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2020/07/22/climate/22CLI-GLOBALTEMPS-sub/22CLI-GLOBALTEMPS-sub-facebookJumbo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to See Comet Neowise Before It s Gone</title><link href="/How-to-See-Comet-Neowise-Before-It-s-Gone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to See Comet Neowise Before It s Gone" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/How-to-See-Comet-Neowise-Before-It-s-Gone</id><content type="html" xml:base="/How-to-See-Comet-Neowise-Before-It-s-Gone/">&lt;p&gt;In late March, a team of astronomers working on a space telescope mission called Neowise discovered a comet booking it past the sun, 160 million miles away from Earth. The comet, officially known as C/2020 F3 but usually just referred to as Neowise, is a 3-mile-wide chunk of ice and dust on a 6,000-year loop around the solar system. It’s just one of thousands of space rocks discovered with the Neowise telescope, but its trajectory means that for a few weeks this summer it will give observers in the northern hemisphere a rare cosmic light show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the most impressive-looking comet that I have seen since the 1990s with Hale-Bopp,” says George Hripcsak, an amateur astronomer in New York City. Hale-Bopp is a comet on a 2,500-year orbit around the sun that made its closest pass by Earth in 1997. It was visible to the naked eye for a year and a half, and famously inspired the mass suicide of the Heaven’s Gate cult. (Although comet Neowise isn’t quite as bright as Hale-Bopp was, it also doesn’t appear to have prompted any human sacrifices.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best time to catch a glimpse of Neowise was in early July, just after it made its closest approach to the sun and reached peak brightness. The comet has grown noticeably dimmer over the past few days as it moves away from the sun, but if you haven’t had a chance to check it out yet, it’s not too late. Neowise makes its closest approach to the Earth on Thursday, and if you live in the northern hemisphere you’ll still be able to see it with your naked eye for a few more days. We asked amateur astronomers for their best tips on how to go comet-spotting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to Look For&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all comets, Neowise consists of a dense nucleus made of ice, dust, and ionized gas that form a brilliant double tail as they blow off the comet. The Neowise tail is huge; it covers as much sky as if you were to place 12 full moons side by side. “Seeing a tail that long doesn’t happen very often,” says Hripcsak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When to See Comet Neowise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to spot the comet, the best time to go stargazing is about an hour after sunset. Depending on where you live, this will probably be around 10 pm. The comet will be visible for about an hour or so before it drops below the horizon. “It needs to be dark enough for you to be able to pick out the entire Big Dipper, not just the handle,” says Katherine Troche, an amateur astronomer in New York City. “If you can get away from the streetlights, your visibility will improve, but you may still need binoculars as the comet will become less bright over the next few weeks.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to Spot the Comet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comet Neowise is visible from anywhere in the northern hemisphere. But the night sky is a pretty big space to search, so amateur and professional astronomers have built a number of apps to help you find celestial objects, including the comet, based on your location. If you want to stargaze like the pros, there’s SkySafari 6 for iOS and Android phones, but it’ll set you back $20. Free apps include Celestron’s SkyPortal.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">In late March, a team of astronomers working on a space telescope mission called Neowise discovered a comet booking it past the sun, 160 million miles away from Earth. The comet, officially known as C/2020 F3 but usually just referred to as Neowise, is a 3-mile-wide chunk of ice and dust on a 6,000-year loop around the solar system. It’s just one of thousands of space rocks discovered with the Neowise telescope, but its trajectory means that for a few weeks this summer it will give observers in the northern hemisphere a rare cosmic light show.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://media.wired.com/photos/5f177affee4adf9eae61d0fc/191:100/w_1280,c_limit/Science_neowise_1227542003.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://media.wired.com/photos/5f177affee4adf9eae61d0fc/191:100/w_1280,c_limit/Science_neowise_1227542003.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">It s Possible to Grow Radishes on the Moon Finds NASA Scientist</title><link href="/It-s-Possible-to-Grow-Radishes-on-the-Moon-Finds-NASA-Scientist/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It s Possible to Grow Radishes on the Moon Finds NASA Scientist" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/It-s-Possible-to-Grow-Radishes-on-the-Moon-Finds-NASA-Scientist</id><content type="html" xml:base="/It-s-Possible-to-Grow-Radishes-on-the-Moon-Finds-NASA-Scientist/">&lt;p&gt;In these days of social distancing, some of us learned how to bake bread, some of us cake, but with the moon projects at stake, however; NASA scientist Max Coleman meddles with desert soil in his kitchen to develop a way to grow radishes on the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEE ALSO: LUNAR FACTS: THE MOON IS AN ODD AND FASCINATING PLACE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, the plan sounds like something out of the movie script of “The Martian”. Coleman went with radishes because these bad boys vegetate rather quickly. This is important because on the moon, days and nights last 14 Earth days each. Coleman also said, “They have been used before in space, and they germinate very, very fast,” in the press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the COVID-19 breakout, Coleman and his team of 12 had to postpone on-site tests of the sensors planned for moon mission use. The team now works remotely from home, during one of their video meetings Coleman pondered how they could vegetate radishes on the moon. He had the idea of doing some tests with no nutrient soil and soil with a small amount of nutrients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some discussion, Coleman went “Let’s not theorize about this; why don’t we just do it!” and ordered radish seeds along with desert sand, which is closest you can get to no-nutrient on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to handle feeding the astronauts with as little material as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We want to do one tiny step in that direction, to show that lunar soil contains stuff which can be extracted from it as nutrients for plants,” Coleman said, and added, “this includes getting the right chemical elements to allow plants to make chlorophyll and grow cell walls.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radishes are renowned for their little water need, still, to Coleman’s surprise the less he watered them the more successful radishes were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the properties of the moon are a tad bit different from Earth, Coleman concluded; “We can’t properly test here on Earth with perfect lunar soil, but we’re doing as much here as we can. Then we want to show that it actually does work on the Moon.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">In these days of social distancing, some of us learned how to bake bread, some of us cake, but with the moon projects at stake, however; NASA scientist Max Coleman meddles with desert soil in his kitchen to develop a way to grow radishes on the moon.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://inteng-storage.s3.amazonaws.com/img/iea/Lg6E8LpaGN/sizes/radish-sprouts_md.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://inteng-storage.s3.amazonaws.com/img/iea/Lg6E8LpaGN/sizes/radish-sprouts_md.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Planetary Researchers Surprised to Find a Ring of Fire on Venus</title><link href="/Planetary-Researchers-Surprised-to-Find-a-Ring-of-Fire-on-Venus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Planetary Researchers Surprised to Find a Ring of Fire on Venus" /><published>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/Planetary-Researchers-Surprised-to-Find-a-Ring-of-Fire-on-Venus</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Planetary-Researchers-Surprised-to-Find-a-Ring-of-Fire-on-Venus/">&lt;p&gt;ETH researchers used computer simulations to classify the current activity of corona structures on the surface of Venus. To their surprise, they found a previously undiscovered ring of fire on our neighboring planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago, planetary researchers discovered unusual circular structures on the surface of Venus when observing high-​resolution images from NASA’s Magellan mission. Such structures are known as coronae (from the Latin meaning “crowns”; singular: corona). A few years ago, a team of ETH researchers led by Taras Gerya, Professor of Geophysics at the Department of Earth Sciences, used computer models to investigate how these structures may have formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most researchers assume that these odd circular surface features are formed by mantle plumes from deep within the planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mantle plume is an upwelling of hot, molten rock that is transported by convection currents from the lower mantle to the crust in a column that widens in a mushroom-​shape at the top. The heat it carries melts the surface of the crust in a circular form. Continuous material rising from greater depths widens the plume head and expands the ring structure on the surface to form a corona. The solid crust surrounding the mantle plume may crack and ultimately sink below the edge of the corona, triggering local tectonic processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer simulations of structural variations of coronae&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the topography of coronae is by no means homogeneous or easy to describe. “These structures exist in a large variety of shapes and dimensions on the Venusian surface,” says Anna Gülcher, a doctoral student in Gerya’s research group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following up on this observation, Gülcher used a larger set of improved 3D simulations to re-​examine the coronae as she sought to establish a link between the variation in surface topography and the processes at work beneath. Her study was recently published in the journal Nature Geoscience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new simulations show that a corona’s topography depends on the thickness and strength of the crust where the mantle plume strikes it and, above all, that their topographies are directly related to how active the column of magma beneath the surface is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note, however, that the position and dynamics of Earth’s ring of fire are the result of plate tectonics, she explains. On Venus, the cause is vertical hotspot volcanism—a phenomenon that occurs in only a few places on Earth, such as below the Hawaiian Islands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly why the mantle plumes on Venus are arranged in such a belt, and what this means for deep interior processes on Venus, is an important question to address in future studies, Gülcher says. This may be done with large-​scale computer simulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge computing capacity required&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their models, the researchers simulate only the very top few hundred kilometers of the mantle plume. In reality, however, the plume conduits could be over 1,000 kilometers long: “Simulating the total length the plumes could reach is out of the question because of the huge computing capacity it would require,” Gülcher says. The current simulations, performed using the Euler cluster at ETH, are already eight times larger than previous ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The planetary scientists hope that their findings will also provide fresh insights into how mantle plumes function below the surface of the Earth. They are likely to be what causes hotspot volcanism, as seen in the Hawaiian Islands. Mantle plumes may have been a trigger for plate tectonics observed on Earth as well, as Gerya’s research group was also able to simulate. As mentioned at the time, Venus could serve as a model for the processes that may have taken place in Earth’s early history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Active plumes form a ring of fire around Venus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This salient observation enabled Gülcher and her colleagues to classify over a hundred of large coronae on Venus into two main groups: those that have formed above an active plume that is currently rising and carrying molten material, and those above a plume that has cooled and become inactive. “Every corona structure has a specific signature that indicates what is going on beneath it,” Gülcher says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a map of Venus, she plotted all the coronae according to how their activity was classified. To her surprise, most of the coronae overlying active mantle plumes form a belt in Venus’ southern hemisphere. Only a handful of active plumes are located outside this band. “We called this band the ‘Ring of Fire’ on Venus in reference to the ‘Ring of Fire’ on Earth,” Gülcher says. She assumes that the belt coincides with a zone that expels high levels of rising plume material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on this research, read Scientists Identify 37 Active Volcanoes on Venus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reference: “Corona structures driven by plume–lithosphere interactions and evidence for ongoing plume activity on Venus” by Anna J. P. Gülcher, Taras V. Gerya, Laurent G. J. Montési and Jessica Munch, 20 July 2020, Nature Geoscience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DOI: 10.1038/s41561-020-0606-1&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">ETH researchers used computer simulations to classify the current activity of corona structures on the surface of Venus. To their surprise, they found a previously undiscovered ring of fire on our neighboring planet.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://scitechdaily.com/images/Venus-Planet.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://scitechdaily.com/images/Venus-Planet.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>