<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-13T09:42:28+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Bank of America: Solana Could Become The Visa of Crypto</title><link href="/Bank-of-America-Solana-Could-Become-The-Visa-of-Crypto/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bank of America: Solana Could Become The Visa of Crypto" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:37+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:37+00:00</updated><id>/Bank-of-America-Solana-Could-Become-The-Visa-of-Crypto</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Bank-of-America-Solana-Could-Become-The-Visa-of-Crypto/">&lt;p&gt;Alkesh Shah – analyst at Bank of America – predicted Solana could continue to steal some of Ethereum’s market share as it’s easy to use and has significantly lower transaction fees. The strategist further asserted that Solana could become “the Visa” of the cryptocurrency industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High Hopes for Solana&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solana has been one of the top-performing cryptocurrency projects in the past 12 months. Its native token has increased its USD value by nearly 4,300% in one year and is currently sitting as the fifth-largest digital asset with a market capitalization of roughly $50 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this significant advancement, the protocol could reach new heights soon, Alkesh Shah from Bank of America opined. He argued that Solana is superior to some of its rivals as it offers low transaction costs and enhanced scalability relative. Moreover, it utilizes both proof-of-stake and proof-of-history technology, granting it further advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to its differentiated design, Solana could take market share away from Ethereum, Shah said. It is worth noting that the latter is still functioning under the proof-of-work mechanism. Ethereum transactions per second are also considerably slower than Solana’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These innovations allow for the processing of an industry-leading ~65,000 transactions per second with average transaction fees of $0.00025 while remaining relatively decentralized and secure,” Shah said regarding Solana’s speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, the analyst made the bold prediction that the fifth-biggest cryptocurrency project could one day serve as “the Visa of the digital asset ecosystem.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ADVERTISEMENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He explained this could occur because the protocol successfully facilitates micropayments. It also plays a vital role in the gaming and non-fungible token universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solana Could Be The Next Bitcoin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Founder of the cryptocurrency exchange FTX – Sam Bankman-Fried – is also a keen proponent of the blockchain project. Not long ago, he said Solana had “a real shot” at becoming the next most dominant digital asset project because of its speed of scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another advantage that Solana has is the fact that it is green-focused. According to a recent report, it is actually less harmful to the environment than the web browsing giant Google. The statement estimated that two Google searches consume more energy than one transaction on the Solana network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does not end there. A single transaction on Solana consumes 24 times less energy than charging a mobile phone. In fact, the project’s network uses around 3,186,000 kWh per year, which is equivalent to the average electricity usage of 986 households in the USA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">Alkesh Shah – analyst at Bank of America – predicted Solana could continue to steal some of Ethereum’s market share as it’s easy to use and has significantly lower transaction fees. The strategist further asserted that Solana could become “the Visa” of the cryptocurrency industry.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/SolanaRace.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/SolanaRace.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Currency central: The future of money</title><link href="/Currency-central-The-future-of-money/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Currency central: The future of money" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:36+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:36+00:00</updated><id>/Currency-central-The-future-of-money</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Currency-central-The-future-of-money/">&lt;p&gt;The conclusion of the experiment was more than satisfactory. A report detailing the findings co-authored by SAMA and CBUAE and released recently said, “The project confirmed that DLT can provide central banks the ability to reimagine both domestic and cross-border payment systems in new ways,” and then added, “We are pleased by the promising results, insights, and learnings described in this report and trust that they will benefit the central banking community and broader financial ecosystem in visualising the potential of this new technology to transform the GCC (Gulf Cooperation Council) financial markets and indeed our industry.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the process, both the UAE and Saudi Arabia, renewed the spotlight on a new trend sweeping the global financial sector and at the same time contributed to the learning quotient on CBDCs. They are part of a growing list of 90 countries engaged in various stages of rolling out the CBDC — which is nothing but virtual money backed by a country’s central bank. These include Sweden, South Korea and Cambodia who have launched pilots and countries like Brazil, China, the United States and India who have signalled their intent. Together, they are creating the quotient of experiences to ready for the launch a CBDC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, first off the blocks was the Eastern Caribbean Central Bank, which rolled out its pilot in April last year and, then, in early December 2021 they extended it to two more islands, Dominica and Montserrat. DCash, the name of their CBDC, was launched in the islands of Antigua and Barbuda, Grenada, Saint Kitts and Nevis, and Saint Lucia. Other central banks are keen, but are yet take the plunge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question, then, is why is there a sudden surge in interest among central banks all over the world about a CBDC? The obvious logic from the outside looking in is the growing popularity of decentralised currencies like a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;crypto currency. The USP of crypto currencies in offering frictionless transactions — particularly those involving cross-border transactions like remittances and simultaneously solving for trust (the sine qua non of any central bank currency) through the use of a transparent mechanism like blockchain — is offering an alternative currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, private currencies are poised to compete with fiat currencies. This is something that could potentially upend the world of finance. Presumably central banks would prefer to be part of the solution, in ensuring frictionless payments at low or no costs to consumers by tapping the same tech — and thereby stay ahead of potential competition. All the more since banning a crypto currency in a new world order where money in the form of code does not recognise geography is hardly an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressing a recent webinar hosted by the Vidhi Centre for Legal Policy on the CBDC, Reserve Bank of India (RBI) Deputy Governor T Rabi Sankar very candidly admitted as much. “It is not clear what specific need is met by these private VCs (virtual currencies) that official money cannot meet as efficiently, but that may in itself not come in the way of their adoption. If these VCs gain recognition, national currencies with limited convertibility are likely to come under threat,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Blockchain Logic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to keep in mind that the one aspect that is common to both CBDC and cryptocurrency is the underlying technology: blockchain. In short, blockchain is the driver of this disruption, and cryptocurrency is just an example of its application. The technology can be used for a host of services, including the delivering of social benefits like pensions, poverty-relief packages and unemployment benefits. Among other things, it will eliminate leakages due to corruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The geeky definition, sourced from IBM, is: “It (blockchain) is a shared, immutable ledger that facilitates the process of recording transactions and tracking assets in a business network. An asset can be tangible (a house, car, cash, land) or intangible (intellectual property, patents, copyrights, branding).”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key terms are shared, ledger and asset. Essentially, the technology enables the inter-linking of a secure computer network to transact business where every entity who is part of it has equal knowledge about every leg of the transaction. Exactly why it is also often referred to as decentralised computing — DeFi or decentralised finance — is nothing but a blockchain application in finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a utopian world in which everyone knows what is going on. Information is power, not by withholding it but by sharing it with every stakeholder. So, at one level, it becomes that much more difficult to pull off scams without the cover of anonymity. What this very obviously does is reduce traditional risks associated with a business transaction and, of course, usher in the cost efficiencies. And unlike in a centralised system, there is no single point vulnerability in the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, it is prone to cyber-attacks. Nonetheless scores of crypto currencies have started to emerge. From less than ten a few years ago, a guesstimate pegs them at just under 8,000 at present. They are applying blockchain benefits, efficiency and accuracy to the business of information — the one factor influencing competitiveness. As IBM succinctly explains the benefits: “The faster it’s received and the more accurate it is, the better.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the definition of blockchain based on a shared digital network mentioned earlier, a cryptocurrency is a digital currency created by a private entity — who issues a token, which then becomes the currency; Facebook, for instance, is calling its token Diem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the time when private currencies existed, before they were replaced by sovereign currencies. Exactly the reason why cryptocurrency is seen as a threat to central bank currencies world over. Especially ‘stablecoin’ — one of the popular crypto currencies — which mimics an official currency as its value is pegged to a reserve asset which can either be the US dollar or gold: thereby it is less susceptible to volatility, something that is the norm with most of the tokens in circulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike in the case of a cryptocurrency, a CBDC is based on a private blockchain network and is essentially like an Intranet. In effect, it will be like creating a PDF version of a print magazine: the form is different but will not do anything more than a fiat currency which is physical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cryptocurrency, on the other hand, employs a public blockchain network, which allows for decentralised computing — something that is very similar to the worldwide Internet architecture. As David Wessel, senior fellow and director, The Hutchins Center on Fiscal and Monetary Policy, Brookings Institution, pointed out during a recent webinar, a cryptocurrency combines network theory (which promotes efficiency), gain theory (creates incentives through issue of tokens like bitcoins for all the participants in the transaction) and cryptography (which ensures security).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is these foundations that are posing a threat to fiat currencies issued by central banks, which is exactly why they are moving quickly to plug the efficiency gap faced by central currencies, especially with cross-border transactions entailing exports and imports. Any trade financed by a CBDC will be settled in real time as it is a fiat and won’t need to go through the rigour of inter-bank settlements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was also established by Project Aber initiated jointly by Saudi Arabia and the UAE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tipping Point in Global Finance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subtext of this seeming faceoff between crypto currencies and the CBDC is as Eswar Prasad, Senior Fellow, Brookings Institution, explained in his just released book The Future of Money, a tipping point in global finance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The era of cash is drawing to an end and that of Central Bank digital currencies has begun. Money, banking, and finance are on the verge of transformation. Physical money is becoming a relic. The digital payment system is becoming the norm around the world. Banking is going to change as other forms of financial intermediation gain prominence. Much of the world’s population will gain access to at least basic financial services, improving lines and economic forecasts,” he writes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, several countries in the developing world are already pushing the envelope, especially in enabling financial inclusion and real-time payments. In fact, several of them are ahead of the developed countries like the United States in FinTech innovation. While M-Pesa in Kenya enables a mobiles-based money transfer, Unified Payments Interface (UPI) from India and the most recent launch of PIX, the real-time payments from Brazil, offer similar and efficient solutions. All of them are also forcing a shift in consumer behaviour, the death of the leather wallet as it were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India’s UPI, for example, is capable of solving any denomination payment (including for one rupee) and a large volume of transactions. At the moment, UPI’s use is growing exponentially and averaging about 2-3 billion transactions a month — but this transactional efficiency can be scaled, if required, to 2 billion a day. In fact, in value terms, UPI was just shy of logging a record $1 trillion worth of transactions in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The proposed digital rupee to be issued by the RBI can instantly leverage the growing UPI platform to reach 200 million users — a difficult target for any country to match. This could popularise the use of CBDC and enable the Reserve Bank of India reach critical mass in quick time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addressing the seminar hosted by Brookings, Prasad framed this competition between&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the CBDC and crypto currencies favourably. Something where the two systems may actually complement each other and creating a win-win for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is important in my view is really a new era of competition that could ultimately benefit both consumers and businesses, but it’s going to be in the form of digital payments of various sorts. And this is going to be good not just for consumers and businesses within economies, but cross-border payments where there are a lot of frictions that affect, say, economic migrants sending any money back home, exporters and importers. All of these barriers are going to become much less significant impediments to the flow of finance.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anil Padmanabhan is a journalist based in New Delhi&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">The conclusion of the experiment was more than satisfactory. A report detailing the findings co-authored by SAMA and CBUAE and released recently said, “The project confirmed that DLT can provide central banks the ability to reimagine both domestic and cross-border payment systems in new ways,” and then added, “We are pleased by the promising results, insights, and learnings described in this report and trust that they will benefit the central banking community and broader financial ecosystem in visualising the potential of this new technology to transform the GCC (Gulf Cooperation Council) financial markets and indeed our industry.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/220115062532OJQJ.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/220115062532OJQJ.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Keep This ETF in Your Back Pocket to Fight Off Inflation</title><link href="/Keep-This-ETF-in-Your-Back-Pocket-to-Fight-Off-Inflation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keep This ETF in Your Back Pocket to Fight Off Inflation" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:34+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:34+00:00</updated><id>/Keep-This-ETF-in-Your-Back-Pocket-to-Fight-Off-Inflation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Keep-This-ETF-in-Your-Back-Pocket-to-Fight-Off-Inflation/">&lt;p&gt;Global inflation continues to weigh on the minds of investors, which is why having diversified exposure to alternative assets is a must in order to fend off inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One alternative is bitcoin, which has had a roller coaster ride over the past few months. After reaching an all-time high in November 2021, the leading cryptocurrency has fallen below $50,000 after seeing upwards of $69,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, it can still serve as an inflationary hedge given its bullish 2021. If bitcoin can see a return to form towards the upside, it can serve a purpose in any portfolio, particularly if the goal is to mitigate inflation risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like commodities, used as a complementary investment to a portfolio of stocks and bonds,” a ProShares market outlook for 2022 notes. “Particularly because of its fixed supply, bitcoin is also often viewed as a hedge against inflationary pressures.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Barriers to invest in the asset class have previously been high and included the use of unregulated exchanges or wallets,” the outlook adds further, noting in a chart below that it has vastly outperformed stocks and bonds. “However, recent innovations—including bitcoin-linked ETFs—have made exposure to bitcoin more attainable for the average investor. Bitcoin is volatile and relatively uncorrelated with traditional asset classes, so a modest allocation may go a long way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accessible Bitcoin Exposure Sans the Volatility&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Bitcoin has become less volatile over the years as its popularity as an investment vehicle grows, investing directly in the cryptocurrency still isn’t for the weak at heart. That’s where the ProShares Bitcoin ETF (BITO) comes into play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the ProShares market outlook mentions, ETFs linked to the leading cryptocurrency can make the digital currency more accessible to investors. Furthermore, investing directly in the digital asset on a public exchange opens potential hacking risks, as the ProShares outlook also notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, as opposed to directly investing in the cryptocurrency itself, another way to get alternate exposure to bitcoin is to play its future price increases. As such, ETF investors may want to play on this bullish notion with Proshares’ BITO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors who can’t stomach the volatility that’s hit bitcoin as of late but still want alternative asset exposure to the leading cryptocurrency may want to give the fund a closer look. Additionally, bitcoin’s price of just over $40,000 (as of January 14) may not fit everyone’s budget, but BITO can provide alternate exposure at a lower price of entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more news, information, and strategy, visit the Crypto Channel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">Global inflation continues to weigh on the minds of investors, which is why having diversified exposure to alternative assets is a must in order to fend off inflation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/Keep-This-ETF-in-Your-Back-Pocket-to-Fight-Off-Inflation.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/Keep-This-ETF-in-Your-Back-Pocket-to-Fight-Off-Inflation.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Money: back to the future</title><link href="/Money-back-to-the-future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Money: back to the future" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:33+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:33+00:00</updated><id>/Money-back-to-the-future</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Money-back-to-the-future/">&lt;p&gt;The continuing process of digitalisation of the world’s financial system as well as the move away from cash during the pandemic are raising existential questions about the future of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newsletter from 14 January 2022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write this newsletter from Belfast, where the DeLorean sports car – most famous for having been used as Marty McFly’s time machine in the Back to the Future movies – was manufactured. I invite you to join me in a DeLorean time machine as we travel back and forth across decades to see what money was like in the recent past and what it may be like in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to 2000. I taught my very first lecture at Queen’s University Belfast that year. The topic was money and the debate in class focused on the possibility and merits of a futuristic cashless society. That year more than three-quarters of total payments were made in cash. Other payments were made using cheques, direct debits and credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The arrival of the ATM (automated teller machine) in 1967 had revolutionised banking and payments by making cash much easier to access. According to LINK, there were about 31,500 ATMs scattered across the UK in 2000, which was a 75% increase from one decade earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we fast-forward to 2010, two major things had changed in the realm of money as highlighted in my Economics Observatory article on the lessons from history for digital currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, chip-and-pin and contactless payment cards had been introduced in 2003 and 2007 respectively. Despite these innovations, cash was still being used in 65% of payments in 2010 and the number of ATMs had doubled since 2000 to just over 63,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Bitcoin – the world’s first cryptocurrency – had been introduced to the world several months after (and partly as a response to) the global financial crisis of 2007-09.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his Observatory article on Bitcoin and other digital currencies, William Quinn (Queen’s University Belfast) provides a good introduction to the cryptocurrency and explains its advantages and disadvantages compared with traditional currencies. He suggests that the advantages of Bitcoin are few (if any), while the disadvantages include its costliness as a medium of exchange and its poor store-of-value property, which arises from its very high volatility, as Figure 1 shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 1: Price of Bitcoin (US dollars), December 2016 to January 2022&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: Blockchain.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next stop in our time machine takes us back to 2020. In this world, we see how the innovations of the previous decade have transformed money. To begin with, cash use has shrivelled to a mere 17% of all payments and the number of ATMs in the UK has fallen sharply from a high of 70,588 in 2015 to 54,574.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trend was well under way before Covid-19, but as the Observatory article by Bernardo Bátiz-Lazo (Northumbria University) and Manual Bautista-González (Columbia University) illustrates, the pandemic has accelerated the move towards a cashless society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pandemic has also seen increased interest in Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies, with over 4,000 different cryptocurrencies now in circulation. Meme cryptocurrencies, such as Shiba Inu or Dogecoin, became very popular with the general public during 2020 and into 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his Observatory article on Dogecoin, Andrew Urquhart (University of Reading) describes how this meme cryptocurrency works and explains how it became one of the world’s largest. In terms of market value, Dogecoin and Shiba Inu are the 12th and 14th largest cryptocurrencies, with market values of $21.7 billion and $16.5 billion respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pandemic has also witnessed increased speculation in cryptocurrencies as retail investors have poured their savings into all things crypto. This has resulted in very steep rises in the prices of cryptocurrencies. Figure 2 shows the appreciation in price between the start of 2020 and the end of 2021 of the three largest cryptocurrencies, as well as the two largest meme cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Figure 2: Appreciation in the prices of leading cryptocurrencies between the start of 2020 and the end of 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: Coinmarketcap.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: The appreciation in Shiba Inu is from 2 August 2020; the scale is logarithmic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as rising dramatically over the past two years, cryptocurrency prices have also been very volatile, as illustrated by the price of Bitcoin in Figure 1. In his Observatory article, William Quinn explores the main drivers of changes in the price of Bitcoin, suggesting that the price is largely determined by three things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, large holders, known as ‘whales’, who have the ability to manipulate the market and move the price of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, news coverage and discussion of cryptocurrencies on social media brings in new naïve investors who buy Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies, which in turn drives up prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, the number of Tether stablecoins that have been issued. Although the price of Bitcoin is usually reported in dollars, Tether is the main currency for buying Bitcoin. It is an on- and off-ramp for Bitcoin investors, in other words, a vehicle for helping investors convert fiat currencies into Bitcoin and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stablecoins, such as Tether or USD Coin, have grown in popularity from the beginning of 2020. The market capitalisation of Tether, for example, has grown from $4.11 billion at the start of 2020 to $78.43 billion at the end of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The volatility of cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin has undermined any claim that they are money or have money-like properties. Stablecoins, on the other hand, have a stable value because they are convertible one-for-one into US dollars or a basket of currencies. As I point out in my Observatory article, this makes most stablecoins akin to bank money. But the difference is that banks are regulated, and their deposits are underwritten by insurance and government guarantees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2030&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the flux capacitor in our DeLorean has enough power to get us to 2030, what might we see when we go to the shops and cafes and walk down the high street?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ATMs are much less common. Cash is used for a small number of purchases and mainly by the poor and old. Government policy has attempted to slow down the march towards the cashless society and to ensure that citizens are not excluded from the digital payments system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cash is still the back-up means of payment for many because global pressures and geopolitical forces mean more frequent electricity, telecoms networks and internet outages, as well as cyber-attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would be unsurprised to see in 2030 that the cryptocurrency bubble and craze is long over and forms a new chapter in the second edition of our book Boom and Bust: A Global History of Financial Bubbles. Nevertheless, some of the underlying crypto technology is being used for decentralised finance applications and smart contracts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stablecoins, where they still exist, are regulated by the authorities and have been subsumed into the traditional banking system. The main digital currency is one provided by central banks, like the Bank of England, in the form of a central bank digital currency (CBDC). The report on 13 January 2022 by the House of Lord’s Economic Affairs Committee, which argued that CBDC was a solution in search of a problem, has been long forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew Urquhart, in his Observatory article on CDBCs, argues that their development is inevitable, and in my article, I argue that the chief lesson from history is that currency issue is eventually concentrated in the hands of government or their central banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The economic debate around the globe in 2030 is focused on the issues of privacy and exclusion because CBDCs are being used in some countries to control the citizenry and exclude minorities and dissidents from the formal economy. Maybe we should have listened to the House of Lords back in 2022 when they raised concerns about privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we leave 2030, I will buy a souvenir with some Britcoins (the colloquial name for the Bank of England’s CBDC) to take back to 2022 – a celebratory book telling the story of how Northern Ireland beat England on penalties in the final of the 2030 FIFA World Cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: John Turner, Queen’s University Belfast and Economics Observatory lead editor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by Mark Sivewright on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">The continuing process of digitalisation of the world’s financial system as well as the move away from cash during the pandemic are raising existential questions about the future of money.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/mark-sivewright-EoCyR5cofPc-unsplash.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/mark-sivewright-EoCyR5cofPc-unsplash.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NSAV TO ACQUIRE SIGNIFICANT MINORITY STAKE IN METAVERSE NETWORK (MNC), EXPANDS PRESENCE IN $500 BILLION GLOBAL METAVERSE MARKET</title><link href="/NSAV-TO-ACQUIRE-SIGNIFICANT-MINORITY-STAKE-IN-METAVERSE-NETWORK-MNC-EXPANDS-PRESENCE-IN-500-BILLION-GLOBAL-METAVERSE-MARKET/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NSAV TO ACQUIRE SIGNIFICANT MINORITY STAKE IN METAVERSE NETWORK (MNC), EXPANDS PRESENCE IN $500 BILLION GLOBAL METAVERSE MARKET" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:31+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:31+00:00</updated><id>/NSAV-TO-ACQUIRE-SIGNIFICANT-MINORITY-STAKE-IN-METAVERSE-NETWORK-MNC-EXPANDS-PRESENCE-IN-500-BILLION-GLOBAL-METAVERSE-MARKET</id><content type="html" xml:base="/NSAV-TO-ACQUIRE-SIGNIFICANT-MINORITY-STAKE-IN-METAVERSE-NETWORK-MNC-EXPANDS-PRESENCE-IN-500-BILLION-GLOBAL-METAVERSE-MARKET/">&lt;p&gt;$NSAV - NSAV TO ACQUIRE SIGNIFICANT MINORITY STAKE IN METAVERSE NETWORK (MNC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;METAVERSE NETWORK (MNC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;METAVERSE NETWORK (MNC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$NSAV - NSAV TO ACQUIRE SIGNIFICANT MINORITY STAKE IN METAVERSE NETWORK (MNC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;METAVERSE NETWORK (MNC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;METAVERSE NETWORK (MNC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London, England, Jan. 14, 2022 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) – Net Savings Link, Inc. (OTC Pink: NSAV), a cryptocurrency, blockchain and digital asset technology company, today announced that the Company has agreed to acquire a 10% stake in Metaverse Network LLC. (MNC) https://metaversenetwork.llc/ . MNC’s main asset is its ownership of leading cryptocurrency exchange, BQEX Ltd. https://bqex.ltd/ . BQEX Exchange has over 4 million registered users. Metaverse Network LLC. will go public in New York in Q1 2022, potentially making NSAV’s stake even far more valuable. This acquisition will further expand NSAV’s presence in the $500 billion global Metaverse market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qFMSb-Dv7T0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, NSAV announced that it will partner with Metaverse Network LLC. to launch a pioneer Non-Fungible Token (NFT). Under the terms of the deal, NSAV will receive 50% of the founder’s pool of the token, or between 5 to 7.5% of the total NFT tokens. Additional details of this groundbreaking NFT, including the tokenomics, will be released in the next week or so. The booming NFT market surpassed $40 billion in 2021 and management expects the growth to continue in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.bnnbloomberg.ca/nft-market-surpassed-40-billion-in-2021-new-estimate-shows-1.1703953&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;W. Y. Cheung, CEO of MNC stated, “We are thrilled to work with NSAV management. They are very blockchain savvy and their vision has always enlightened me. We are very impressed with the advanced technical ability of the NSAV team.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dato’ Sri Desmond Lim, Interim CEO and Senior Vice President of Cryptocurrency Operations for NSAV and Silverbear Capital partner stated, “This is another concrete step to commercialize the metaverse relationship between NSAV and Metaverse network. According to public information, Metaverse has the potential to be a $1 trillion market, which we can harness from and we believe NSAV should also prepare for this era to arrive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Story continues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://cointelegraph.com/news/the-metaverse-is-a-1t-opportunity-after-users-increase-10x-grayscale-report&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About MNC:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MNC is a centralized App that transforms diversified users to decentralized universe DApps. It is a “playground” that supports both creators and users for access, allowing to create a link between the present universe and Metaverse to work together in harmony. As Blockchain environments are dominating the landscape in the next era to come, MNC believes token ecology is essential to access the new era community and to operate in the decentralized economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About NSAV:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NSAV’s vision is the establishment of a fully integrated technology company, which provides turnkey technological solutions to the cryptocurrency, blockchain and digital asset industries. Over time, the Company plans to provide a wide range of services such as software solutions, e-commerce, financial services, advisory services and information technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further information please contact NSAV at info@nsavholdinginc.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NSAV Twitter account can be accessed at https://twitter.com/nsavtech&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NSAV corporate website can be accessed at http://nsavholdinginc.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NSAV Premium OTC Crypto Trading Desk website can be accessed at https://nsavholdinginc.com/otc-desk/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NSAV Hong Kong OTC Crypto Trading Desk website can be accessed at https://hkotc.co/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NSAVDEX 2 Exchange website can be accessed at https://nsavdex.io/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NSAVDEX Telegram account can be accessed at https://t.me/NSAVDEXorg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silverbear Capital Inc. https://www.sbcfinancialgroup.com.hk/ , a leading, global investment banking firm, will be advising NSAV on strategic matters related to this transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silverbear Capital Inc. (SBC) has a dynamic of disciplines on a broad commercial level and practice. SBC has a strong group of Partners in a wide range of disciplines with seasoned experience in finance, management, and professional practice. https://www.sbcfinancialgroup.com.hk/meet-our-team/ .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: Silverbear Capital Inc. does not constitute investment advice, or an offer or solicitation to sell, or a solicitation to buy, or any other investment product (nor shall any such shares or product be offered or sold to any person) in any jurisdiction in which an offer, solicitation, purchase or sale would be unlawful under the securities law of that jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This press release contains certain forward-looking statements within the meaning of Section 27A of the Securities Act of 1933, as amended and Section 21E of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, which are intended to be covered by the safe harbors created thereby. Investors are cautioned that, all forward-looking statements involve risks and uncertainties, including without limitation, the ability of Net Savings Link, Inc. to accomplish its stated plan of business. Net Savings Link, Inc. believes that the assumptions underlying the forward-looking statements contained herein are reasonable, any of the assumptions could be inaccurate, and therefore, there can be no assurance that the forward-looking statements included in this press release will prove to be accurate. In light of the significant uncertainties inherent in the forward- looking statements included herein, the inclusion of such information should not be regarded as a representation by Net Savings Link, Inc. or any other person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Net Savings Link, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;info@nsavholdinginc.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attachments&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">$NSAV - NSAV TO ACQUIRE SIGNIFICANT MINORITY STAKE IN METAVERSE NETWORK (MNC)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/282002af521e0e2f7dff4deb4d96903f" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/282002af521e0e2f7dff4deb4d96903f" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kazakhstan’s bitcoin ‘paradise’ may be losing its lustre</title><link href="/Kazakhstan-s-bitcoin-paradise-may-be-losing-its-lustre/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kazakhstan’s bitcoin ‘paradise’ may be losing its lustre" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:26+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:26+00:00</updated><id>/Kazakhstan-s-bitcoin-paradise-may-be-losing-its-lustre</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Kazakhstan-s-bitcoin-paradise-may-be-losing-its-lustre/">&lt;p&gt;A view shows smoke billowing from inside a building that houses several TV and radio stations following the protests triggered by fuel price increase, in Almaty, Kazakhstan January 6, 2022. REUTERS/Mariya Gordeyeva&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary Internet shutdown knocked data centres offline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Government also eyeing tighter rules on mining&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some big bitcoin miners looking to move overseas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kazakh mining industry is second-largest on earth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LONDON, Jan 14 (Reuters) - Kazakhstan may no longer be the bitcoin sanctuary it once was, according to some big miners who are looking to leave the global crypto hub following internet shutdowns last week that compounded fears about tightening regulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government web shutdowns during an explosion of unrest in the country, the world’s second-largest centre for mining, caused bitcoin’s global computing power to drop around 13% as data centres used to produce the cryptocurrency were knocked offline. read more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alan Dorjiyev of the National Association of Blockchain and Data Center Industry in Kazakhstan, which represents 80% of legal mining companies in the country, said most crypto producers were now back online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register now for FREE unlimited access to Reuters.com Register&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet the resumption of operations may belie problems to come for the fast-growing cryptocurrency industry, according to four major miners interviewed by Reuters, with some saying they or their clients may look for other countries to operate in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet outage compounded growing concerns about the stability and prospects of the business as tighter government oversight looms, the miners said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vincent Liu, a miner who moved operations to Kazakhstan from China to take advantage of the country’s cheap power, said the changing environment had led him to look at shifting operations to North America or Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Two or three years earlier, we called Kazakhstan a paradise of the mining industry because of the stable political environment and stable electricity,” said Liu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are evaluating the situation … I suppose we will keep a part of hashrate in Kazakhstan and will move some to other countries,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies are “mined” by powerful computers that compete against others hooked up to a global network to solve complex mathematical puzzles. The process guzzles electricity and is often powered by fossil fuels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan became the world’s No.2 centre for bitcoin mining after the United States last year, attracting an influx of miners and data centre bookings from former global leader China after a crackdown on the industry by Beijing. read more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August, Kazakhstan accounted for 18% of the global “hashrate” - crypto jargon for the amount of computing power being used by computers connected to the bitcoin network. That was up from 8% in April, before Chinese miners shifted machines and bought capacity at Kazakh data centres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;POWER PLAYS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan’s crypto mining farms are mostly powered by aging coal plants, which are a headache for authorities as they seek to decarbonise the economy. Power-hungry miners have forced the former Soviet state to import electricity and ration domestic supplies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government is now looking at how to tax and regulate the largely underground and foreign-owned industry. It said last year it planned to crack down on unregistered “grey” miners who it estimates might be consuming twice as much power as the “white” or officially registered ones. read more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Din-mukhammed Matkenov, co-founder of crypto miner BTC KZ, said an influx of Chinese miners had worsened problems for domestic miners by gobbling up power. Clients may look to move to the United States and Russia, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We think that the development and stability of mining industry in Kazakhstan is in danger,” said Matkenov, whose firm has three data centres in Ekibastuz, a city in northern Kazakhstan, running over 30,000 mining rigs. Patchy power supply has complicated the company’s business, he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is very unstable and really hard to predict the profits to pay the electricity bill and salaries. At the moment we are close to being bankrupt and clients are trying to find other countries where they can relocate to with a more stable governmental ruling.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kazakhstan’s energy ministry did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, Kazakhstan’s relatively low taxes, labour costs and equipment still offer advantages, the four miners said. Power costs a minimum of $0.03-$0.04 per kilowatt, Matkenov said, similar to the United States and lower than $0.05 in Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is an ease of doing business in Kazakhstan that allows well-capitalised projects to deploy much faster than would be possible in the West,” said Mike Cohen of Canada-based miner Pow.re.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Those willing to establish operations in the region have a greater tolerance for geopolitical risk and are not put off by fossil fuel-based energy sources.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register now for FREE unlimited access to Reuters.com Register&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reporting by Tom Wilson in London; Additional reporting by Tamara Vaal in Nur-Sultan; Editing by Pravin Char&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Standards: The Thomson Reuters Trust Principles.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">A view shows smoke billowing from inside a building that houses several TV and radio stations following the protests triggered by fuel price increase, in Almaty, Kazakhstan January 6, 2022. REUTERS/Mariya Gordeyeva</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/74LX3SZAJBMBLMDYEPXYS4SNGU.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/74LX3SZAJBMBLMDYEPXYS4SNGU.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A new era for the crypto age</title><link href="/A-new-era-for-the-crypto-age/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A new era for the crypto age" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:25+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:25+00:00</updated><id>/A-new-era-for-the-crypto-age</id><content type="html" xml:base="/A-new-era-for-the-crypto-age/">&lt;p&gt;In January 2009, as the world was reeling from a financial meltdown of near unfathomable proportions, a new currency was born. A decentralised digital currency for the post-crisis age, bitcoin promised an alternative to the mainstream financial system for those who found themselves suddenly suspicious of the traditional banking institutions of decades past. From its earliest days of trading, bitcoin had its fervent supporters. While some dismissed it as an underground fad, others believed that bitcoin was truly the future of money, and imagined a utopia where crypto replaced cash. These voices have only grown stronger over the course of the last decade, as bitcoin has enjoyed a meteoric rise, moving rapidly from the financial margins into the mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a $2trn industry (see Fig 1), cryptocurrency is no longer an underground phenomenon. In September of this year, El Salvador made history by becoming the first country in the world to adopt bitcoin as legal tender. On the other side of the Atlantic, Ukraine is said to be hot on its heels, with plans to adopt bitcoin as legal tender, according to reports. For early proponents of bitcoin, this feels like a landmark moment, confirming what they always believed to be true: that the future of currency is crypto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, while bitcoin has its supporters, it is not without its sceptics. Many economists view cryptocurrencies with suspicion, with regulators in both Europe and the US issuing warnings on the dangers of trading with crypto. Its highly volatile nature means that El Salvador’s bitcoin experiment is something of a gamble – and we are yet to see whether it will pay off. But with one country paving the way with crypto, others may soon follow suit. For better or for worse, El Salvador could be the start of a digital currency domino effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brave new world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big problems often require radical solutions. El Salvador has long been plagued with a number of very particular economic woes: a small, central American country of just 6.5 million citizens, the nation’s economy is heavily reliant on remittances – money sent home from the two million Salvadorans who are currently living and working abroad. With expatriated Salvadorans sending more than $4bn back to their home country every year, remittances make up one fifth of El Salvador’s total GDP. Within El Salvador itself, meanwhile, two-thirds of citizens work within the informal economy, and 70 percent do not have bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A desire to tackle this unique set of economic circumstances seems to have driven El Salvador’s decision to embrace cryptocurrency. President Nayib Bukele – who at the age of 40 is often described as Latin America’s first millennial President – has championed crypto as a path to both financial inclusion and independence for Salvadoran citizens. It is his hope that the move could save Salvadorans up to $400m a year in transaction costs on remittances, while giving access to financial services to those who are currently unbanked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In El Salvador, we are trying to start the design of a country for the future,” Bukele said in a video message broadcast to the Bitcoin 2021 conference in June of this year, where he first announced his plans to formally adopt the cryptocurrency as legal tender. “In the short term, this will generate jobs and help to provide financial inclusion to thousands outside the formal economy. In the medium and long term, we hope that this decision can help us push humanity at least a tiny bit into the right direction.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legal tender&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the announcement of Bukele’s crypto-vision for El Salvador in June, a bitcoin bill was passed, requiring all Salvadorian businesses to accept payment in bitcoin as well as the US dollar – the nation’s existing legal tender – effective from September 7. To mark the launch of the nation’s new bitcoin era, all Salvadoran citizens were gifted a digital wallet called Chivo (Spanish slang for ‘cool’), with $30 of credit pre-loaded for each user to spend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this may all sound very promising, the reality proved to be rather more challenging than perhaps anticipated. The country’s landmark bitcoin adoption day was beset by technical difficulties – the Chivo digital wallet was forced offline for hours after government servers were overwhelmed by an influx of sign-ups, and President Bukele took to social media to complain that app stores on Apple and Huawei devices were not yet hosting the government-backed app. Elsewhere, it was reported that ATMs were running out of money, as citizens rushed to convert their $30 bitcoin holdings into cash. In the capital city, more than 1,000 people took to the streets in protest of the bitcoin adoption, setting off fireworks and burning a tyre in front of the Supreme Court building in an impassioned display of opposition to the law change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Like all innovations, El Salvador’s bitcoin process has a learning curve,” Bukele said in a tweet, reflecting on the rollout. “Not everything will be achieved in a day, or in a month.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there may have indeed been noble intentions behind El Salvador’s bitcoin experiment, it’s clear that creating a crypto-utopia is going to be a very hard task for tech-savvy Bukele to pull off. Opinion polls show that the overwhelming majority of Salvadorans remain unsure as to how bitcoin actually works, while the currency’s extreme volatility is yet another source of anxiety for many. At a time when pandemic-related economic uncertainty remains rife, it is understandable that bitcoin feels like too large of a gamble for some sceptics. And yet, despite the many teething troubles that El Salvador has encountered, it looks like a number of other countries are now looking to follow in its digital footsteps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The path to financial freedom?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;El Salvador is one of a growing number of developing economies that have been gravitating towards cryptocurrencies. In Mexico, Cuba and Venezuela crypto transactions are fast becoming a part of daily life, allowing for fast, cheap and reliable cross-border transactions in countries that also rely heavily on remittances. Just one day after El Salvador officially adopted bitcoin as legal tender, Panama introduced a draft bill that aims to recognise bitcoin as an alternative payment method – suggesting that the cryptocurrency domino effect may already be underway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phenomenon isn’t unique to Latin America, either. In developing economies across the globe, crypto appears to be gaining mainstream appeal. Each year, leading blockchain data company Chainanalysis publishes its Global Cryptocurrency Adoption Index, listing the world’s top 20 countries for crypto adoption (see Fig 2). In the 2021 ranking, 19 of the 20 countries listed are emerging and frontier markets, reflecting a surge in usage in developing markets. From South-East Asia to Sub-Saharan Africa, cryptocurrencies are gaining a significant foothold – and are quietly filling gaps in the market that traditional financial services were never able to penetrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should perhaps be unsurprising that crypto has enjoyed such success in the developing world. After all, many developing countries were also early adopters of mobile payments, with citizens both urban and rural leapfrogging traditional financial products and moving straight into the world of remote, cashless payments. The best-known success story is Kenya’s M-Pesa, a mobile-money platform that has recently hit 50 million users across Africa, and that has been credited with expanding financial inclusion across the continent by enabling payments and transfers among the traditionally unbanked. While it goes without saying that cryptocurrency is an entirely different world to that of mobile payments, the early success of such technologies may have paved the way for the digital currencies of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing nations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is the case with El Salvador, crypto’s potential to enable cheap cross-border transactions is central to its appeal in developing nations around the world. Migrant remittances are a significant source of income for low- and middle-income countries, totalling approximately $554bn worldwide at the end of 2019, according to the International Organisation for Migration. That said, sending money back home can be a slow, complex and above all, costly exercise for many migrants living abroad. The UN estimates that currency conversions and fees on international transfers eat up approximately seven percent of the total amount sent through remittances every year – a considerable percentage of what is a crucial source of income for some of the world’s most economically vulnerable people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Salvadoran government is currently exploring options to mine bitcoin using geothermal power&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In areas of instability, conflict or hyperinflation, meanwhile, crypto is proving to be something of a safety net to many. In Afghanistan, cash all but dried up following the Taliban takeover in September, forcing banks to close and seeing citizens struggle to purchase food and other basic necessities. A freezing of foreign aid has aggravated the unfolding humanitarian crisis in the country, while money transfer services MoneyGram and Western Union temporarily halted services in Afghanistan in the weeks following the US military’s withdrawal – cutting off many Afghans from a critical source of income in a desperate time of need. For those seeking an urgent solution to the nation’s cash crisis, crypto has offered a much-needed lifeline, with the conflict-ridden country seeing a surge in cryptocurrency usage among its citizens in 2021. Indeed, in Chainanalysis’ Global Cryptocurrency Adoption Index, Afghanistan now ranks seventh in the world for peer-to-peer crypto transactions. Last year, however, it didn’t even appear on the list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein, Libya, Palestine and Syria are all near the top in global online searches for bitcoin and other forms of cryptocurrency, while downloads of bitcoin wallet BlueWallet grew by 1,781 percent in Lebanon in 2020, as the country continues to grapple with an ongoing financial meltdown. In times of conflict and crisis, it would seem crypto offers a way to circumvent broken systems and to provide some financial protection to those in real need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No safe bet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrency is far from being the perfect cure to the world’s many financial ills. It has, undoubtedly, been a useful – and at times, necessary – tool for some of the world’s most vulnerable citizens. But it is not without its flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In more developed economies, there remains a more sceptical outlook on crypto, both among economists and the wider population alike. Indeed, in the US and Europe, cryptocurrency payments are far from being an everyday occurrence for most citizens. The world of crypto remains something of a niche subculture, largely dominated by semi-professional traders and blockchain aficionados. There is also a significant gender imbalance among traders, too – in the US, 76 percent of current crypto holders are men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main criticism of crypto, however, is that it is notoriously volatile in price. Thought to be 10 times more volatile than most major currencies, the market value of cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin can fluctuate by hundreds of dollars in a single day, making crypto a high-risk investment for many. Regulators have repeatedly warned about the dangers of investing and trading in cryptocurrency, citing this unpredictable and extreme volatility as one of their most pressing concerns. Price fluctuation not only puts people’s personal finances at risk, experts warn, but could potentially threaten financial stability across multiple different markets. In October, Bank of England Deputy Governor Sir John Cunliffe called for urgent cryptocurrency regulation, citing financial stability concerns. In a speech given at Sibos, an annual banking conference, he compared the current crypto boom to the rocketing value of US subprime mortgages before the catastrophic 2008 global financial crash. Without rapid intervention, he argued, a potential crypto crash could plunge the global economy back into another 2008-level crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When something in the financial system is growing very fast, and growing in largely unregulated space, financial stability authorities have to sit up and take notice,” he said. “They have to think very carefully about what could happen and whether they, or other regulatory authorities, need to act.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2021 alone, cryptocurrencies have surged by around 200 percent to an estimated value of $2.3trn – up from $800bn in 2020. As Cunliffe noted in his speech, subprime mortgages were valued at around $1.2trn in 2008, and triggered a global financial meltdown of unprecedented proportions when borrowers began defaulting on loans. With the fallout from the 2008 crash still fresh in economists’ minds, it is hardly surprising that regulators are setting alarm bells ringing when it comes to crypto’s seemingly unstoppable growth (see Fig 3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmental issues&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And crypto’s inherently volatile nature isn’t the only cause for concern. There is also growing unease among sceptics and aficionados alike over bitcoin’s environmental impact. Bitcoin mining – the process through which ‘new’ bitcoins are created – is incredibly energy intensive. In order to be awarded a new bitcoin, ‘miners’ must use their computers to solve a series of incredibly complex puzzles. Whoever solves the puzzle first is awarded a new coin to their computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, solving the problems requires the use of incredibly powerful specialised computers, which then need to run at full capacity, burning through an extraordinary amount of energy during each mining operation. As a result of this energy intensive process, the Cambridge Centre for Alternative Finance estimates that a single bitcoin transaction has the same carbon footprint as 680,000 Visa transactions. Already, this considerable carbon consumption is beginning to damage bitcoin’s reputation on the global stage. In May, Tesla CEO and long-standing crypto advocate Elon Musk announced that his electric car company would no longer be accepting bitcoin for car purchases, due to pressing concerns over the currency’s environmental impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When there’s confirmation of reasonable (~50 percent) clean energy usage by miners with positive future trend, Tesla will resume allowing bitcoin transactions,” Musk said in a tweet, clarifying his position. Environmental concerns also played a role in the World Bank’s decision to decline a request from El Salvador to assist with implementing bitcoin as legal tender. The central American nation approached the World Bank earlier this year, seeking technical assistance with its plans to formally adopt bitcoin as an alternative national currency. “While the government did approach us for assistance on bitcoin, this is not something the World Bank can support given the environmental and transparency shortcomings,” a World Bank spokesperson told Reuters in July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If crypto continues on its current upwards trajectory, the inconvenient truths surrounding its environmental impact and its inherent volatility will surely become increasingly difficult to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An undefined future&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all modern innovations and technological advances, the world of cryptocurrency is a fast-moving one. In little over a decade, crypto has gone from a niche, abstract idea to a $2trn industry. Bitcoin’s introduction as legal tender in El Salvador marks a pivotal moment in the history of cryptocurrency, but the journey certainly isn’t over yet. In many ways, it feels like this could just be the beginning, as countries around the world look to potentially follow El Salvador’s lead. No matter the outcome of the Salvadoran bitcoin experiment, one thing is for certain – governments across the globe will be watching closely, and taking notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less than one month on from the Bitcoin Law coming into effect in El Salvador, more people are said to have a Chivo bitcoin wallet than a traditional bank account. According to President Bukele, three million Salvadorans are now using Chivo – almost half of the country’s total population. By contrast, only a third of Salvadoran citizens are believed to have a bank account. It’s amongst these unbanked citizens that bitcoin is likely to be having the greatest impact. For those with access to a smartphone but not to a bank, payments, deposits and money transfers are now available to them at the touch of a button. While financial inclusion may have previously been a real economic hurdle for El Salvador, now digital literacy is perhaps the most pressing challenge, as the Bitcoin Law means little if citizens don’t fully understand the financial options available to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In developing economies across the globe, crypto appears to be gaining mainstream appeal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the initial glitches and setbacks, El Salvador’s bitcoin gamble has already achieved some undeniably impressive results. As of October, 30 bitcoin ATM machines have been installed in major cities in the US, including Los Angeles, Houston and Chicago, in the hopes that Salvadoran expats will use Chivo to send money back home. The plan appears to be working – in a tweet posted on October 16, President Bukele told his followers: “today, we received 24,076 remittances, adding up to $3,069,761.05 (in one day).”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the environmental aspect of bitcoin, too, the country also appears to be making some progress. Aware of the growing concerns surrounding the cryptocurrency’s carbon footprint, the Salvadoran government is currently exploring options to mine bitcoin using geothermal power. A pilot project has been set up at a geothermal power station near El Salvador’s Tecapa volcano, where 300 state-of-the-art mining computers are currently being powered by electricity generated from the volcano’s high-pressure steam. In El Salvador, where geothermal electricity already accounts for a quarter of domestic energy production, volcano-powered mining could be the solution to bitcoin’s dirty problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world watches on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is still far too early in El Salvador’s bitcoin journey to draw any firm conclusions on its success or lack thereof. But it certainly seems likely that the country’s bold experiment will fuel a new flurry of activity in the world of digital currencies. Most of the world’s central banks are already looking to create their own versions of digital currencies, with the Bank of England announcing in April that it is exploring the possibility of launching a new form of digital money to exist alongside cash and bank deposits. According to a report by PwC, 60 governments around the world are currently working on some form of Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC), with 88 percent of those under construction said to be based on blockchain – the same technology that powers bitcoin. With so many CBDCs being tested, the question is not if they will be introduced, but when.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for whether any countries will be as bold as El Salvador in adopting any form of cryptocurrency as legal tender, that remains to be seen. For now, the future of crypto remains as unpredictable as its market value.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">In January 2009, as the world was reeling from a financial meltdown of near unfathomable proportions, a new currency was born. A decentralised digital currency for the post-crisis age, bitcoin promised an alternative to the mainstream financial system for those who found themselves suddenly suspicious of the traditional banking institutions of decades past. From its earliest days of trading, bitcoin had its fervent supporters. While some dismissed it as an underground fad, others believed that bitcoin was truly the future of money, and imagined a utopia where crypto replaced cash. These voices have only grown stronger over the course of the last decade, as bitcoin has enjoyed a meteoric rise, moving rapidly from the financial margins into the mainstream.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/E021_rt-600x450.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/E021_rt-600x450.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">North Korean hackers behind the recent cryptocurrency crimes, says Kaspersky Labs</title><link href="/North-Korean-hackers-behind-the-recent-cryptocurrency-crimes-says-Kaspersky-Labs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="North Korean hackers behind the recent cryptocurrency crimes, says Kaspersky Labs" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:24+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:24+00:00</updated><id>/North-Korean-hackers-behind-the-recent-cryptocurrency-crimes-says-Kaspersky-Labs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/North-Korean-hackers-behind-the-recent-cryptocurrency-crimes-says-Kaspersky-Labs/">&lt;p&gt;×&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report released on Thursday by the Russian cybersecurity Kaspersky Labs states that the recent and regular phishing and social engineering attacks targeting cryptocurrency startups have been caused by North Korean hackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackers understand that most cryptocurrency businesses are small or medium-sized startups, and cant invests lots of money into their internal security system and hence take advantage by….&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">×</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Polkadot Recovery And HUH Token Are Successfully Multi-Chain</title><link href="/Polkadot-Recovery-And-HUH-Token-Are-Successfully-Multi-Chain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polkadot Recovery And HUH Token Are Successfully Multi-Chain" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:18+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:18+00:00</updated><id>/Polkadot-Recovery-And-HUH-Token-Are-Successfully-Multi-Chain</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Polkadot-Recovery-And-HUH-Token-Are-Successfully-Multi-Chain/">&lt;p&gt;Polkadot Recovery And HUH Token Are Successfully Multi-Chain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polkadot is one of many different cryptocurrencies that are experiencing a recovery period in their market price. This is a welcomed period after such an extensive bearish trend that took over the crypto market towards the end of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HUH Token also shared its exciting news. HUH token is now multichain and its creators are continuing the development of their social media platform that will be released at a later date for the public. This is a space that has not been heavily explored before and could present an opportunity for those who want to hold the token before the social platform launches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polkadot has its own blockchain and therefore, its native currency is a coin. Polkadot is an interesting concept as it is formed of two different types of blockchain. The main blockchain is known as the relay chain, where permanent transactions take place. The alternative blockchains are created by users and Polkadot refers to them as parachains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parachains are meant to be adapted for various use cases and then feedback to the main blockchain, the idea being that normal blockchains can be limited in the number of uses they can provide. Whereas Polkadot is bringing a unique concept to the cryptocurrency space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HUH Token was developed primarily with the HUH team’s future vision in mind. That vision includes a social media platform where HUH Token would be a currency within the network. The idea would involve a significant incentive for content creators to move themselves and their audience to the new platform as there would be rewards for the content they make. Creators would be rewarded for the type and amount of engagement on anything that they make, allowing a wide variety of entertainment types to be shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the social platform being a future endeavour, HUH Token itself also has qualities that are appealing to investors who are considering purchasing a newer token. HUH Token has a referral system that provides Binance Coin to those who successfully refer new buyers. Moreover, HUH Token provides static reflection. This is a small fee applied to trades involving HUH Token. This fee is then redistributed across every HUH Token wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the latest updates for HUH Token is that they have become a multichain cryptocurrency. Initially, the token was only available on PancakeSwap. Since then, HUH Token has been listed on UniSwap and is therefore available on the Ethereum and Binance Blockchain. This will allow more users to purchase HUH Token or swap using a wider variety of tokens, increasing the token’s trading volume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future endeavours are an essential factor when considering where to place your money with hopes of a high return. Polkadot is one of the contenders for a new blockchain to challenge for a higher position in the cryptocurrency world. HUH Token is a brand-new token with exciting prospects. It could be worth acquiring it before the token increases in price due to updates on their overarching project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn More About HUH Token Here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Website: https://huh.social&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HUH Official Swap: https://swap.huh.social/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Telegram: https://t.me/HUHTOKEN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter: https://twitter.com/HuhToken&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/huhToken/&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">Polkadot Recovery And HUH Token Are Successfully Multi-Chain</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/Polkadot.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/Polkadot.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Crypto Growth in Africa – The How and the Why</title><link href="/Crypto-Growth-in-Africa-The-How-and-the-Why/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crypto Growth in Africa – The How and the Why" /><published>2022-01-15T09:18:11+00:00</published><updated>2022-01-15T09:18:11+00:00</updated><id>/Crypto-Growth-in-Africa-The-How-and-the-Why</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Crypto-Growth-in-Africa-The-How-and-the-Why/">&lt;p&gt;The cryptocurrency market remains a vast and rapidly growing sector and one that currently boasts a cumulative market capitalisation value of $2.26 trillion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the crypto space is largely synonymous with innovation in developed economies, its continued growth has actually been driven by rising demand in developing countries and regions across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take Africa, for example, where cryptocurrency transactions totalled $105.6 billion in the year ending June 2021 on the back of soaring peer-to-peer (P2P) transactions. But why has Africa become a natural home for cryptocurrency growth in the current marketplace?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rise and Rise of Cryptocurrency in Africa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incredibly, cryptocurrency adoption in Africa grew by 1200% in the year ending June 2021, with this established as the fastest adoption rate in the world. So, although the continent continues to play catch-up with other regions globally, the rate and pace of growth is truly something to behold at present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, markets such as Nigeria, Tanzania, Kenya and South Africa have showcased some of the highest grassroots adoptions in the world, with each of these nations ranked in the top 20 Global Crypto Adoption Index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we drill down deeper into the numbers, we can see that monthly cryptocurrency transfers to and from Africa of under $10,000 (which are typically made by individuals and small businesses) increased by more than 55% during the year to reach $316 million in June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to data from Chainalysis, the number of monthly transfers also rose by nearly half during the same period, surpassing the 600,700 record set previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of this activity is taking place in Nigeria, which is home to the region’s largest economy, along with South Africa and Kenya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is Africa Blazing a Trail in the Crypto Market?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin (BTC) is also the market-leading crypto asset in Africa, although it’s interesting to note that the region’s users largely use this token for the purpose of commerce rather than speculation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a reversal of the BTC trends observed elsewhere in the developed world, where Bitcoin is largely owned and leveraged by financial traders to speculate and secure considerable returns on investment through platforms such as the webtrader MT4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why is this the case? Well, the answer also describes the same reason that cryptocurrency is popular in Africa in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More specifically, there’s a large and unbanked population in Africa, with up to 57% of the population (approximately 95 million) lacking access to a traditional bank account and even basic financial services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these people, cryptocurrency represents a viable and accessible currency rather than an investment asset, and one that can be utilised to buy products, secure services and engage in digital currency transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, crypto adoption rates are likely to increase further in the months and years ahead, particularly given Africa’s relatively young and tech-savvy population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feature photo by Tezos on Unsplash&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="CRYPTOCURRENCY" /><summary type="html">The cryptocurrency market remains a vast and rapidly growing sector and one that currently boasts a cumulative market capitalisation value of $2.26 trillion.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/tezos-OtZDVgAqP9A-unsplash.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/15-01-2022/tezos-OtZDVgAqP9A-unsplash.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>