<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-29T19:21:44+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Moderna aims to price coronavirus vaccine at 50 60 per course Report</title><link href="/Moderna-aims-to-price-coronavirus-vaccine-at-50-60-per-course-Report/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moderna aims to price coronavirus vaccine at 50 60 per course Report" /><published>2020-07-29T17:23:58+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T17:23:58+05:30</updated><id>/Moderna-aims-to-price-coronavirus-vaccine-at-50-60-per-course-Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Moderna-aims-to-price-coronavirus-vaccine-at-50-60-per-course-Report/">&lt;p&gt;The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters. The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderna Inc is planning to price its coronavirus vaccine at $50 to $60 per course, at least $11 more than another vaccine from Pfizer Inc and BioNTech, the Financial Times reported on Tuesday, citing unnamed sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderna’s proposed price for a two-dose course sold to governments compares with $39 for two doses under a deal that Pfizer Inc and German partner BioNTech struck with the U.S. government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industry analysts said Pfizer and BioNTech’s $2 billion deal to cover 50 million patients, which is contingent on an approvable product, would likely pressure other manufacturers to set similar prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderna’s proposed price would apply to the United States and other high-income countries, according to the report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;READ&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Covid-19 vaccine tracker, July 29: Pfizer-BioNTech on the heels of Moderna, enters late stage clinical trials&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Moderna spokesperson said the company was in discussions with governments about potential supply of the vaccine, called mRNA-1273, but did not provide any details on pricing “given the confidential nature of the discussions and contracts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pfizer, Moderna and Merck &amp;amp; Co have said they plan to sell their vaccines at a profit, while some drugmakers, including Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson have announced plans to price their vaccines on a not-for-profit basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Also read&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Why India will remain a central player in the development of vaccines&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AstraZeneca Plc agreed to provide the United States 300 million doses of its potential vaccine in exchange for $1.2 billion in upfront funding, which works out to $4 per dose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US government has provided Moderna with nearly $1 billion in funding to support its research and development efforts for its potential COVID-19 vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;READ&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Moderna vaccine protects 16 monkeys from coronavirus; 30,000 humans await&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus Explained Covid-19 vaccine tracker: Pfizer-BioNTech on the heels of Moderna&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India coronavirus numbers explained: Many states yet to ramp up tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply Put: In market high, some fears Click here for more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funding is part of “Operation Warp Speed,” an initiative by the Trump administration to hasten the production of an inoculation for COVID-19, which has so far killed around 650,000 people worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 The Indian Express is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@indianexpress) and stay updated with the latest headlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the latest Coronavirus Outbreak News, download Indian Express App.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters. The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.indianexpress.com/2020/05/moderna.jpg?w=759" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.indianexpress.com/2020/05/moderna.jpg?w=759" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Exclusive Samsung making three Galaxy S21 models in other words water is wet</title><link href="/Exclusive-Samsung-making-three-Galaxy-S21-models-in-other-words-water-is-wet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exclusive Samsung making three Galaxy S21 models in other words water is wet" /><published>2020-07-29T16:44:25+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:44:25+05:30</updated><id>/Exclusive-Samsung-making-three-Galaxy-S21-models-in-other-words-water-is-wet-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Exclusive-Samsung-making-three-Galaxy-S21-models-in-other-words-water-is-wet/">&lt;p&gt;Our ever-reliable sources have revealed to us that Samsung’s 2021 flagship Galaxy S lineup will have three different models. That shouldn’t come as a surprise for anyone who hasn’t been living under a rock for the last year or two. The Galaxy S10 was the first Galaxy S series to come in three sizes, and Samsung stuck with that routine for the Galaxy S20 series. Next year looks set to be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this moment, Samsung has started developing the 5G variants of the three Galaxy S21 models, using model numbers SM-G991, SM-G996, and SM-G998. If Samsung doesn’t mix up the naming scheme, these devices should launch as the Galaxy S21, Galaxy S21+, and Galaxy S21 Ultra, though nothing can be said for certain at this point in time. There will probably be LTE variants as well, but we can’t currently see any sign of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;128GB and 256GB storage variants, but there could be more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also told the three Galaxy S21 models are currently in development with 128GB and 256GB of storage. That is probably not a complete list, or maybe it is. Samsung has already done away with 1TB variants of its flagship phones – the last Galaxy flagship to ship with 1TB of internal storage was the Galaxy S10+, and in a post-COVID world where people are less willing to spend huge sums of money on phones, maybe Samsung will cancel the 512GB option as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all that is speculation. Although the rumor mill sprung into action months ago, it’s too early to say what the Galaxy S21 lineup will be like. Of course, you can depend on us to break more information about the Galaxy S21 as time goes on. Till then, there’s the Galaxy Note 20 and Galaxy Note 20 Ultra to look forward to, along with the third foldable phone from Samsung, all of which will go official on August 5.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Our ever-reliable sources have revealed to us that Samsung’s 2021 flagship Galaxy S lineup will have three different models. That shouldn’t come as a surprise for anyone who hasn’t been living under a rock for the last year or two. The Galaxy S10 was the first Galaxy S series to come in three sizes, and Samsung stuck with that routine for the Galaxy S20 series. Next year looks set to be the same.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.sammobile.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Galaxy-S20-hands-on-9-720x405.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.sammobile.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Galaxy-S20-hands-on-9-720x405.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Google AR Search Reportedly Adds 23 New Insects Context Link Spotted in Google News</title><link href="/Google-AR-Search-Reportedly-Adds-23-New-Insects-Context-Link-Spotted-in-Google-News/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google AR Search Reportedly Adds 23 New Insects Context Link Spotted in Google News" /><published>2020-07-29T16:44:02+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:44:02+05:30</updated><id>/Google-AR-Search-Reportedly-Adds-23-New-Insects-Context-Link-Spotted-in-Google-News</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Google-AR-Search-Reportedly-Adds-23-New-Insects-Context-Link-Spotted-in-Google-News/">&lt;p&gt;Google has reportedly added 23 new insects to its AR search feature, allowing users to virtually see them roaming in their homes. The new insects added to AR search include various kinds of beetles, butterflies, and cicadas. Separately, Google is also testing a new ‘For Context’ feature in Google News. This feature will essentially give you a broader perspective on the primary news search. The contextual link shows up right below the main news, and this context link is usually from the same publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Verge reports that Google has added 23 new insects in its AR Search results. This includes rhinoceros beetle, Hercules beetle, Atlas beetle, stag beetle, giant stag, Miyama stag beetle, shining ball scarab beetle, jewel beetle, ladybug, firefly, Rosalia batesi, swallowtail butterfly, morpho butterfly, atlas moth, mantis, grasshopper, dragonfly, hornet, robust cicada, brown cicada, periodical cicada, Walker’s cicada, and evening cicada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has added various kinds of beetles and cicadas to AR Search&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credit: The Verge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To search for the new insects, type the name in search and then click on the ‘View in 3D’ option. The insect will then superimpose into your background and buzz around the house. This feature works only on AR Core supported devices running on Android. iPhone users will need to run on iOS 11 software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separately, Google has started showing context links in Google News for specific search results. This feature was spotted by Valentin Pletzer, and it appears to be live only on mobile for now. Few Google News stories have an additional small box at the bottom that show context links about the same topic from the same publication. This ‘For Context’ box shows up only for a few publications and only for a few stories for now. Google may be testing it with a few publications, and stories from CNET and Forbes appear to be showing context links. These links look to offer a bigger picture about the primary story in Google News. There is no clarity on when this feature will roll out broadly for all users, and how exactly it will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are smartphone prices rising in India? We discussed this on Orbital, our weekly technology podcast, which you can subscribe to via Apple Podcasts, Google Podcasts, or RSS, download the episode, or just hit the play button below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Google has reportedly added 23 new insects to its AR search feature, allowing users to virtually see them roaming in their homes. The new insects added to AR search include various kinds of beetles, butterflies, and cicadas. Separately, Google is also testing a new ‘For Context’ feature in Google News. This feature will essentially give you a broader perspective on the primary news search. The contextual link shows up right below the main news, and this context link is usually from the same publication.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/google_context_links_1_1596010022179.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/google_context_links_1_1596010022179.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazfit Bip S Lite launched in India with 30 day battery life and sub Rs 4 000 price tag</title><link href="/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite-launched-in-India-with-30-day-battery-life-and-sub-Rs-4-000-price-tag/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazfit Bip S Lite launched in India with 30 day battery life and sub Rs 4 000 price tag" /><published>2020-07-29T16:40:25+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:40:25+05:30</updated><id>/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite-launched-in-India-with-30-day-battery-life-and-sub-Rs-4-000-price-tag</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite-launched-in-India-with-30-day-battery-life-and-sub-Rs-4-000-price-tag/">&lt;p&gt;Amazfit Bip S Lite will go on sale in India from July 29th via Flipkart and official Amazfit store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights Amazfit Bip S Lite is a watered-down version of the Bip S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fitness band is priced under Rs 4,000 in India&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Features include Always-on Transflective display, optical heart rate sensor, more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazfit has launched a new fitness tracker in India, called Amazfit Bip S Lite. The wearable is a lighter version of Amazfit Bip S (review) that made its debut in India back in back June with Rs 4,999 sticker price. The Amazfit Bip S Lite is priced in India much more reasonably and shares a lot of DNA with its elder sibling such as 1.28-inch always-on transflective display, optical heart rate sensor, and 5ATM water-resistant. However, the battery life of the watch has been reduced to 30 days from 40 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Amazfit Bip S Lite price in India is set at Rs 3,799. The wearable will be available via flash sale from tomorrow, i.e. July 29th, via Flipkart and official Amazfit store. The open sale of the Amazfit Bip S Lite is slated to begin from August 5th onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Amazfit Bip S does not come with built-in GPS and just eight different types of sports mode instead of 10. The wearable’s sports mode include Treadmill, Outdoor running, Walking, Indoor cycling, Outdoor cycling, Yoga, Elliptical trainer, and Freestyle. Amazfit claims that the Bip S Lite also has integrated Huami-PAI for detailed analysis of your heart health and overall fitness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The device tips the scale at just 30 grams (with straps) and features Corning Gorilla 3 tempered glass + anti-fingerprint coating to keep the smudges at bay. The Amazfit Bip S Lite comes with Bluetooth 5.0/ BLE connectivity, music control options, and supports for smartphones running iOS 10/ Android 5.0 or above. The watch features PPG bio-tracking optical heart rate sensor and 3-axis acceleration sensors, and packs 150 watch faces with a couple of custom widgets.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Amazfit Bip S Lite will go on sale in India from July 29th via Flipkart and official Amazfit store.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://static.hub.91mobiles.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://static.hub.91mobiles.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazon Alexa App Gets Its Biggest Refresh Ever And The Focus Is On Continuity Personalization</title><link href="/Amazon-Alexa-App-Gets-Its-Biggest-Refresh-Ever-And-The-Focus-Is-On-Continuity-Personalization/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazon Alexa App Gets Its Biggest Refresh Ever And The Focus Is On Continuity Personalization" /><published>2020-07-29T16:38:33+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:38:33+05:30</updated><id>/Amazon-Alexa-App-Gets-Its-Biggest-Refresh-Ever-And-The-Focus-Is-On-Continuity-Personalization</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Amazon-Alexa-App-Gets-Its-Biggest-Refresh-Ever-And-The-Focus-Is-On-Continuity-Personalization/">&lt;p&gt;Amazon is giving the Alexa app for Android and iOS a fresh coat of paint, perhaps the biggest in years. The new app will be available for Android, iOS and Amazon’s own Fire OS. There will be visual improvements across the app, updated navigation methods and a more personalized experience based on how you use Alexa, particularly with relation to Skills. Amazon says the update will roll out on the Google Play Store for Android phones, the Apple App Store for the iPhone and on Amazon’s own Fire OS devices over the next month, and everyone should have it in a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home screen of the updated Alexa app will now have a large Alexa button at the top, which users can either tap to invoke the virtual assistant or simply say Alexa. Beneath that sit a list of personalized suggestions, which will be based on how you interact with Alexa either on your phone or with any of the Alexa-enabled Echo smart speakers or third-party Alexa smart speakers that you may own. This will include music streaming, including suggestions from third party apps such as Spotify if you have linked any of those accounts, upcoming reminders, music suggestions to pick up from where you left off last and maybe even continue with an audiobook while at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to note that while Amazon is prioritizing Alexa Skills in the updated Alexa app for Android and iPhone, third-party skills have been pushed back to a separate Skills &amp;amp; Games section. This is possibly to simplify the experience for users and not complicate it with skills that they may or may not use often. There are changes to the Reminders, Settings, Routines and Skills menus as well for further simplification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to use the new Alexa app and see how much Amazon’s efforts have managed to simplify the experience for users. Over time, with so many features regularly added and so many Alexa devices now on sale, the app seemed to have become a bit cluttered and it wasn’t exactly intuitive at times when you wanted to find something in a jiffy. The fact that Amazon is now focusing on letting you pick up from where you last left off adds to a continuity that could let you shift music from an Echo speaker at home to the Echo Buds wireless earbuds as you are about to step out of home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change in how third-party skills are now listed within the app perhaps comes as a result of a recent study that shows most of these remain unused. A research by Voicebot suggests that as many as 61% of Alexa’s third-party skills have no ratings at all, which indicates they aren’t popular. The research also says only 5% of Alexa skills have earned 10 or more ratings and just 1% have more than 100 ratings from users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Amazon Alexa app will show up on your Android phone or Apple iPhone’s application stores anytime in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Amazon is giving the Alexa app for Android and iOS a fresh coat of paint, perhaps the biggest in years. The new app will be available for Android, iOS and Amazon’s own Fire OS. There will be visual improvements across the app, updated navigation methods and a more personalized experience based on how you use Alexa, particularly with relation to Skills. Amazon says the update will roll out on the Google Play Store for Android phones, the Apple App Store for the iPhone and on Amazon’s own Fire OS devices over the next month, and everyone should have it in a few weeks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2020/07/1595908287_amazon-alexa-app.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2020/07/1595908287_amazon-alexa-app.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Affordable Redmi 9 India launch on August 4 Everything we know</title><link href="/Affordable-Redmi-9-India-launch-on-August-4-Everything-we-know/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Affordable Redmi 9 India launch on August 4 Everything we know" /><published>2020-07-29T16:36:53+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:36:53+05:30</updated><id>/Affordable-Redmi-9-India-launch-on-August-4-Everything-we-know</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Affordable-Redmi-9-India-launch-on-August-4-Everything-we-know/">&lt;p&gt;Redmi 9 India launch on Aug 4 Redmi 9 India launch on Aug 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After launching the Redmi Note 9 in the country, Xiaomi teases to bring much affordable Redmi 9 in India. The smartphone is all set to launch in India on August 4. The company has confirmed that the upcoming Redmi phone will go on sale during Amazon Prime Day set to begin on August 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably, the Redmi 9 is already available in the global market hence we expect the same model to arrive in India next month. The phone will succeed the Redmi 8 launched last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to all the previous launch events, Xiaomi will host the Redmi 9 launch online. The event will begin at 12noon on the slated date. The online launch event will most likely be streamed on Xiaomi’s YouTube channel and social media channels. The Redmi 9 live stream link is yet to be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dedicated page for the Redmi 9 is already available on Mi.com and Amazon.in and here’s everything that has been revealed so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redmi 9: What we know so far&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teaser put out on Amazon.in shows the upcoming Redmi phone in green colour similar to the Redmi Note 9 series phones. There could be other colour options available as well. The global variant comes with Carbon Grey, Sunset Purple and Ocean Green&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the teaser on Amazon, the Redmi 9 appears with a waterdrop notch on the front and minimal bezels on the sides. The 3.5mm headphone jack, speaker grills and charging port are placed at the bottom. The phone isn’t revealed from the back but is likely to be similar to the global version. The global variant of the Redmi 9 comes with four rear cameras at the back bundled with rear mounted fingerprint sensor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REVIEW: Redmi Note 9&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global version comes with a 6.53-inch FHD+ dot drop display with screen resolution of 2340×1080. It is powered by Media Tek Helio G80 processor paired with up to 4GB RAM and 64GB of internal storage. For India, Xiaomi could bring new variants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the camera front, the Redmi 9 includes 13MP+8MP+5MP+2MP rear camera setup while the front packs an 8MP selfie shooter. Other features that the phone includes are – 5020mAh battery paired with 10W charger in the box, Type C port, Gorilla Glass 3 on the front, rear-mounted fingerprint sensor, face ID, and 2 + 1 card slot design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redmi 9 price in India&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the global market the Redmi 9 comes in two models – 3GB RAM + 32GB storage model at €149 (roughly around Rs 12,800) and 4GB RAM and 64GB internal storage at €179 (roughly around Rs 15,400). In India, the Redmi 9 is expected to be slightly cheaper in comparison, like every other Redmi numeric series. Year after year Redmi numeric series is priced under Rs 8,000 and the Redmi 9 is also expected to belong to the same price point. However, the increase in GST could add some more bucks to the official price tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 The Indian Express is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@indianexpress) and stay updated with the latest headlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© IE Online Media Services Pvt Ltd&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Redmi 9 India launch on Aug 4 Redmi 9 India launch on Aug 4</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.indianexpress.com/2020/07/Redmi-9-759.jpg?w=759" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.indianexpress.com/2020/07/Redmi-9-759.jpg?w=759" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Viral Posts Share False Claims About COVID 19 Test Results</title><link href="/Viral-Posts-Share-False-Claims-About-COVID-19-Test-Results/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Viral Posts Share False Claims About COVID 19 Test Results" /><published>2020-07-29T16:32:23+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:32:23+05:30</updated><id>/Viral-Posts-Share-False-Claims-About-COVID-19-Test-Results</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Viral-Posts-Share-False-Claims-About-COVID-19-Test-Results/">&lt;p&gt;Widely shared social media post claim the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) says that positive COVID-19 results simply mean people have previously contracted a cold. In reality, the claim is a misinterpretation of a paragraph discussing antibody tests on the CDC’s website. Health experts confirm COVID-19 is detected with viral tests, not an analysis of antibodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“SHOCKER: CDC admits COVID-19 ‘positive result’ just means you’ve previously contracted the common cold,” one Facebook post says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot of a false Facebook post, taken on July 23, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar Facebook posts from the US have been archived here and here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also Read: WHO Has Not Said Cats And Dogs Cannot Contract COVID-19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Polish Facebook post shared a screenshot of the actual paragraph from the CDC’s website. The caption translates to: “American CDC reports that a positive test result (allegedly for COVID-19) could mean that you had any other cold or flu caused by other coronaviruses”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screenshot of the misleading Polish Facebook post, taken on July 27, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The screenshot used in the post can be found on the CDC website under the topic: “Test for Past Infection (Antibody Test)”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screenshot of the paragraph (in the red rectangle) on CDC website, taken on July 24, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But health experts say the social media posts have misinterpreted the paragraph – including Kenyan doctor Githinji Gitahi, a board member of the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention. The institution is part of the African Union and unrelated to the American CDC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viral test to confirm COVID-19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gitahi, who also runs the medical NGO Amref Health Africa, told AFP Fact Check there are two types of tests for COVID-19 – the direct or viral test, and the indirect test, also referred to as the antibody test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blood samples are used to check for traces of antibodies, which indicate if someone was previously infected with SARS-CoV-2 – the virus that causes COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also Read: No, WHO Is Not Advertising Home-based Jobs To Fight COVID-19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The viral test, meanwhile, uses samples from the respiratory system, such as a swab from the inside of your nose, throat or lungs to detect an ongoing COVID-19 infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Since there is currently no antibody test that is specific to antibodies produced to fight SARS-CoV-2, there is a likelihood to test positive if one tests for antibodies but it might not be because of COVID-19 but because the antibodies came from other coronaviruses, even the one that causes the common cold,” Gitahi said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because of this confusion, we do not use the antibody test to confirm COVID-19 infection but we use the viral test, which is conducted in the nose or throat with swabs or in the lungs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antibody tests used for surveillance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US-based CDC told AFP Fact Check that a viral test will not produce a positive result for COVID-19 from the traces of other human coronaviruses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The viral test detects the SARS-CoV-2 virus in respiratory samples. The presence of other human coronaviruses in a respiratory sample do not produce a positive result on a diagnostic test for SARS-CoV-2,” spokeswoman Jasmine Reed said in an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A positive result on an antibody test might mean that a person had a past infection with SARS-CoV-2. But there is a small chance that antibodies from an infection with a different coronavirus, such as the one that causes the common cold, might cause a positive result on a SARS-CoV-2 antibody test.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WHO acknowledges that antibody tests such as serology testing can be used in COVID-19 surveillance to measure the extent of infection in the population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it cautions against the uncertainty of the test in terms of sensitivity and specificity, and its ability to “assess cross-reactivity” with other coronaviruses.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Widely shared social media post claim the US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) says that positive COVID-19 results simply mean people have previously contracted a cold. In reality, the claim is a misinterpretation of a paragraph discussing antibody tests on the CDC’s website. Health experts confirm COVID-19 is detected with viral tests, not an analysis of antibodies.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.boomlive.in/h-upload/2020/07/28/926470-cdc.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.boomlive.in/h-upload/2020/07/28/926470-cdc.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">6 Vitamin C Rich Foods Suggested BY FSSAI For Strong Immunity And Healthy Skin</title><link href="/6-Vitamin-C-Rich-Foods-Suggested-BY-FSSAI-For-Strong-Immunity-And-Healthy-Skin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 Vitamin C Rich Foods Suggested BY FSSAI For Strong Immunity And Healthy Skin" /><published>2020-07-29T16:31:02+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:31:02+05:30</updated><id>/6-Vitamin-C-Rich-Foods-Suggested-BY-FSSAI-For-Strong-Immunity-And-Healthy-Skin</id><content type="html" xml:base="/6-Vitamin-C-Rich-Foods-Suggested-BY-FSSAI-For-Strong-Immunity-And-Healthy-Skin/">&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C-Rich diet helps in building immunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights Vitamin C nutrient is known to boost immunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FSSAI suggested 6 vitamin C-rich plant-based. foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go through the list and these foods to your immunity-boosting diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good immune system means healthy you! Immunity is our front-runner line of defence against flu, virus and infections like cold, cough and fever. The ongoing pandemic of Coronavirus has made it even more important for us to boost our immunity, and there’s no better way than to do it with the help of our diet. The grapevine is full of diet tips and information, but what really could be worthy of our attention are the suggestions coming from FSSAI (Food Safety &amp;amp; Standards Authority of India) - the apex food regulator of India under the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FSSAI recently posted on Twitter declaring 5 plant-based foods that are rich in vitamin-C for building immunity that also contain various nutrients that may help improving our skin health as well. A lot has already been said about the nutrient of vitamin C and how it plays a significant role in stimulating our body’s immune system. FSSAI helped us in picking out 6 topmost vitamin C-rich plant-based foods that we must include in our everyday diet; here they are -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 vitamin C-rich foods for good immunity and skin health:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian gooseberry contains a range of polyphenols that are known to be excellent immunity boosters. Amla is also known as a great food for hair growth and skin health. You can have amla juice regularly or use it as pickle or murabba to accompany your meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: 5 Tips To Keep Fruits And Vegetables Clean According To FSSAI)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amla is good for hair and skin health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: istock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capsicum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capsicum is one of the most common vegetables that we use to cook meals - from various Indian dishes to a plethora of international dishes. Make sabzi, pasta, fried rice, sandwich and more such foods with this vegetable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orange is probably the most-sought after fruit for daily dose of vitamin C, and it rightly is. Juice it to have a glass of fresh orange juice every day or make desserts, salads or breakfast cereals with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guava&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the monsoon and winter start, guavas start swarming the vegetable markets. This nutrient-rich fruit comes at a time when building our immunity is even more crucial. So stock up guava in your kitchen and include it in your daily fruit serving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Papaya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This super-healthy fruit is available all year-round; that means we can reap its benefits all the time for a healthy body and beautiful skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another food recommended by health experts to consume every day for vitamin C-fix. The best way to do it is by drinking lemon water/lemonade every day. You can also garnish your salads, snacks and meals with a dash of lemon juice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: How To Keep Packaged Milk Clean Amid COVID-19?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lemon is rich in vitamin C nutrient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add these vitamin C-rich foods to your immunity-boosting diet and enjoy good health and gorgeous skin and hair.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Vitamin C-Rich diet helps in building immunity.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-06/e7630aho_vitamin-c_625x300_15_June_20.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-06/e7630aho_vitamin-c_625x300_15_June_20.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">72 of US adults are wearing masks what is the data for India</title><link href="/72-of-US-adults-are-wearing-masks-what-is-the-data-for-India/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="72 of US adults are wearing masks what is the data for India" /><published>2020-07-29T16:28:08+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:28:08+05:30</updated><id>/72-of-US-adults-are-wearing-masks-what-is-the-data-for-India-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/72-of-US-adults-are-wearing-masks-what-is-the-data-for-India/">&lt;p&gt;Over the past month the Covid map of India has transformed. Not only did 65% of the cases on Sunday come from outside Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu and Delhi, half of India’s districts now have over 500 cases each. On the good news front treatment protocols are greatly improved and testing capacity is being ramped up sharply in several places, efforts are underway for the country to do a million tests a day in a few weeks, and various vaccine trials are progressing well in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Google extending its global work from home option for employees till June 30 next year is just one of many indicators that the virus shall not be overcome anytime soon. Doing everything possible to arrest its spread is therefore imperative, to limit the wreckage of lives and livelihoods before a vaccine becomes available. Masks are a central part of this defense, their return on investment is quite incomparable. But reflective of the general scarcity of good data in India, we have no nationwide estimate of how prevalent mask wearing has become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Stanford University study suggests a great disparity in the quality of Covid-19 data reporting across India. Overall there is significant shortage of granular details like age, gender, comorbidities and even districts. But it is this granularity that can make some of the most productive interventions possible. On mask wearing, likewise, if we had the data we could put more public and even private resources into the regions or demographics that have not taken to the habit out of either cultural or financial reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the US, where of course there is a weird political constituency for the cause of not wearing masks, a Fortune magazine and SurveyMonkey poll suggests that 67% of all Americans now wear masks. More heavy-duty polling by Ipsos, Pew and Gallop also enables tracking behavioral improvement over the months. An online Gallup Panel survey conducted between June 29-July 5 found 54% of American women as compared to 34% American men saying that they always wear a mask outside their home, which maybe suggests the need to rope in some serious male/macho role models in public service campaigns about how masks save lives (and jobs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That overall 44% of US adults said they “always” wear a mask when outside their homes and 28% said they do so “very often” indicates how far this simple and yet powerful tool is still from the near universal adoption as seen in countries like Japan. What about India? What percentage of the population is masking up? Which segments are showing resistance? How much of this is for financial reasons? We don’t know. But we should find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is the dangling on the neck error. Another widely reported error is pulling down the mask just when one starts talking – Rajasthan CM Ashok Gehlot did this just last week while addressing a large group of mediapersons crowded next to him, Madhya Pradesh CM Shivraj Singh Chouhan did the same at no less than a Covid ward where he is admitted and from where he was broadcasting to the public with various health service providers also present in the ward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also people who are wearing the same mask days on end without washing it regularly. Without essential mask hygiene, like not touching its outer surface because that is at risk of virus deposits, the mask can become useless. Surely there is still not enough conversation about this. And this conversation needs to take place especially with all those who do not have the luxury of work from home, who are out and about in the great Unlock that hopes to put the country on the economic recovery path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, mask prices have dropped considerably. Surgical ones are to be had for Rs 5 now, and bulk prices would be much lower. Governments can make bulk purchases and organize mask distribution camps, where say a week’s supply is handed out alongside basic instructions. This would help put information about proper use into the wider ecosystem, where of course homemade masks also play a key role. Let’s get our act together on this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Over the past month the Covid map of India has transformed. Not only did 65% of the cases on Sunday come from outside Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu and Delhi, half of India’s districts now have over 500 cases each. On the good news front treatment protocols are greatly improved and testing capacity is being ramped up sharply in several places, efforts are underway for the country to do a million tests a day in a few weeks, and various vaccine trials are progressing well in the world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://static.toiimg.com/imagenext/toiblogs/photo/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Renuka-Bisht-1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://static.toiimg.com/imagenext/toiblogs/photo/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Renuka-Bisht-1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">21 Existing Drugs Identified Appear to Block SARS CoV 2 Replication in The Lab</title><link href="/21-Existing-Drugs-Identified-Appear-to-Block-SARS-CoV-2-Replication-in-The-Lab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="21 Existing Drugs Identified Appear to Block SARS CoV 2 Replication in The Lab" /><published>2020-07-29T16:27:48+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:27:48+05:30</updated><id>/21-Existing-Drugs-Identified-Appear-to-Block-SARS-CoV-2-Replication-in-The-Lab</id><content type="html" xml:base="/21-Existing-Drugs-Identified-Appear-to-Block-SARS-CoV-2-Replication-in-The-Lab/">&lt;p&gt;In an industry where getting one drug developed from lab to clinic can cost hundreds of millions of dollars and decades of time, it helps when scientists can be thrifty and make use of substances that already exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A global team of researchers has now done just that, by searching through one of the world’s largest collections of already developed drugs to discover 21 potential treatments for COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will need considerably more research to determine if any of these drugs can be used to help COVID-19 patients, but it’s an excellent first step, bypassing some of the barriers for producing completely new drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The development of a vaccine is likely to require at least 12-18 months, and the typical timeline for approval of a novel antiviral therapeutic can exceed 10 years,” the team writes in their new paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thus, repurposing of known drugs could significantly accelerate the deployment of novel therapies for COVID-19.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers took the ReFRAME Drug Repurposing Library - 11,987 compounds which have either received FDA approval or made it to clinical-trials – and began testing them against SARS-CoV-2 in a line of cells called Vero, cultured from the kidney of an African green monkey (Chlorocebus sp.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We realised early in the COVID-19 pandemic that ReFRAME would be an invaluable resource for screening for drugs to repurpose against the novel coronavirus,” says medical chemist and study co-author Arnab Chatterjee from Calibr, the drug discovery division of Scripps Research that created ReFRAME.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As was expected, the vast majority of the tests didn’t result in much, but the team did find 100 compounds that inhibited viral replication of SARS-CoV-2 in Vero cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team then demonstrated that 21 of those 100 compounds had a dose-response relationship – meaning the dose required to be effective wasn’t also likely to cause harm to humans. One of these was remdesivir, so that leaves 20 yet to be tested for COVID-19 treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of those 21 drugs, 13 were found to be effective at concentrations that could be safely used in COVID-19 patients and had previously entered clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This study significantly expands the possible therapeutic options for COVID-19 patients, especially since many of the molecules already have clinical safety data in humans,” said virologist Sumit Chanda from Sanford Burnham Prebys Medical Discovery Institute in California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This report provides the scientific community with a larger arsenal of potential weapons that may help bring the ongoing global pandemic to heel.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 21 drugs are currently being tested further using small animal models or mini lungs that can mimic human tissue. However, the team has already found three that worked in human stem cell-derived lung tissue, and one showed antiviral effects in a lab-based lung culture system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all exciting stuff, but as we’ve seen in many examples so far, caution is needed before rushing into the administration of new drugs, even during a pandemic - not all promising compounds will actually work against COVID-19, even if those drugs have been approved for other ailments in the past. The more treatments we have however, the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While some of these drugs are currently in clinical trials for COVID-19, we believe it’s important to pursue additional drug candidates so we have multiple therapeutic options,” says Chanda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research has been published in Nature.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">In an industry where getting one drug developed from lab to clinic can cost hundreds of millions of dollars and decades of time, it helps when scientists can be thrifty and make use of substances that already exist.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2020-07/processed/GettyImages-924655686_1_1024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.sciencealert.com/images/2020-07/processed/GettyImages-924655686_1_1024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>