<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-11T12:34:20+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">EPFO new rule EPF account will now get an additional benefit of up to Rs 7 lakh learn new decision</title><link href="/EPFO-new-rule-EPF-account-will-now-get-an-additional-benefit-of-up-to-Rs-7-lakh-learn-new-decision/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EPFO new rule EPF account will now get an additional benefit of up to Rs 7 lakh learn new decision" /><published>2020-09-11T11:30:15+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:30:15+05:30</updated><id>/EPFO-new-rule-EPF-account-will-now-get-an-additional-benefit-of-up-to-Rs-7-lakh-learn-new-decision</id><content type="html" xml:base="/EPFO-new-rule-EPF-account-will-now-get-an-additional-benefit-of-up-to-Rs-7-lakh-learn-new-decision/">&lt;p&gt;On the death of employees falling under the Employees Provident Fund Organization (EPFO), the limit for the maximum assurance to their dependents has been increased. Now the maximum insurance benefit will be 7 lakh rupees under the Employees Deposit Linked Insurance (EDLI) Scheme 1976, which is currently 6 lakh rupees. The decision was taken at a meeting of the Central Board of Trustees (CBT), EPF, chaired by Labor Minister Santosh Gangwar on Wednesday. The meeting was virtual and the interest rate on EPF was also fixed for the financial year 2019-20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CBT has decided to increase the maximum sum assured under the Employees Deposit Linked Insurance (EDLI) Scheme 1976 from the current Rs 6 lakh to Rs 7 lakh. For this, the Board has approved amendment in paragraph 22 (3) of EDLI 1976. With this decision, in case of unfortunate death of the members of the scheme, they will be able to provide additional help to the people / families dependent on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is EDLI Scheme&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EPFO also provides life insurance facility to its subscribers/member employees. All subscribers of EPFO ​​are covered under the EDLI 1976 scheme. The EDLI scheme can be claimed on behalf of the nominee of the Member Employee by the sickness, accident or natural death of the employee. Now this benefit is also being given to the aggrieved family of employees who have worked in more than one establishment within 12 months immediately before death. There is a lump sum payment. Employees do not have to pay any amount in EDLI. The company collects the premium in exchange for the employee.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">On the death of employees falling under the Employees Provident Fund Organization (EPFO), the limit for the maximum assurance to their dependents has been increased. Now the maximum insurance benefit will be 7 lakh rupees under the Employees Deposit Linked Insurance (EDLI) Scheme 1976, which is currently 6 lakh rupees. The decision was taken at a meeting of the Central Board of Trustees (CBT), EPF, chaired by Labor Minister Santosh Gangwar on Wednesday. The meeting was virtual and the interest rate on EPF was also fixed for the financial year 2019-20.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/money.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/money.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Facebook has a new plan to fight climate misinformation</title><link href="/Facebook-has-a-new-plan-to-fight-climate-misinformation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Facebook has a new plan to fight climate misinformation" /><published>2020-09-11T11:27:41+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:27:41+05:30</updated><id>/Facebook-has-a-new-plan-to-fight-climate-misinformation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Facebook-has-a-new-plan-to-fight-climate-misinformation/">&lt;p&gt;In the geographic heart of the tech industry Wednesday, it was hard to think of anything except the orange skies, dark and tinted by wildfire smoke. The image software on iPhones failed to capture the dystopian hue, or the feeling of being surrounded by it. Silicon Valley workers tweeted that it felt like night time, or a perpetual sunset, or a scene from “Blade Runner 2049.” It marked the fourth week of severe fire and ash in the Western US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation shifted from the already-apocalyptic pandemic to another global public health disaster: climate change. For those who don’t know, this is not what California is usually like. The first time I smelled smoke in my San Francisco apartment, in 2015, I imagined something nearby was on fire—not that it was happening miles north of the city. I turned on an air purifier, which I’d purchased for my partner’s allergies, never expecting it would be necessary for anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The climate disaster is undeniable to those who have experienced its harms, and a political talking point for the rest. Facebook is full of misinformation on the topic, which, when noticed and reported by users, is sent to the company’s third-party fact-checkers. Over the summer, a nonprofit called C02 Coalition, which claimed that carbon dioxide created by humans was beneficial for the planet, was banned from advertising on Facebook after too many fact violations. The group successfully appealed its ban, and had the fact-checks labels on its posts removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook said that it considered such posts to be opinions, ineligible for fact-checking, causing a miniature scandal when the checker, Climate Feedback, spoke out. ‘We don’t believe that articles in an opinion section should be immune from fact-checking,” Climate Feedback science editor Scott Johnson wrote in an email to Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook also doesn’t take the additional step of removing misinformation on the climate, because the company has ruled that such posts don’t cause imminent harm to human health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, in the aggregate, they do. Facebook has recently re-evaluated its approach to climate misinformation, according to spokesman Andy Stone. The company is working on a climate information center, which will display information from scientific sources. Stone said Facebook isn’t ready to officially announce anything, but it’s easy to imagine what this might look like. Facebook has already devised centers for factual information about Covid-19, and about voting and the upcoming election, both of which it has promoted heavily on its site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The info center approach would put less pressure on evaluating each individual post, in favor of directing users to what they need to know more about generally. It could plausibly be more effective than the fact-checking process, which sometimes takes days or weeks to complete, long after a claim has gone viral. Of course, it won’t help address individual disputed claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, to get the general idea of what’s going on, anyone in Silicon Valley can look out the window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story has been published from a wire agency feed without modifications to the text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to Mint Newsletters * Enter a valid email * Thank you for subscribing to our newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share Via&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">In the geographic heart of the tech industry Wednesday, it was hard to think of anything except the orange skies, dark and tinted by wildfire smoke. The image software on iPhones failed to capture the dystopian hue, or the feeling of being surrounded by it. Silicon Valley workers tweeted that it felt like night time, or a perpetual sunset, or a scene from “Blade Runner 2049.” It marked the fourth week of severe fire and ash in the Western US.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/2020-08-25T045025Z_2_LYNXMPEG7O07S_RTROPTP_3_FRANCE-FACEBOOK-TAX_1598349745521_1599737005508.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/2020-08-25T045025Z_2_LYNXMPEG7O07S_RTROPTP_3_FRANCE-FACEBOOK-TAX_1598349745521_1599737005508.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Study links sleep apnea to higher spine fracture risk among women</title><link href="/Study-links-sleep-apnea-to-higher-spine-fracture-risk-among-women/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Study links sleep apnea to higher spine fracture risk among women" /><published>2020-09-11T11:27:35+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:27:35+05:30</updated><id>/Study-links-sleep-apnea-to-higher-spine-fracture-risk-among-women</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Study-links-sleep-apnea-to-higher-spine-fracture-risk-among-women/">&lt;p&gt;Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) may negatively affect bone health, according to a new study published in the Journal of Bone and Mineral Research. Results from the study indicate that women with a history of OSA may face a higher risk of spine, or vertebral, fractures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using information from the Nurses’ Health Study, investigators examined data pertaining to 55,264 women without a prior history of bone fractures. OSA was self-reported in 1.3 percent of participants in 2002 and increased to 3.3 percent by 2012. Between 2002 and 2014, 461 vertebral fractures and 921 hip fractures occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Women with a history of OSA had a 2-fold higher risk of vertebral fracture relative to those with no OSA history, with the strongest association observed for OSA associated with daytime sleepiness. No association was observed between OSA history and risk of hip fracture. “Our study provides important evidence at the population level that obstructive sleep apnea may hurt bone health that is particularly relevant to the development of vertebral fracture,” said lead author Tianyi Huang, ScD, of Brigham and Women’s Hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Given that we used self-reported clinical diagnoses of sleep apnea and fracture in our study, future studies could use more deeply characterized data to further the understanding of the mechanisms linking sleep apnea to bone health and fracture risk,” Huang added.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) may negatively affect bone health, according to a new study published in the Journal of Bone and Mineral Research. Results from the study indicate that women with a history of OSA may face a higher risk of spine, or vertebral, fractures.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/10_09_2020_06_33_09_4878047.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/10_09_2020_06_33_09_4878047.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ayurveda You should not combine curd with these 5 foods</title><link href="/Ayurveda-You-should-not-combine-curd-with-these-5-foods/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ayurveda You should not combine curd with these 5 foods" /><published>2020-09-11T11:25:51+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:25:51+05:30</updated><id>/Ayurveda-You-should-not-combine-curd-with-these-5-foods</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Ayurveda-You-should-not-combine-curd-with-these-5-foods/">&lt;p&gt;A bowl of fresh and creamy curd topped with some chopped fruits is one the simplest joys of life. Apart from being a perfect meal accompaniment, curd also has a whole lot of health benefits. Loaded with calcium, vitamin B-2, vitamin B-12, magnesium and potassium, it’s also easy to digest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not many people know that curd should not be paired with certain food items. Pairing curd with the wrong food item can be harmful to your health. Here’s a list of 5 foods items curd should not be consumed with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">A bowl of fresh and creamy curd topped with some chopped fruits is one the simplest joys of life. Apart from being a perfect meal accompaniment, curd also has a whole lot of health benefits. Loaded with calcium, vitamin B-2, vitamin B-12, magnesium and potassium, it’s also easy to digest.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/78038917.cms" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/78038917.cms" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">China nod to nasal spray for Covid 19</title><link href="/China-nod-to-nasal-spray-for-Covid-19/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="China nod to nasal spray for Covid 19" /><published>2020-09-11T11:23:59+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:23:59+05:30</updated><id>/China-nod-to-nasal-spray-for-Covid-19</id><content type="html" xml:base="/China-nod-to-nasal-spray-for-Covid-19/">&lt;p&gt;China has approved for trials its first nasal spray vaccine to combat the novel coronavirus that has claimed over 904,000 lives and infected more than 27 million people globally, official media reported on Thursday. The phase I clinical trials are expected to start in November and will be tried out on 100 volunteers. It is the only vaccine of its type approved by China’s National Medical Products Administration, the state-run Global Times reported. The vaccine is a collaborative mission between Hong Kong and the Chinese mainland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microbiologist from the University of Hong Kong, Yuen Kwok-yung, said the vaccine stimulates the natural infection pathway of respiratory viruses to activate the immune response. Scientists do not expect side effects, except for minor nasal obstruction. It is not yet clear whether immunity generated from nasal spray vaccinations will last longer than from injected vaccines. The nasal spray vaccine uses live attenuated influenza vaccine; the other four technical routes China is using to develop the coronavirus vaccines are inactivated vaccines, adenoviral vector-based vaccines, and DNA and mRNA vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">China has approved for trials its first nasal spray vaccine to combat the novel coronavirus that has claimed over 904,000 lives and infected more than 27 million people globally, official media reported on Thursday. The phase I clinical trials are expected to start in November and will be tried out on 100 volunteers. It is the only vaccine of its type approved by China’s National Medical Products Administration, the state-run Global Times reported. The vaccine is a collaborative mission between Hong Kong and the Chinese mainland.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/freepressjournal%2Fimport%2F2013%2F02%2Fsinus.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/freepressjournal%2Fimport%2F2013%2F02%2Fsinus.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Plasma therapy has helped many patients Bengaluru researchers</title><link href="/Plasma-therapy-has-helped-many-patients-Bengaluru-researchers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plasma therapy has helped many patients Bengaluru researchers" /><published>2020-09-11T11:23:48+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:23:48+05:30</updated><id>/Plasma-therapy-has-helped-many-patients-Bengaluru-researchers</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Plasma-therapy-has-helped-many-patients-Bengaluru-researchers/">&lt;p&gt;BENGALURU: Doctors in the city do not share the recent conclusion of the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) that convalescent plasma therapy has not helped in reducing Covid-19 deaths. They say they have been using the therapy in clinical trials for moderate to severe patients and it has helped save many lives. An ICMR study has cast doubts on the benefits of the therapy, setting off a debate among experts.A team of researchers from HCG cancer hospital in Bengaluru had received the Drug Controller General of India’s nod to study the potential use of plasma therapy in moderate Covid-19 cases through clinical trials. The team collaborated with the Bangalore Medical College and Research Institute. HCG has since tied up with 55 hospitals in Karnataka and administered convalescent plasma to 430 patients.“We have seen improvement in nearly 60 per cent of the patients. We are writing to the ICMR in this regard,” said Dr US Vishal Rao, principal investigator of the research. “All our plasma transfusions were strictly monitored for antibodies and then administered. In the ICMR study, researchers have not checked the plasma for antibodies.”Since July, when the drug controller general allowed off-label use of convalescent plasma, multiple private hospitals have been using the therapy on their own.According to Dr C Shivaram, head of transfusion medicine at Manipal Hospitals, the ICMR study has not been able to demonstrate the benefits of plasma therapy unlike Mayo Clinic in the US, which showed a 37 per cent reduction in mortality. “One possible reason is poor patient selection. While the study was intended for moderate patients, undue pressure could have led to its use among severe patients,” said Dr Shivaram, adding that quantitation of antibodies through titres was not available when the ICMR study began. “Lack of standardisation of plasma is another point. When the ICMR trial began, there were no methods or kits to quantitate the antibody to SARS-CoV2 [virus that causes Covid-19] and hence, titration was made optional. This led to poor quality of plasma, with low titre of antibodies, being given to patients.”Another doctor said it was too early to say plasma was not useful: “What would have been the condition of patients had they not received plasma?”According to Dr Rao, the ICMR’s findings don’t match with other studies because neutralising antibody titres were not used. “A study conducted by the ICGEB-Emory Vaccine Centre said 50 per cent of the patients didn’t have neutralising antibodies. The study included many Delhi patients. If plasma without required antibodies is used, it may not be effective. It’s like giving paracetamol of 0.5mg to a patient with high fever,” Dr Rao said.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">BENGALURU: Doctors in the city do not share the recent conclusion of the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) that convalescent plasma therapy has not helped in reducing Covid-19 deaths. They say they have been using the therapy in clinical trials for moderate to severe patients and it has helped save many lives. An ICMR study has cast doubts on the benefits of the therapy, setting off a debate among experts.A team of researchers from HCG cancer hospital in Bengaluru had received the Drug Controller General of India’s nod to study the potential use of plasma therapy in moderate Covid-19 cases through clinical trials. The team collaborated with the Bangalore Medical College and Research Institute. HCG has since tied up with 55 hospitals in Karnataka and administered convalescent plasma to 430 patients.“We have seen improvement in nearly 60 per cent of the patients. We are writing to the ICMR in this regard,” said Dr US Vishal Rao, principal investigator of the research. “All our plasma transfusions were strictly monitored for antibodies and then administered. In the ICMR study, researchers have not checked the plasma for antibodies.”Since July, when the drug controller general allowed off-label use of convalescent plasma, multiple private hospitals have been using the therapy on their own.According to Dr C Shivaram, head of transfusion medicine at Manipal Hospitals, the ICMR study has not been able to demonstrate the benefits of plasma therapy unlike Mayo Clinic in the US, which showed a 37 per cent reduction in mortality. “One possible reason is poor patient selection. While the study was intended for moderate patients, undue pressure could have led to its use among severe patients,” said Dr Shivaram, adding that quantitation of antibodies through titres was not available when the ICMR study began. “Lack of standardisation of plasma is another point. When the ICMR trial began, there were no methods or kits to quantitate the antibody to SARS-CoV2 [virus that causes Covid-19] and hence, titration was made optional. This led to poor quality of plasma, with low titre of antibodies, being given to patients.”Another doctor said it was too early to say plasma was not useful: “What would have been the condition of patients had they not received plasma?”According to Dr Rao, the ICMR’s findings don’t match with other studies because neutralising antibody titres were not used. “A study conducted by the ICGEB-Emory Vaccine Centre said 50 per cent of the patients didn’t have neutralising antibodies. The study included many Delhi patients. If plasma without required antibodies is used, it may not be effective. It’s like giving paracetamol of 0.5mg to a patient with high fever,” Dr Rao said.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/photo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/photo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Coronavirus Who will get the vaccine first</title><link href="/Coronavirus-Who-will-get-the-vaccine-first/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coronavirus Who will get the vaccine first" /><published>2020-09-11T11:23:40+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:23:40+05:30</updated><id>/Coronavirus-Who-will-get-the-vaccine-first-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Coronavirus-Who-will-get-the-vaccine-first/">&lt;p&gt;Image copyright Getty Images&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If or when scientists succeed in making a coronavirus vaccine, there won’t be enough to go around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research labs and pharmaceutical companies are rewriting the rulebook on the time it takes to develop, test and manufacture an effective vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unprecedented steps are being taken to ensure roll-out of the vaccine is global. But there are concerns that the race to get one will be won by the richest countries, at the expense of the most vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So who will get it first, how much will it cost and, in a global crisis, how do we make sure nobody gets left behind?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vaccines to fight infectious diseases usually take years to develop, test and deliver. Even then, their success is not guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To date, only one human infectious disease has been totally eradicated - smallpox - and that took 200 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest - from polio to tetanus, measles, mumps and TB - we live with, or without, thanks to vaccinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How soon can we expect a coronavirus vaccine?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image copyright Reuters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trials involving thousands of people are already under way to see which vaccine can protect against Covid-19, the respiratory disease caused by coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A process that usually takes five to 10 years, from research to delivery, is being pared down to months. In the meantime, manufacturing is being scaled up - with investors and manufacturers risking billions of dollars to be ready to produce an effective vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russia says trials of its Sputnik-V vaccine have shown signs of an immune response in patients and mass vaccination will start in October. China says it has developed a successful vaccine that is being made available to its military personnel. But concerns have been raised about the speed at which both vaccines have been produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neither are on the World Health Organization’s list of vaccines that have reached phase three clinical trials - the stage that involves more widespread testing in humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these leading candidates hope to get their vaccine approved by the end of the year - although the WHO has said it does not expect to see widespread vaccinations against Covid-19 until the middle of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;British drug manufacturer AstraZeneca, which has the licence for the Oxford University vaccine, is ramping up its global manufacturing capacity and has agreed to supply 100 million doses to the UK alone and possibly two billion globally - should it prove successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pfizer and BioNTech, who say they have invested more than $1bn in their Covid-19 programme developing an mRNA vaccine, expect to be ready to seek some form of regulatory approval as early as October this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If approved, that would mean manufacturing up to 100 million doses by the end of 2020 and potentially more than 1.3 billion doses by the end of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are around 20 other pharmaceutical companies with clinical trials under way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all of them will succeed - normally only about 10% of vaccine trials are successful. The hope is that the global focus, new alliances, and common purpose will raise the odds this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even if one of these vaccines is successful, the immediate shortfall is clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preventing vaccine nationalism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governments are hedging their bets to secure potential vaccines, making deals for millions of doses with a range of candidates before anything has been officially certified or approved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK government, for example, has signed deals for undisclosed sums for six potential coronavirus vaccines that may or may not prove successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US hopes to get 300 million doses by January from its investment programme to fast-track a successful vaccine. The US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) has even advised states to be prepared for a vaccine roll-out as early as 1 November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not all countries are in a position to do likewise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organisations such the Medecins Sans Frontieres, often on the frontline delivering vaccines, say locking in advanced deals with pharmaceutical companies creates “a dangerous trend of vaccine nationalism by richer nations”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This in turn reduces global stocks available to the vulnerable in poorer countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, the price of life-saving vaccines has left countries struggling to fully immunise children against diseases such as meningitis, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Mariângela Simão, the WHO’s assistant director-general responsible for access to medicines and health products, says we need to ensure vaccine nationalism is held in check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The challenge will be to ensure equitable access - that all countries have access, not just those who can pay more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a global vaccine task force?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WHO is working with the epidemic response group, Cepi, and the Vaccine Alliance of governments and organisations, known as Gavi, to try to level the playing field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least 80 rich nations and economies, so far, have signed up to the global vaccine plan known as Covax, which aims to raise $2bn (£1.52bn) by the end of 2020 to help buy and fairly distribute a drug worldwide. The US, which wants to leave the WHO, is not one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By pooling resources in Covax, participants hope to guarantee 92 lower income countries, in Africa, Asia and Latin America, also get “rapid, fair and equitable access” to Covid-19 vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The facility is helping to fund a range of vaccine research and development work, and supporting manufacturers in scaling up production, where needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a wide portfolio of vaccine trials signed up to their programme, they are hoping at least one will be successful so they can deliver two billion doses of safe, effective vaccines by the end of 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“With COVID-19 vaccines we want things to be different,” says Gavi’s CEO Dr Seth Berkley. “If only the wealthiest countries in the world are protected, then international trade, commerce and society as a whole will continue to be hit hard as the pandemic continues to rage across the globe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much will it cost?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While billions of dollars are being invested in vaccine development, millions more are being pledged to buy and supply the vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prices per dose depend on the type of vaccine, the manufacturer and the number of doses ordered. Pharmaceutical company Moderna, for example, is reportedly selling access to its potential vaccine at between $32 and $37 a dose (£24 to £28).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AstraZeneca, on the other hand has said it will supply its vaccine “at cost” - or a few dollars per dose - during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Serum Institute of India (SSI), the world’s largest vaccine manufacturer by volume, is being backed by $150m from Gavi and the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation to make and deliver up to 100 million doses of the successful Covid-19 vaccines for India and low- and middle-income countries. They say the ceiling price will be $3 (£2.28) a dose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But patients receiving the vaccine are unlikely to be charged in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the UK, mass distribution will be via the NHS health service. Student doctors and nurses, dentists and vets could be trained to back up existing NHS staff in administering the jab en masse. Consultation is currently under way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other countries, such as Australia, have said they will offer free doses to their population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People receiving vaccines via humanitarian organisations - a vital cog in the global distribution wheel - will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the US, while the shot might be free, healthcare professionals could charge for administering the jab - leaving uninsured Americans possibly facing a vaccine bill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So who gets it first?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the pharmaceutical companies will be making the vaccine, they won’t be the ones who decide who gets vaccinated first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image copyright EPA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Each organisation or country will have to determine who it immunises first and how it does that,” Sir Mene Pangalos - AstraZeneca’s Executive Vice President told the BBC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the initial supply will be limited, reducing deaths and protecting health care systems are likely to be prioritised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gavi plan is that countries signed up to Covax, high or low income alike, will receive enough doses for 3% of their population - which would be enough to cover health and social care workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more vaccine is produced, allocation is increased to cover 20% of the population - this time prioritising over 65s and other vulnerable groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After everybody has received 20%, the vaccine would be distributed according to other criteria, such as country vulnerability and immediate threat of Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countries have until 18 September to commit to the programme and make their upfront payments by 9 October. Negotiations are still under way for many other elements of the allocation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The only certainty is that there won’t be enough - the rest is still up in the air,” says Dr Simao.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gavi insists richer participants can request enough doses to vaccinate between 10-50% of their population, but no country will receive enough doses to vaccinate more than 20% until all countries in the group have been offered this amount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Berkley says a small buffer of about 5% of the total number of available doses will be kept aside, “to build a stockpile to help with acute outbreaks and to support humanitarian organisations, for example to vaccinate refugees who may not otherwise have access”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you distribute a global vaccine?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image copyright Markel Redondo/ MSF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot depends on which vaccine is successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ideal vaccine has a lot to live up to. It needs to be affordable. It needs to generate strong, long-lasting immunity. It needs a simple refrigerated distribution system and manufacturers must be able to scale-up production rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WHO, UNICEF and Medecins Sans Frontieres (MFS / Doctors Without Borders), already have effective vaccination programmes in place around the world with the so called “cold chain” facilities - cooler trucks and solar fridges to keep vaccines at the right temperature as they travel from factory to field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But adding a new vaccine to the mix could pose huge logistical problems for those already facing a difficult environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vaccines usually need to be kept refrigerated - usually between 2C and 8C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not too much of a challenge in most developed countries, but can be an “immense task” where infrastructure is weak and electricity supply and refrigeration unstable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maintaining vaccines under cold chain is already one of the biggest challenges’ countries face and this will be exacerbated with the introduction of a new vaccine,” MSF medical adviser Barbara Saitta told the BBC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You will need to add more cold chain equipment, make sure you always have fuel (to run freezer and refrigerators in absence of electricity) and repair/replace them when they break and transport them wherever you need them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AstraZeneca has suggested their vaccine would need the regular cold chain between 2C and 8C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it looks like some candidate vaccines will need ultra-cold chain - storage at -60C or colder before being diluted and distributed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To keep the Ebola vaccine at -60°C or colder we had to use a special cold chain equipment to store and transport them, plus we had to train staff to use all this new equipment,” said Barbara Saitta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also the question of the target population. Vaccination programmes usually target children, so agencies will have to plan how to reach people that normally are not part of the immunization program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the world waits for the scientists to do their bit, many more challenges await. And vaccines are not the only weapon against coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Vaccines are not the only solution,” Says Dr Simao, of the WHO. “You need to have diagnostics. You need to have a way to decrease mortality, so you need therapeutics, and you need a vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Besides that, you need everything else - social distancing, avoiding crowded places and so on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I need to know about the coronavirus?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Image copyright Getty Images</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/_114295664_menmasks976_getty.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/_114295664_menmasks976_getty.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bose launches QuietComfort Earbuds Sport Earbuds and three new Frames</title><link href="/Bose-launches-QuietComfort-Earbuds-Sport-Earbuds-and-three-new-Frames/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bose launches QuietComfort Earbuds Sport Earbuds and three new Frames" /><published>2020-09-11T11:21:48+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:21:48+05:30</updated><id>/Bose-launches-QuietComfort-Earbuds-Sport-Earbuds-and-three-new-Frames</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Bose-launches-QuietComfort-Earbuds-Sport-Earbuds-and-three-new-Frames/">&lt;p&gt;Bose has launched a slew of products, including two wireless earbuds and three new audio sunglasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first and most important of these are the Bose QuietComfort Earbuds. These $280 pair are the company’s first in-ear truly wireless noise-canceling earphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, the QuietComfort Earbuds feature Bose’ active noise-canceling system that uses microphones and a new algorithm to cancel out ambient noise. The semi in-ear design ear tips also help block sound passively and feature fins to keep them in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the Bose Headphones 700, the QuietComfort Earbuds also feature customizable noise cancellation, where you can dial in the degree of cancellation if you want to let in some of the ambient sound. You can also enable full transparency to let in all of the ambient sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bose makes pretty bold claims regarding the sound, claiming you won’t find better sounding wireless earbuds. The company has tuned the QuietComfort Earbuds for a more natural sound and there’s also a new volume-optimized Active EQ feature that adjusts sound based on volume to make up for low frequency loss at lower volumes and prevents distortion at higher volumes. The QC Earbuds support Bluetooth 5.1 and the AAC codec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The QC Earbuds feature a touch sensitive outside surface and all controls are accessed using touch gestures. The Earbuds are also IPX4 rated for water and sweat resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The QC Earbuds come in two colors, Triple Black, and Soapstone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Bose claims 6 hours of battery life with continuous use and the charging case provides two additional charges for a total of 18 hours. The Earbuds can provide up to 2 hours of playback with a 2-hour charge and the charging case is Qi-certified for wireless charging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next is the Bose Sport Earbuds. These $180 wireless earbuds lack active noise-cancellation but are fairly similar otherwise. With the focus on workouts, the Sport Earbuds also feature IPX4 water-resistance and Bose’ StayHear Max tips with the semi in-ear design and a tiny wing to keep them in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the QC Earbuds, the Sport Earbuds support Bluetooth 5.0 but still have the same AAC support and Active EQ. They also have 5 hours of battery life and the case provides two more full charges for a total of 15 hours. Like the QC Earbuds, the Sport Earbuds also have a touch sensitive outside surface for controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sport Earbuds come in three colors, Baltic Blue, Glacier White, and Triple Black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bose also announced the second generation of its audio sunglasses. The new Bose Frames come in three versions, Soprano, Tenor, and Tempo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Soprano and Tenor are similar, with the main difference being the design. The Soprano have a cat eye lens design while the Tenor have a square frame. Other than that, both feature a nylon frame, high-gloss black finish, and polycarbonate polarized lenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both also feature swap-out lenses that can be replaced with optional mirrored rose gold and purple fade lenses for the Soprano, and Mirrored Silver and Mirrored Blue for Tenor. Or you could use your prescription lenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both also have the same Bose Open Ear Audio design that is said to be fuller and deeper sounding than previous generation models. They have 5.5 hours of battery life, and beamforming microphone array for voice calls. Both also feature touch sensitive sides for controlling volume and playback and have a motion sensor that detects when you remove them to turn them off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s the Bose Frames Tempo, which have a sporty design. They feature soft silicone nose pads that come in three sizes in the box. The included polycarbonate polarized lenses have a mirrored black finish with 12% VLT (visible light transmission) but can be swapped out for Road Orange that allows 20% VLT, Trail Blue that allows 28% VLT, and Twilight Yellow that allows 77% VLT. All of these are ideal for different environments and different time of day so you can pick based on your needs. Lastly, the Tempo is also IPX4 splash resistant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from these differences, the Tempo is similar to the Soprano and Tenor. All three are priced at $250.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Bose has launched a slew of products, including two wireless earbuds and three new audio sunglasses.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/gsmarena_006.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/gsmarena_006.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Company of Heroes finally arrives on Android with an excellent port</title><link href="/Company-of-Heroes-finally-arrives-on-Android-with-an-excellent-port/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Company of Heroes finally arrives on Android with an excellent port" /><published>2020-09-11T11:21:40+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:21:40+05:30</updated><id>/Company-of-Heroes-finally-arrives-on-Android-with-an-excellent-port</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Company-of-Heroes-finally-arrives-on-Android-with-an-excellent-port/">&lt;p&gt;Feral Interactive has ported a solid library of console-quality games to Android over the years, and today the studio has finally released Company of Heroes on Android. Feral originally brought this popular real-time strategy game to the iPad back in February (2020), and over the last few months, has been working on the smartphone version for both Android and iOS. So if you’re looking for a deep strategy game to dive into on your smartphone, starting today, you can grab Company of Heroes from the Play Store for $13.99.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re unfamiliar with Company of Heroes, the above trailer offers a quick look at what this strategy game will provide. Everything takes place in real-time, and as you can see, the game is themed around World War II. The gameplay is mostly comprised of micromanaging your squads (you control troops, not individuals) as you follow each level’s objectives. These objectives will range from simple things like moving your troops to certain locations to the more difficult tasks like winning close-quarter skirmishes. All in all, Company of Heroes plays like a traditional RTS, so things like resource management and base-building are also in the mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for performance, after testing the game on my Red Magic 5S and OnePlus 8, I can confirm Company of Heroes performs admirably. Load times are better than I expected, and the framerate is stable, even during demanding skirmishes. Really, the only thing I can see holding people back is the small UI. After all, Company of Heroes started as a PC game designed to be controlled with a mouse, and while the touch controls in today’s port work well enough, you’ll still have to deal with a few tiny buttons as well as limited screen space. And there’s no getting out of this. The entire game is built around touch controls, and it does not support controllers. This also means the game does not support the Nvidia Shield, though this isn’t surprising since this port was explicitly designed for smartphones. There also appears to be no way to play online, so it would seem this feature was removed for the mobile version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all of Feral’s mobile ports, Company of Heroes is a premium release. This means you’ll have to plunk down $13.99 if you’d like to play. To put this price into perspective, Company of Heroes is still selling for $19.99 on Steam. So the Android port is priced rather competitively, which is always lovely to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we’ve known that Company of Heroes would come to Android since April (2020), and while it feels like it’s been a long wait, it’s finally here, and I’m glad to report that the wait was worth it. Not only is this a solid port that performs well, but the game itself is also pretty dang fun, especially if you enjoy real-time strategy games. While the small UI, lack of online play, and $14 price tag may hold a few people back from taking the plunge, there’s no denying that console-quality strategy games are hard to come by on Android. So if you don’t mind a few caveats, you can grab Company of Heroes from the Play Store widget below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">Feral Interactive has ported a solid library of console-quality games to Android over the years, and today the studio has finally released Company of Heroes on Android. Feral originally brought this popular real-time strategy game to the iPad back in February (2020), and over the last few months, has been working on the smartphone version for both Android and iOS. So if you’re looking for a deep strategy game to dive into on your smartphone, starting today, you can grab Company of Heroes from the Play Store for $13.99.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/Company-of-Heroes.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/Company-of-Heroes.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">WhatsApp Spotted Working on Catalogue Shortcut New Call Button Features in Latest Android Beta Report</title><link href="/WhatsApp-Spotted-Working-on-Catalogue-Shortcut-New-Call-Button-Features-in-Latest-Android-Beta-Report/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WhatsApp Spotted Working on Catalogue Shortcut New Call Button Features in Latest Android Beta Report" /><published>2020-09-11T11:21:37+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-11T11:21:37+05:30</updated><id>/WhatsApp-Spotted-Working-on-Catalogue-Shortcut-New-Call-Button-Features-in-Latest-Android-Beta-Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="/WhatsApp-Spotted-Working-on-Catalogue-Shortcut-New-Call-Button-Features-in-Latest-Android-Beta-Report/">&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp is reportedly working on several improvements, and some of them were spotted in the code of the latest Android beta. This includes a new Catalogue Shortcut for business accounts enabling quick access to their product portfolio. There is also a new ‘Add WhatsApp Doodles’ option that is under development allowing users to make their solid wallpaper look a bit more fancy. Separately, a new ‘Call’ button is also under works. This new call button looks to slightly tweak the process of making video and voice calls inside the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WABetaInfo, which tracks new features in WhatsApp, dug into the latest WhatsApp 2.20.200.3 beta for Android to spot several new features. The first one is the possible addition of a quick shortcut in business chats, when the business has set a catalogue. This catalogue icon will be added next to the Call button whenever it arrives. This new shortcut is under development and will not be seen even if users are on the latest beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separately, WhatsApp is also working on a new Call button that will combine the video and voice call shortcuts into one. Currently, we see separate icons in chats for video and voice calls, but this new button looks to combine the two, and when you tap on the button, it will allow choosing the call type. This new shortcut could tweak the process of calls a little bit. It is under development and is reported to be available in a future build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tracker says that this new call button will initially be available in business chats only WhatsApp may later expand the feature for other chats too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp is also working on several wallpaper improvements, as reported in the past, and one of the new improvements is the ability to add doodles on a solid chat wallpaper in chats A new ‘Add WhatsApp Doddles’ option has been spotted in WhatsApp 2.20.200.3 beta for Android enabling users to superimpose doodles in chat wallpapers. Again, this feature is also not enabled for beta users yet and was only found in the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2020, will WhatsApp get the killer feature that every Indian is waiting for? We discussed this on Orbital, our weekly technology podcast, which you can subscribe to via Apple Podcasts or RSS, download the episode, or just hit the play button below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">WhatsApp is reportedly working on several improvements, and some of them were spotted in the code of the latest Android beta. This includes a new Catalogue Shortcut for business accounts enabling quick access to their product portfolio. There is also a new ‘Add WhatsApp Doodles’ option that is under development allowing users to make their solid wallpaper look a bit more fancy. Separately, a new ‘Call’ button is also under works. This new call button looks to slightly tweak the process of making video and voice calls inside the app.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/whatsapp_android_wabetainfo_1599715760636.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/11-09-2020/whatsapp_android_wabetainfo_1599715760636.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>