<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-10T12:30:50+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Big Tech Antitrust Hearing Facebook s Mark Zuckerberg Skewered With Internal Emails</title><link href="/Big-Tech-Antitrust-Hearing-Facebook-s-Mark-Zuckerberg-Skewered-With-Internal-Emails/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Big Tech Antitrust Hearing Facebook s Mark Zuckerberg Skewered With Internal Emails" /><published>2020-07-30T14:02:45+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-30T14:02:45+05:30</updated><id>/Big-Tech-Antitrust-Hearing-Facebook-s-Mark-Zuckerberg-Skewered-With-Internal-Emails</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Big-Tech-Antitrust-Hearing-Facebook-s-Mark-Zuckerberg-Skewered-With-Internal-Emails/">&lt;p&gt;Facebook Chief Executive Mark Zuckerberg stumbled at a congressional hearing on alleged abuse of market power on Wednesday, as lawmakers confronted the social media titan with damaging internal emails about the company’s acquisitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The House Judiciary Committee’s antitrust panel appeared to draw on a rich trove of Facebook company emails, releasing numerous screenshots of correspondence from Zuckerberg and other Facebook executives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the exchanges, lawmakers got Zuckerberg to acknowledge that he saw photo-sharing app Instagram and messaging app WhatsApp as competitors when Facebook acquired them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The businesses are nascent but…if they grow to a large scale they could be very disruptive to us,” Zuckerberg wrote in 2012, two months before the Instagram purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another email, written the same day Facebook announced the acquisition, Zuckerberg conceded that “Instagram was our threat,” adding: “one thing about startups though is you can often acquire them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representative Joe Neguse, a Democrat, noted that a 2014 email showed Facebook’s CFO referring to the company’s acquisition strategy as a “land grab.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We have name for this; it is monopoly,” Neguse said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The committee presented fewer such exchanges to the other executives testifying at the hearing, which also featured Amazon’s Jeff Bezos, Alphabet-owned Google’s Sundar Pichai and Apple’s Tim Cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Democratic Representative Pramila Jayapal used an email to grill Zuckerberg on whether Facebook copied competitors like Snapchat for anti-competitive reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How many competitors did Facebook end up copying?” she asked. “I don’t know,” Zuckerberg answered, stammering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She asked if Facebook had ever threatened to clone a competitor’s feature while negotiating to buy them. “I would like to just remind you that you are under oath and there are quotes from Facebook’s own documents,” she told him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documents also shed new light on how the social media giant saw the competitive landscape. In a 2012 graphic, Facebook touted the company as “95 percent of all social media in the US.” The graphic was titled: “The industry consolidates as it matures.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© Thomson Reuters 2020&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">Facebook Chief Executive Mark Zuckerberg stumbled at a congressional hearing on alleged abuse of market power on Wednesday, as lawmakers confronted the social media titan with damaging internal emails about the company’s acquisitions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/facebook_zuckerberg_antitrust_hearing_reuters_1596084842807.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/facebook_zuckerberg_antitrust_hearing_reuters_1596084842807.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">88 Indian workforce prefers WFH flexibility manual finance processes cause Rs 16 000 crore loss</title><link href="/88-Indian-workforce-prefers-WFH-flexibility-manual-finance-processes-cause-Rs-16-000-crore-loss/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="88 Indian workforce prefers WFH flexibility manual finance processes cause Rs 16 000 crore loss" /><published>2020-07-30T13:54:04+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-30T13:54:04+05:30</updated><id>/88-Indian-workforce-prefers-WFH-flexibility-manual-finance-processes-cause-Rs-16-000-crore-loss</id><content type="html" xml:base="/88-Indian-workforce-prefers-WFH-flexibility-manual-finance-processes-cause-Rs-16-000-crore-loss/">&lt;p&gt;Around 88 per cent of workforce in India prefers to have the flexibility to work from home (WFH), and 69 per cent of Indian employees believe their efficiency has increased while working remotely – highest in the Asia Pacific region, according to a report by SAP Concur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the report, many Indian firms still run manual finance and administrative processes, resulting in inefficiencies that lead to productivity losses, which is estimated to be to the tune of over Rs 16,800 crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For latest updates and live news on coronavirus, click here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Remote work will be the default mode of work for many organisations in the foreseeable future. Embracing this change, 88 per cent of employees in India have expressed their preference to have the flexibility of remote working,” the SAP Concur report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reported is based on a survey, conducted in May, of 300 senior management to executive level employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It found that 69 per cent of Indian employees believe their productivity has increased while working from home, which is higher than their other APAC counterparts with an overall average of 60 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These figures show positive signs of large scale acceptance of the upcoming ‘new normal’ in the country at a time when Covid-19 pandemic has forced the companies to implement remote working almost overnight,” the report said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian employees spent an average of 6.1 hours per month filing expense claims, more than half of a typical workday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Managers had it worse – they spent an additional 7.3 hours reviewing and approving expense claims with the total time adding up to an astonishing 13.4 hours a month,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the report, merely 11 per cent of Indian organisations have embraced end-to-end digital finance and administrative processes which take up significant employee time that can otherwise be used for productive work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across India, 36 per cent of mid-large sized companies are still using manual processes for submitting business expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asia Insight, the entity which conducted the survey, used International Labour Organization (ILO) statistics on output per worker and the number of workers, and the survey’s results to calculate the impact of manual process in terms of potential revenue loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It derived that saving just 10 per cent of the time spent on filing and approving claims would translate to US 2.25 billion (Rs 16,827 crore) of potential GDP revenue gain for India each year, assuming all the lost hours are diverted to productive work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CORONAVIRUS SPECIAL COVERAGE ONLY ON DH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“2020 is proving to be a turning point for companies in terms of managing employee experience and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While employees working remotely are being supported digitally in many areas, there still exists a major gap in digital adoption for crucial yet often overlooked finance and administrative processes,” Mankiran Chowhan, Managing Director – Indian Subcontinent, SAP Concur said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said bringing in digital transformation for expense claims or invoice processing can have a huge multiplier effect on business and cost control, and at the same time provide the operational agility needed for business continuity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the inefficiency costs, the study also found that current expense management systems’ support for modern payment methods is inadequate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“More than a third (39 per cent) of respondents said they want their expense management software to integrate with external apps to enable added functionality like reimbursement of payments made through apps,” it said.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">Around 88 per cent of workforce in India prefers to have the flexibility to work from home (WFH), and 69 per cent of Indian employees believe their efficiency has increased while working remotely – highest in the Asia Pacific region, according to a report by SAP Concur.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.deccanherald.com/sites/dh/files/articleimages/2020/07/30/iStock-1069549614-1596070334.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.deccanherald.com/sites/dh/files/articleimages/2020/07/30/iStock-1069549614-1596070334.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">6 Vitamin C Rich Foods Suggested BY FSSAI For Strong Immunity And Healthy Skin</title><link href="/6-Vitamin-C-Rich-Foods-Suggested-BY-FSSAI-For-Strong-Immunity-And-Healthy-Skin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 Vitamin C Rich Foods Suggested BY FSSAI For Strong Immunity And Healthy Skin" /><published>2020-07-30T13:38:50+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-30T13:38:50+05:30</updated><id>/6-Vitamin-C-Rich-Foods-Suggested-BY-FSSAI-For-Strong-Immunity-And-Healthy-Skin</id><content type="html" xml:base="/6-Vitamin-C-Rich-Foods-Suggested-BY-FSSAI-For-Strong-Immunity-And-Healthy-Skin/">&lt;p&gt;Vitamin C-Rich diet helps in building immunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights Vitamin C nutrient is known to boost immunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FSSAI suggested 6 vitamin C-rich plant-based. foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go through the list and these foods to your immunity-boosting diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good immune system means healthy you! Immunity is our front-runner line of defence against flu, virus and infections like cold, cough and fever. The ongoing pandemic of Coronavirus has made it even more important for us to boost our immunity, and there’s no better way than to do it with the help of our diet. The grapevine is full of diet tips and information, but what really could be worthy of our attention are the suggestions coming from FSSAI (Food Safety &amp;amp; Standards Authority of India) - the apex food regulator of India under the Ministry of Health and Family Welfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FSSAI recently posted on Twitter declaring 5 plant-based foods that are rich in vitamin-C for building immunity that also contain various nutrients that may help improving our skin health as well. A lot has already been said about the nutrient of vitamin C and how it plays a significant role in stimulating our body’s immune system. FSSAI helped us in picking out 6 topmost vitamin C-rich plant-based foods that we must include in our everyday diet; here they are -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 vitamin C-rich foods for good immunity and skin health:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indian gooseberry contains a range of polyphenols that are known to be excellent immunity boosters. Amla is also known as a great food for hair growth and skin health. You can have amla juice regularly or use it as pickle or murabba to accompany your meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: 5 Tips To Keep Fruits And Vegetables Clean According To FSSAI)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amla is good for hair and skin health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: istock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capsicum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Capsicum is one of the most common vegetables that we use to cook meals - from various Indian dishes to a plethora of international dishes. Make sabzi, pasta, fried rice, sandwich and more such foods with this vegetable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orange is probably the most-sought after fruit for daily dose of vitamin C, and it rightly is. Juice it to have a glass of fresh orange juice every day or make desserts, salads or breakfast cereals with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guava&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the monsoon and winter start, guavas start swarming the vegetable markets. This nutrient-rich fruit comes at a time when building our immunity is even more crucial. So stock up guava in your kitchen and include it in your daily fruit serving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Papaya&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This super-healthy fruit is available all year-round; that means we can reap its benefits all the time for a healthy body and beautiful skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is another food recommended by health experts to consume every day for vitamin C-fix. The best way to do it is by drinking lemon water/lemonade every day. You can also garnish your salads, snacks and meals with a dash of lemon juice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also Read: How To Keep Packaged Milk Clean Amid COVID-19?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lemon is rich in vitamin C nutrient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add these vitamin C-rich foods to your immunity-boosting diet and enjoy good health and gorgeous skin and hair.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Vitamin C-Rich diet helps in building immunity.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-06/e7630aho_vitamin-c_625x300_15_June_20.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://c.ndtvimg.com/2020-06/e7630aho_vitamin-c_625x300_15_June_20.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">21 drugs that could help to treat COVID 19</title><link href="/21-drugs-that-could-help-to-treat-COVID-19/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="21 drugs that could help to treat COVID 19" /><published>2020-07-30T13:27:45+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-30T13:27:45+05:30</updated><id>/21-drugs-that-could-help-to-treat-COVID-19</id><content type="html" xml:base="/21-drugs-that-could-help-to-treat-COVID-19/">&lt;p&gt;A study recently identified 21 existing drugs that could improve the effect of remdesivir&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remdesivir, produced by Gilead Sciences, has been marked as the drug that can fight COVID-19. Think of remdesivir then as a superhero – how much of an impact would it make without the support of others? Other drugs could significantly impact how well remdesivir acts in the human body, and make the crucial difference for patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Nature study authored by a global team of scientists and led by Sumit Chanda, PhD, professor at Sanford Burnham Prebys Medical Discovery Institute, has identified 21 existing drugs that stop the replication of SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scientists analysed one of the world’s largest collections of known drugs for their ability to block the replication of SARS-CoV-2, and reported 100 molecules with confirmed antiviral activity in laboratory tests. Of these, 21 drugs were determined to be effective at concentrations that could be safely achieved in patients. Notably, four of these compounds were found to work synergistically with remdesivir, a current standard-of-care treatment for COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chanda, director of the Immunity and Pathogenesis Program at Sanford Burnham Prebys and senior author of the study, commented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Remdesivir has proven successful at shortening the recovery time for patients in the hospital, but the drug doesn’t work for everyone who receives it. That’s not good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As infection rates continue to rise in America and around the world, the urgency remains to find affordable, effective, and readily available drugs that can complement the use of remdesivir, as well as drugs that could be given prophylactically or at the first sign of infection on an outpatient basis.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story behind the 21 drugs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the study, the research team performed extensive testing and validation studies, including evaluating the drugs on human lung biopsies that were infected with the virus, evaluating the drugs for synergies with remdesivir, and establishing dose-response relationships between the drugs and antiviral activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 21 drugs that were effective at blocking viral replication, the scientists found:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13 have previously entered clinical trials for other indications and are effective at concentrations, or doses, that could potentially be safely achieved in COVID-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two are already FDA approved: astemizole (allergies), clofazamine (leprosy), and remdesivir has received Emergency Use Authorization from the agency (COVID-19).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four worked synergistically with remdesivir, including the chloroquine derivative hanfangchin A (tetrandrine), an antimalarial drug that has reached Phase 3 clinical trials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chanda further said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This study significantly expands the possible therapeutic options for COVID-19 patients, especially since many of the molecules already have clinical safety data in humans. This report provides the scientific community with a larger arsenal of potential weapons that may help bring the ongoing global pandemic to heel.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Based on our current analysis, clofazimine, hanfangchin A, apilimod and ONO 5334 represent the best near-term options for an effective COVID-19 treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While some of these drugs are currently in clinical trials for COVID-19, we believe it’s important to pursue additional drug candidates so we have multiple therapeutic options if SARS-CoV-2 becomes drug resistant.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers are currently testing all 21 compounds in small animal models and “mini lungs,” or lung organoids, that mimic human tissue. If these studies are favourable, the team will approach the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to discuss a clinical trial evaluating the drugs as treatments for COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examining over 12,000 drugs to find 21&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drugs were first identified by high-throughput screening of more than 12,000 drugs from the ReFRAME drug repurposing collection–the most comprehensive drug repurposing collection of compounds that have been approved by the FDA for other diseases or that have been tested extensively for human safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arnab Chatterjee, PhD, vice president of medicinal chemistry at Calibr and co-author on the paper, says ReFRAME was established to tackle areas of urgent unmet medical need, especially neglected tropical diseases. Dr Chatterjee commented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We realized early in the COVID-19 pandemic that ReFRAME would be an invaluable resource for screening for drugs to repurpose against the novel coronavirus,” says Chatterjee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drug screen was completed as rapidly as possible due to Chanda’s partnership with the scientist who discovered the first SARS virus, Kwok-Yung Yuen, M.D., chair of Infectious Diseases at the University of Hong Kong; and Shuofeng Yuan, Ph.D., assistant research professor in the Department of Microbiology at the University of Hong Kong, who had access to the SARS-CoV-2 virus in February 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">A study recently identified 21 existing drugs that could improve the effect of remdesivir</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.openaccessgovernment.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/lab-rem.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.openaccessgovernment.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/lab-rem.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">78 Covid 19 patients develop heart condition study finds</title><link href="/78-Covid-19-patients-develop-heart-condition-study-finds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="78 Covid 19 patients develop heart condition study finds" /><published>2020-07-30T13:14:19+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-30T13:14:19+05:30</updated><id>/78-Covid-19-patients-develop-heart-condition-study-finds</id><content type="html" xml:base="/78-Covid-19-patients-develop-heart-condition-study-finds/">&lt;p&gt;It is not just the lungs that get severely affected in coronavirus disease (Covid-19) patients but also the heart, according to a new study that found that as many of 78% of Covid-19 patients monitored developing a heart condition, independent of pre-existing conditions. To be sure, the study was based on a small sample and needs further (and more extensive) research and validation, but it adds to the number of body organs affected by the virus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study also found that 60% of those infected with Sars-Cov-2, the virus that causes Covid-19, had an ongoing myocardial inflammation (swelling of heart muscles); it has been published in the journal ‘JAMA Cardiology’ on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click here for full Covid-19 coverage&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study, Outcomes of Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance Imaging in Patients Recently Recovered From Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19), looked at the cardiovascular effects in patients who suffered from Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data from about 100 recovered patients from the University Hospital, Frankfurt’s Covid-19 registry between April and June 2020 was analysed for the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…cardiac magnetic resonance imaging revealed cardiac involvement in 78 patients (78%) and ongoing myocardial inflammation in 60 patients (60%), which was independent of preexisting conditions, severity and overall course of the acute illness, and the time from the original diagnosis,” the study added. .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers emphasise upon the need for studying in detail long-term cardiovascular consequences of Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts in India have also been asking for examination of clinical data to know the long-term health impact among Covid-19 patients post recovery as there have been observations made by clinicians on recently recovered patients experiencing long-term effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is a huge percentage, and looks like induced by virus or its after-effects such as inflammation. There is a need for large studies to reach a conclusion but that would require funding and access to data,” says Dr Giridhara Babu, head, Life Course epidemiology, Indian Institute of Public Health, Public Health Foundation of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clinicians here have observed that Covid-19 leads to other long-term health complications involving kidneys, liver, even eyes in patients after discharge from hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The joint monitoring group under the Union health ministry’s technical wing- Directorate General of Health Services, is independently reviewing clinical data available so far to draft guidelines for managing post-recovery health complications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our experts are working on putting a document together to guide people on what kind of long-term care would be required,” said Rajesh Bhushan, officer on special duty, health ministry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group is chaired by Dr Rajiv Garg, director general health services, along with specialist doctors from the All India Institute of Medical Sciences, Delhi, and representatives of the Indian Council of Medical Research (ICMR) and World Health Organisation (WHO) office in India .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data is being collected from several hospitals across the country that are treating Covid-19 patients. The hospitals include three from Delhi: The central government-run Safdarjung Hospital, Ram Manohar Lohia Hospital, and Lady Hardinge Hospital. Apart from these, clinical data is also being sought from six other All India Institute of Medical Sciences that treat Covid-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">It is not just the lungs that get severely affected in coronavirus disease (Covid-19) patients but also the heart, according to a new study that found that as many of 78% of Covid-19 patients monitored developing a heart condition, independent of pre-existing conditions. To be sure, the study was based on a small sample and needs further (and more extensive) research and validation, but it adds to the number of body organs affected by the virus.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.hindustantimes.com/rf/image_size_960x540/HT/p2/2020/07/30/Pictures/assignment-name-in-brief_95b1ef6c-d1df-11ea-9021-e9155cd8ee83.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.hindustantimes.com/rf/image_size_960x540/HT/p2/2020/07/30/Pictures/assignment-name-in-brief_95b1ef6c-d1df-11ea-9021-e9155cd8ee83.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Moderna aims to price coronavirus vaccine at 50 60 per course Report</title><link href="/Moderna-aims-to-price-coronavirus-vaccine-at-50-60-per-course-Report/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moderna aims to price coronavirus vaccine at 50 60 per course Report" /><published>2020-07-29T17:23:58+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T17:23:58+05:30</updated><id>/Moderna-aims-to-price-coronavirus-vaccine-at-50-60-per-course-Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Moderna-aims-to-price-coronavirus-vaccine-at-50-60-per-course-Report/">&lt;p&gt;The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters. The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderna Inc is planning to price its coronavirus vaccine at $50 to $60 per course, at least $11 more than another vaccine from Pfizer Inc and BioNTech, the Financial Times reported on Tuesday, citing unnamed sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderna’s proposed price for a two-dose course sold to governments compares with $39 for two doses under a deal that Pfizer Inc and German partner BioNTech struck with the U.S. government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industry analysts said Pfizer and BioNTech’s $2 billion deal to cover 50 million patients, which is contingent on an approvable product, would likely pressure other manufacturers to set similar prices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderna’s proposed price would apply to the United States and other high-income countries, according to the report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;READ&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Covid-19 vaccine tracker, July 29: Pfizer-BioNTech on the heels of Moderna, enters late stage clinical trials&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Moderna spokesperson said the company was in discussions with governments about potential supply of the vaccine, called mRNA-1273, but did not provide any details on pricing “given the confidential nature of the discussions and contracts.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pfizer, Moderna and Merck &amp;amp; Co have said they plan to sell their vaccines at a profit, while some drugmakers, including Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson have announced plans to price their vaccines on a not-for-profit basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Also read&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Why India will remain a central player in the development of vaccines&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AstraZeneca Plc agreed to provide the United States 300 million doses of its potential vaccine in exchange for $1.2 billion in upfront funding, which works out to $4 per dose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US government has provided Moderna with nearly $1 billion in funding to support its research and development efforts for its potential COVID-19 vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;READ&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Moderna vaccine protects 16 monkeys from coronavirus; 30,000 humans await&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus Explained Covid-19 vaccine tracker: Pfizer-BioNTech on the heels of Moderna&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India coronavirus numbers explained: Many states yet to ramp up tests&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply Put: In market high, some fears Click here for more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The funding is part of “Operation Warp Speed,” an initiative by the Trump administration to hasten the production of an inoculation for COVID-19, which has so far killed around 650,000 people worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 The Indian Express is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@indianexpress) and stay updated with the latest headlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the latest Coronavirus Outbreak News, download Indian Express App.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters. The final price for Moderna’s COVID vaccine has yet to be determined, a person familiar with the discussions told Reuters.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.indianexpress.com/2020/05/moderna.jpg?w=759" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.indianexpress.com/2020/05/moderna.jpg?w=759" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Exclusive Samsung making three Galaxy S21 models in other words water is wet</title><link href="/Exclusive-Samsung-making-three-Galaxy-S21-models-in-other-words-water-is-wet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exclusive Samsung making three Galaxy S21 models in other words water is wet" /><published>2020-07-29T16:44:25+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:44:25+05:30</updated><id>/Exclusive-Samsung-making-three-Galaxy-S21-models-in-other-words-water-is-wet-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Exclusive-Samsung-making-three-Galaxy-S21-models-in-other-words-water-is-wet/">&lt;p&gt;Our ever-reliable sources have revealed to us that Samsung’s 2021 flagship Galaxy S lineup will have three different models. That shouldn’t come as a surprise for anyone who hasn’t been living under a rock for the last year or two. The Galaxy S10 was the first Galaxy S series to come in three sizes, and Samsung stuck with that routine for the Galaxy S20 series. Next year looks set to be the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this moment, Samsung has started developing the 5G variants of the three Galaxy S21 models, using model numbers SM-G991, SM-G996, and SM-G998. If Samsung doesn’t mix up the naming scheme, these devices should launch as the Galaxy S21, Galaxy S21+, and Galaxy S21 Ultra, though nothing can be said for certain at this point in time. There will probably be LTE variants as well, but we can’t currently see any sign of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;128GB and 256GB storage variants, but there could be more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also told the three Galaxy S21 models are currently in development with 128GB and 256GB of storage. That is probably not a complete list, or maybe it is. Samsung has already done away with 1TB variants of its flagship phones – the last Galaxy flagship to ship with 1TB of internal storage was the Galaxy S10+, and in a post-COVID world where people are less willing to spend huge sums of money on phones, maybe Samsung will cancel the 512GB option as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all that is speculation. Although the rumor mill sprung into action months ago, it’s too early to say what the Galaxy S21 lineup will be like. Of course, you can depend on us to break more information about the Galaxy S21 as time goes on. Till then, there’s the Galaxy Note 20 and Galaxy Note 20 Ultra to look forward to, along with the third foldable phone from Samsung, all of which will go official on August 5.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Our ever-reliable sources have revealed to us that Samsung’s 2021 flagship Galaxy S lineup will have three different models. That shouldn’t come as a surprise for anyone who hasn’t been living under a rock for the last year or two. The Galaxy S10 was the first Galaxy S series to come in three sizes, and Samsung stuck with that routine for the Galaxy S20 series. Next year looks set to be the same.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.sammobile.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Galaxy-S20-hands-on-9-720x405.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.sammobile.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/Galaxy-S20-hands-on-9-720x405.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Google AR Search Reportedly Adds 23 New Insects Context Link Spotted in Google News</title><link href="/Google-AR-Search-Reportedly-Adds-23-New-Insects-Context-Link-Spotted-in-Google-News/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google AR Search Reportedly Adds 23 New Insects Context Link Spotted in Google News" /><published>2020-07-29T16:44:02+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:44:02+05:30</updated><id>/Google-AR-Search-Reportedly-Adds-23-New-Insects-Context-Link-Spotted-in-Google-News</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Google-AR-Search-Reportedly-Adds-23-New-Insects-Context-Link-Spotted-in-Google-News/">&lt;p&gt;Google has reportedly added 23 new insects to its AR search feature, allowing users to virtually see them roaming in their homes. The new insects added to AR search include various kinds of beetles, butterflies, and cicadas. Separately, Google is also testing a new ‘For Context’ feature in Google News. This feature will essentially give you a broader perspective on the primary news search. The contextual link shows up right below the main news, and this context link is usually from the same publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Verge reports that Google has added 23 new insects in its AR Search results. This includes rhinoceros beetle, Hercules beetle, Atlas beetle, stag beetle, giant stag, Miyama stag beetle, shining ball scarab beetle, jewel beetle, ladybug, firefly, Rosalia batesi, swallowtail butterfly, morpho butterfly, atlas moth, mantis, grasshopper, dragonfly, hornet, robust cicada, brown cicada, periodical cicada, Walker’s cicada, and evening cicada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has added various kinds of beetles and cicadas to AR Search&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credit: The Verge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To search for the new insects, type the name in search and then click on the ‘View in 3D’ option. The insect will then superimpose into your background and buzz around the house. This feature works only on AR Core supported devices running on Android. iPhone users will need to run on iOS 11 software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separately, Google has started showing context links in Google News for specific search results. This feature was spotted by Valentin Pletzer, and it appears to be live only on mobile for now. Few Google News stories have an additional small box at the bottom that show context links about the same topic from the same publication. This ‘For Context’ box shows up only for a few publications and only for a few stories for now. Google may be testing it with a few publications, and stories from CNET and Forbes appear to be showing context links. These links look to offer a bigger picture about the primary story in Google News. There is no clarity on when this feature will roll out broadly for all users, and how exactly it will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are smartphone prices rising in India? We discussed this on Orbital, our weekly technology podcast, which you can subscribe to via Apple Podcasts, Google Podcasts, or RSS, download the episode, or just hit the play button below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Google has reportedly added 23 new insects to its AR search feature, allowing users to virtually see them roaming in their homes. The new insects added to AR search include various kinds of beetles, butterflies, and cicadas. Separately, Google is also testing a new ‘For Context’ feature in Google News. This feature will essentially give you a broader perspective on the primary news search. The contextual link shows up right below the main news, and this context link is usually from the same publication.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/google_context_links_1_1596010022179.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://i.gadgets360cdn.com/large/google_context_links_1_1596010022179.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazfit Bip S Lite launched in India with 30 day battery life and sub Rs 4 000 price tag</title><link href="/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite-launched-in-India-with-30-day-battery-life-and-sub-Rs-4-000-price-tag/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazfit Bip S Lite launched in India with 30 day battery life and sub Rs 4 000 price tag" /><published>2020-07-29T16:40:25+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:40:25+05:30</updated><id>/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite-launched-in-India-with-30-day-battery-life-and-sub-Rs-4-000-price-tag</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite-launched-in-India-with-30-day-battery-life-and-sub-Rs-4-000-price-tag/">&lt;p&gt;Amazfit Bip S Lite will go on sale in India from July 29th via Flipkart and official Amazfit store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highlights Amazfit Bip S Lite is a watered-down version of the Bip S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fitness band is priced under Rs 4,000 in India&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Features include Always-on Transflective display, optical heart rate sensor, more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazfit has launched a new fitness tracker in India, called Amazfit Bip S Lite. The wearable is a lighter version of Amazfit Bip S (review) that made its debut in India back in back June with Rs 4,999 sticker price. The Amazfit Bip S Lite is priced in India much more reasonably and shares a lot of DNA with its elder sibling such as 1.28-inch always-on transflective display, optical heart rate sensor, and 5ATM water-resistant. However, the battery life of the watch has been reduced to 30 days from 40 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Amazfit Bip S Lite price in India is set at Rs 3,799. The wearable will be available via flash sale from tomorrow, i.e. July 29th, via Flipkart and official Amazfit store. The open sale of the Amazfit Bip S Lite is slated to begin from August 5th onwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Amazfit Bip S does not come with built-in GPS and just eight different types of sports mode instead of 10. The wearable’s sports mode include Treadmill, Outdoor running, Walking, Indoor cycling, Outdoor cycling, Yoga, Elliptical trainer, and Freestyle. Amazfit claims that the Bip S Lite also has integrated Huami-PAI for detailed analysis of your heart health and overall fitness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The device tips the scale at just 30 grams (with straps) and features Corning Gorilla 3 tempered glass + anti-fingerprint coating to keep the smudges at bay. The Amazfit Bip S Lite comes with Bluetooth 5.0/ BLE connectivity, music control options, and supports for smartphones running iOS 10/ Android 5.0 or above. The watch features PPG bio-tracking optical heart rate sensor and 3-axis acceleration sensors, and packs 150 watch faces with a couple of custom widgets.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Amazfit Bip S Lite will go on sale in India from July 29th via Flipkart and official Amazfit store.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://static.hub.91mobiles.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://static.hub.91mobiles.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/Amazfit-Bip-S-Lite.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Amazon Alexa App Gets Its Biggest Refresh Ever And The Focus Is On Continuity Personalization</title><link href="/Amazon-Alexa-App-Gets-Its-Biggest-Refresh-Ever-And-The-Focus-Is-On-Continuity-Personalization/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Amazon Alexa App Gets Its Biggest Refresh Ever And The Focus Is On Continuity Personalization" /><published>2020-07-29T16:38:33+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-29T16:38:33+05:30</updated><id>/Amazon-Alexa-App-Gets-Its-Biggest-Refresh-Ever-And-The-Focus-Is-On-Continuity-Personalization</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Amazon-Alexa-App-Gets-Its-Biggest-Refresh-Ever-And-The-Focus-Is-On-Continuity-Personalization/">&lt;p&gt;Amazon is giving the Alexa app for Android and iOS a fresh coat of paint, perhaps the biggest in years. The new app will be available for Android, iOS and Amazon’s own Fire OS. There will be visual improvements across the app, updated navigation methods and a more personalized experience based on how you use Alexa, particularly with relation to Skills. Amazon says the update will roll out on the Google Play Store for Android phones, the Apple App Store for the iPhone and on Amazon’s own Fire OS devices over the next month, and everyone should have it in a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The home screen of the updated Alexa app will now have a large Alexa button at the top, which users can either tap to invoke the virtual assistant or simply say Alexa. Beneath that sit a list of personalized suggestions, which will be based on how you interact with Alexa either on your phone or with any of the Alexa-enabled Echo smart speakers or third-party Alexa smart speakers that you may own. This will include music streaming, including suggestions from third party apps such as Spotify if you have linked any of those accounts, upcoming reminders, music suggestions to pick up from where you left off last and maybe even continue with an audiobook while at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is interesting to note that while Amazon is prioritizing Alexa Skills in the updated Alexa app for Android and iPhone, third-party skills have been pushed back to a separate Skills &amp;amp; Games section. This is possibly to simplify the experience for users and not complicate it with skills that they may or may not use often. There are changes to the Reminders, Settings, Routines and Skills menus as well for further simplification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to use the new Alexa app and see how much Amazon’s efforts have managed to simplify the experience for users. Over time, with so many features regularly added and so many Alexa devices now on sale, the app seemed to have become a bit cluttered and it wasn’t exactly intuitive at times when you wanted to find something in a jiffy. The fact that Amazon is now focusing on letting you pick up from where you last left off adds to a continuity that could let you shift music from an Echo speaker at home to the Echo Buds wireless earbuds as you are about to step out of home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change in how third-party skills are now listed within the app perhaps comes as a result of a recent study that shows most of these remain unused. A research by Voicebot suggests that as many as 61% of Alexa’s third-party skills have no ratings at all, which indicates they aren’t popular. The research also says only 5% of Alexa skills have earned 10 or more ratings and just 1% have more than 100 ratings from users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Amazon Alexa app will show up on your Android phone or Apple iPhone’s application stores anytime in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Amazon is giving the Alexa app for Android and iOS a fresh coat of paint, perhaps the biggest in years. The new app will be available for Android, iOS and Amazon’s own Fire OS. There will be visual improvements across the app, updated navigation methods and a more personalized experience based on how you use Alexa, particularly with relation to Skills. Amazon says the update will roll out on the Google Play Store for Android phones, the Apple App Store for the iPhone and on Amazon’s own Fire OS devices over the next month, and everyone should have it in a few weeks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2020/07/1595908287_amazon-alexa-app.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.news18.com/ibnlive/uploads/2020/07/1595908287_amazon-alexa-app.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>