<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-14T19:35:30+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Hyderabad based Aurobindo Pharma and CSIR CCMB in joint effort to develop Covid vaccine</title><link href="/Hyderabad-based-Aurobindo-Pharma-and-CSIR-CCMB-in-joint-effort-to-develop-Covid-vaccine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hyderabad based Aurobindo Pharma and CSIR CCMB in joint effort to develop Covid vaccine" /><published>2020-09-17T11:42:08+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:42:08+05:30</updated><id>/Hyderabad-based-Aurobindo-Pharma-and-CSIR-CCMB-in-joint-effort-to-develop-Covid-vaccine</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Hyderabad-based-Aurobindo-Pharma-and-CSIR-CCMB-in-joint-effort-to-develop-Covid-vaccine/">&lt;p&gt;Hyderabad-based Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology (CSIR-CCMB) and Aurobindo Pharma Limited have announced a collaboration to develop vaccine for Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;By&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Published: 8:10 pm 12:44 am&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hyderabad: Hyderabad continues to remain the top destination in the country for pharma companies and researchers involved in the development of vaccine for Covid-19 disease. On Tuesday, the Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (CSIR), Hyderabad-based Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology (CSIR-CCMB) and Aurobindo Pharma Limited have announced a collaboration to develop vaccine for Covid-19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the signed agreement, Aurobindo Pharma will partner with CSIR affiliated laboratories including CCMB in Hyderabad, Institute of Medical Technology (IMTECH), Chandigarh and Indian Institute of Chemical Biology (IICB), Kolkata in developing vaccine candidates using different technology platforms. Aurobindo will undertake clinical development and commercialization of the vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Joining of hands of premier CSIR labs with industry for development of vaccines will amplify India’s efforts in indigenous vaccine development and also help in preparedness for, Director General, CSIR, said that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director, CCMB, Dr. Rakesh Mishra welcomed the collaboration with Aurobindo Pharma Limited. “Our labs are working on novel proteins for vaccine development that have the potential to address the need for a second-generation vaccine. Aurobindo Pharma has proven manufacturing and commercialization capabilities,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the development, N. Govindarajan, Managing Director, Aurobindo Pharma Limited, said “We are proud to join hands with CSIR for developing vaccines to combat the Covid-19 pandemic. This collaboration further strengthens our Covid-19 vaccine development efforts. We are already setting up a large-scale facility in Hyderabad for manufacturing Covid-19 vaccine and other viral vaccines”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from this collaboration, Aurobindo is already developing a vaccine for SARS-CoV-2 through its wholly owned US subsidiary Auro Vaccines. The SARS-COV-2 vaccine candidate is based on the company’s proprietary replication-competent, attenuated, recombinant vesicular stomatitis (VSV, VesiculoVax™) vaccine delivery platform, according to a press release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can get handpicked stories from Telangana Today on Telegram everyday. Click the link to subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click to follow Telangana Today Facebook page and Twitter .&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">Hyderabad-based Centre for Cellular and Molecular Biology (CSIR-CCMB) and Aurobindo Pharma Limited have announced a collaboration to develop vaccine for Covid-19.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/vaccine.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/vaccine.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why lockdown can save the RBI from explaining failure to fight inflation to govt</title><link href="/Why-lockdown-can-save-the-RBI-from-explaining-failure-to-fight-inflation-to-govt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why lockdown can save the RBI from explaining failure to fight inflation to govt" /><published>2020-09-17T11:42:05+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:42:05+05:30</updated><id>/Why-lockdown-can-save-the-RBI-from-explaining-failure-to-fight-inflation-to-govt</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Why-lockdown-can-save-the-RBI-from-explaining-failure-to-fight-inflation-to-govt/">&lt;p&gt;Text Size: A- A+&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mumbai: It seems the Covid-19 lockdown may have allowed the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) to wriggle out of an embarrassing situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central bank is currently facing the grim prospect of answering to Parliament for failing to achieve its inflation target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the RBI Act, if average inflation stays out of the 2-6 per cent range for three consecutive quarters, then it is seen as a failure of the central bank. Average inflation was above 6 per cent in the March and June quarters, and also over 6 per cent in July and August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if minutes of the monetary policy committee (MPC) meeting after the August policy review are an indication, the central bank may have found a way of not writing an explanation letter to the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MPC is of the view that there was a break in the consumer price index (CPI) series since inflation data for April and May was imputed and not collected by visiting the markets by NSO surveyors. The surveyors could not make the field visits for data collection due to the nationwide lockdown imposed to curb the spread of novel coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The NSO has adopted best practices in producing these imputations for the purpose of business continuity in the face of challenges to data collection due to the nation-wide lockdown. The NSO has, however, not provided inflation rates for April and May,” the MPC observed in the August meeting minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For the purpose of monetary formulation and conduct, therefore, the MPC is of the view that CPI prints for April and May can be regarded as a break in the CPI series.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, the MPC has come to the conclusion that there is a break in the CPI series since there was no data collection in April and May, and the inflation figures for these two months was the estimation of NSO and not the actual numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also read: RBI expected to make inflation and growth forecast on 1 October — first time this fiscal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Valid point, but explain’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts agree with the MPC that there is a break in the CPI series, but say the central bank should still write the letter to the lawmakers explaining the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The point that has been made by RBI that the series is broken is technically right,” said A. Prasanna, head of Research, ICICI Securities PD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Since prices of many items were not available, the index was imputed in April and May. So that is a valid point. But my own view is, that itself can be mentioned in the letter. They can explain this in the letter and then give their outlook. RBI’s outlook is that inflation will come down in the second half without any policy action,” Prasanna told ThePrint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its submission to the lawmakers for failing to achieve the inflation target, the central bank needs to answer three questions — why it has failed to achieve its target; what remedial measures it would take to bring inflation back within the target range; and by what time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the minutes, RBI indicated remedial action to bring back inflation will be hiking interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…if inflation persists above the upper tolerance band for one more quarter, monetary policy will be constrained by mandate to undertake remedial action, including an immediate and more than proportionate response to head off the build-up of inflation pressures and prevent it from getting generalised. The question is: can the economy withstand it in this virus-ravaged, debilitated state?” RBI Deputy Governor Michael Patra said in the minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if CPI series is seen as broken, then interest rate hikes can be avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also read: RBI’s first Monetary Policy Committee bows out, its record sullied by inflation at the end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Media and markets creating a big issue’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why would there be a need for remedial measures as RBI’s own estimates suggest inflation will come down in the second half of the financial year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We track September inflation at a lower 6.5%, albeit still above the RBI’s 2-6% mandate. That said, we see CPI inflation slipping to 2.5-3% in 2HFY21 on the back of base effects, good rains and low demand with FY21 GDP set to fall 7.5%,” BofA Securities said in a note to its clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It expects the RBI to cut interest rates by 15 basis points in the next policy review meeting scheduled on 1 October and a total 75 bps in the current financial year. In this financial year so far, the RBI has reduced the policy rates by 40 bps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So I don’t agree with the point in RBI minutes that they will have to spell out remedial measures. RBI can say that without any monetary action inflation will subside below 6% by next year. So where is the need to take remedial measures,” Prasanna said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said the media and markets have created a big issue out of writing a letter, which is a very mechanical and a procedural thing, in his view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“…it should not be called a failure if inflation exceeds target due to one off factors. This word failure has created a stigma. For example, the Bank of England also wrote those letters in 2010 when inflation rose above their target. Notably, they were doing quantitative easing at that time. But they wrote a letter explaining why inflation was high and why it will come down without any need for policy action,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also read: GST compensation cess less than one-fifth of total shortfall, Maharashtra among worst hit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subscribe to our channels on YouTube &amp;amp; Telegram&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why news media is in crisis &amp;amp; How you can fix it You are reading this because you value good, intelligent and objective journalism. We thank you for your time and your trust. You also know that the news media is facing an unprecedented crisis. It is likely that you are also hearing of the brutal layoffs and pay-cuts hitting the industry. There are many reasons why the media’s economics is broken. But a big one is that good people are not yet paying enough for good journalism. We have a newsroom filled with talented young reporters. We also have the country’s most robust editing and fact-checking team, finest news photographers and video professionals. We are building India’s most ambitious and energetic news platform. And have just turned three. At ThePrint, we invest in quality journalists. We pay them fairly. As you may have noticed, we do not flinch from spending whatever it takes to make sure our reporters reach where the story is. This comes with a sizable cost. For us to continue bringing quality journalism, we need readers like you to pay for it. If you think we deserve your support, do join us in this endeavour to strengthen fair, free, courageous and questioning journalism. Please click on the link below. Your support will define ThePrint’s future. Support Our Journalism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Show Full Article&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">Text Size: A- A+</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/1x-1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/1x-1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why India doesn t print a ton of money to fight poverty</title><link href="/Why-India-doesn-t-print-a-ton-of-money-to-fight-poverty/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why India doesn t print a ton of money to fight poverty" /><published>2020-09-17T11:41:58+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:41:58+05:30</updated><id>/Why-India-doesn-t-print-a-ton-of-money-to-fight-poverty</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Why-India-doesn-t-print-a-ton-of-money-to-fight-poverty/">&lt;p&gt;The coronavirus pandemic has pushed the world into a recession. Major global economies are responding to the COVID-19 induced recession by adopting unorthodox measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United States, the European Central Bank, Japan, and even emerging economies such as Turkey and Indonesia are printing money to bring economies back to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, India has refrained from doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the Q1 financial year 2020-21 GDP deceleration of 23.9%, the highest among major economies of the world, the chorus is growing in India for monetisation of the fiscal deficit: in layman’s language, printing more money to boost the ailing economy. Especially, because the repercussions of not spending to support the economy could be irreparable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before that, let’s understand a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is fiscal deficit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fiscal deficit is the difference between the total revenue or income of the government less its expenditure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For FY 2019-20, the central government’s receipts through income taxes, GST and other receipts were Rs 19.32 lakh crore, while its expenditure on schemes, subsidies, and infrastructure, interest payments were Rs 26.98 lakh crore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence, the fiscal deficit was Rs 7.66 lakh crore. It is expressed as a percentage of the GDP. The figure was 3.8% in FY 2019-20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the case of an individual, if she spends more than she earns, how would she make up for the difference? Well, she would need to borrow, from friends or banks or moneylenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the government also borrows money from the market to finance the fiscal deficit. It usually issues bonds which are subscribed by individuals and institutional investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They lend money to the government with the promise of future payment. These bonds carry a lower rate of interest than what is available to corporates/individuals, as they are considered as risk free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central government has hiked the market borrowing for this year to Rs 12 lakh crore from Rs 7.8 lakh crore presented in the Union Budget in the wake of the coronavirus pandemic, implying fiscal deficit will shoot its target.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do governments spend more than they earn?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Politicians and policymakers rely on fiscal deficits to expand popular policies/schemes, such as welfare programmes and public works, without having to raise taxes or cut spending elsewhere in the Budget, to elicit support during elections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is monetisation of fiscal deficit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monetisation of fiscal deficit refers to the purchase of government bonds by the central bank, i.e. the Reserve Bank of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the central bank creates fresh money by simply printing to buy these bonds, in layman’s language, monetisation of deficit means printing more money. This helps finance the spending needs of the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government spends this money on infrastructure projects which creates jobs, having a multiplier effect on the economy. This money could be used by the government to provide more funds for its welfare schemes, NREGA, transfers to Jan Dhan accounts, etcetera which then provide a fillip to consumption, which has been badly hit by the pandemic. Consumption, both private and government, accounts for about 70% of India’s GDP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s great. Why doesn’t India just print tonnes of money and distribute to the populace to ensure nobody is poor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past when countries have tried to get richer by printing money it hasn’t worked. Printing more money increases money supply in the economy. Now everyone has more money, more money is chasing goods and services. This leads to an increase in prices as sellers take advantage of the situation and charge more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has happened earlier in Zimbabwe and Venezuela. The countries suffered from hyperinflation, in simple terms very high inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Zimbabwe prices rose as much as 231,000,000% in a single year in 2008. The paper used probably became worth more than the banknote denomination printed on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should the RBI then print money to revive the economy, especially when the stimulus package announced by the government is deemed insufficient?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Economists are divided on the issue: while some have cautioned against the move, others say limited monetisation can be undertaken given the extraordinary situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The money received by the government from the RBI can be used to fund higher spending and protect the economy, the poor and vulnerable in these abnormal times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Story continues&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">The coronavirus pandemic has pushed the world into a recession. Major global economies are responding to the COVID-19 induced recession by adopting unorthodox measures.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/6fa36bc0-f804-11ea-ab1f-9bbc2940e0e3" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/6fa36bc0-f804-11ea-ab1f-9bbc2940e0e3" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Oil Tanker Industry Is In An Ocean Of Trouble</title><link href="/Oil-Tanker-Industry-Is-In-An-Ocean-Of-Trouble/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oil Tanker Industry Is In An Ocean Of Trouble" /><published>2020-09-17T11:41:52+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:41:52+05:30</updated><id>/Oil-Tanker-Industry-Is-In-An-Ocean-Of-Trouble</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Oil-Tanker-Industry-Is-In-An-Ocean-Of-Trouble/">&lt;p&gt;There has been more than enough written about the woes of various segments of the oil industry and related industries so far this year. But there is one industry that actually thrived during the worst of the crisis: as the world drowned in oil amid slumping demand and excess supply, tanker owners enjoyed a bounce in freight rates as these vessels remained the only storage space for unsellable crude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things have changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OPEC+ oil production cuts helped bring down global inventories, including the massive amounts of oil in floating storage. This brought down freight rates from over $250,000 per day for a Very Large Crude Carrier to less than $30,000 per day, leaving tanker owners wondering how much longer they could survive. Right now, they have one hope, just like air travel: a successful vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oil demand is out the window thanks to the pandemic and there is no telling when—and even if—it will ever be coming back. Yet it is pretty easy to link a rebound in economic activity across the world with a rebound in oil demand. This rebound, however, is contingent on mass vaccinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The list of industries that have been hit hard by Covid-19 is long, with shipping being just one of the many casualties,” shipbroker Gibson said, as quoted by Hellenic Shipping News, earlier this week. “Although in spring tanker rates surged to unprecedented highs amid discharging delays and floating storage demand, today’s market is very different, with TCE earnings on many trades stuck at or below OPEX for a few months now.” Related: OPEC+ Complied 101% With Oil Production Cuts In August&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, demand for tankers for storing oil offshore is on the rise. In fact, Lloyd’s says demand for tankers for floating storage could be the single driver of demand for this industry in the next quarter. Unfortunately, this does not mean that freight rates would recover to the highs of the first half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday, spot rates for Very Large Crude Carriers stood at $27,900 per day, American Shipper senior editor Greg Miller wrote. That’s a lot lower than the $68,000 in average freight rates for the first half of the year and yet it is a massive, 124-percent, improvement on Monday last week. Demand for floating storage is helping tanker owners reach breakeven. But it may take a while to get any better than this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traders and producers stored as much as 1.3 billion barrels of crude during the first five months of this year, both offshore and onshore, Energy Intelligence’s John van Schaik reported earlier this month. Those were good times for tankers. But then OPEC+ started cutting production and floating—and onshore—storage began draining, at a rate of 100 million barrels monthly. Recovery in oil demand following easing of lockdowns helped, however weak it was. But it hasn’t been enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even OPEC+’s easing of their production cuts did not help. Bloomberg wrote in July, the month before cuts were reduced by 2 million barrels daily, that the addition of 2 million bpd to world markets would have been good news any other year if it wasn’t preceded by production cuts of 9.7 million bpd for three months before that. Demand for vessels for floating storage was also on the decline at the time, removing this source demand for tankers as well. And to add insult to injury, Russia and Saudi Arabia, the biggest producers in OPEC+, were keeping more of the additional oil they were producing for the domestic market, probably not least because of still unfavourable prices. Related: Oil Rises After EIA Confirms Crude Inventory Draw&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if this was not enough bad news, there is more. Although growing demand for VLCCs for floating storage is on the rise, much of the oil that traders and producers stored in the spring is still there, FreightWaves’ Miller noted. Off the coast of China, according to Kpler data, there are some 67 million barrels in storage alone. This means that the new demand for offshore storage will by necessity be limited, setting a ceiling on freight rates, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brent crude is trading at just a little over $40 a barrel after last week it fell below this threshold on renewed concern about future demand. WTI is trading below $39 a barrel. There are more than 170 vaccine candidates in different stages of development around the world. Nine are in an advanced stage of testing. There are hopes we could have a working vaccine before the year’s end, although medical experts have been warning against too much optimism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vaccines are the only thing that could save the tanker industry right now. If there is an effective vaccine and mass vaccinations, air travel will start to recover. If air travel starts to recover, so will overall oil demand. Yet it is worth noting that this will not happen overnight, even in the best-case scenario where a vaccine becomes widely available before the end of this year. Tanker owners are due more trouble before the situation returns to anything resembling the normal boom-and-bust cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Irina Slav for Oilprice.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Top Reads From Oilprice.com:&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">There has been more than enough written about the woes of various segments of the oil industry and related industries so far this year. But there is one industry that actually thrived during the worst of the crisis: as the world drowned in oil amid slumping demand and excess supply, tanker owners enjoyed a bounce in freight rates as these vessels remained the only storage space for unsellable crude.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/2020-09-16_2zivybl3rh.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/2020-09-16_2zivybl3rh.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Novavax aims for 2 billion Covid 19 vaccine doses with expanded India deal</title><link href="/Novavax-aims-for-2-billion-Covid-19-vaccine-doses-with-expanded-India-deal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Novavax aims for 2 billion Covid 19 vaccine doses with expanded India deal" /><published>2020-09-17T11:41:10+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:41:10+05:30</updated><id>/Novavax-aims-for-2-billion-Covid-19-vaccine-doses-with-expanded-India-deal</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Novavax-aims-for-2-billion-Covid-19-vaccine-doses-with-expanded-India-deal/">&lt;p&gt;More on Covid-19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;US drug developer Novavax Inc said on Tuesday it was doubling its potential Covid-19 vaccine manufacturing capacity to two billion doses annually under an agreement with Serum Institute of India, sending its shares up about 7%.In August, Novavax signed a deal with Serum Institute, the world’s largest producer of vaccines, to produce a minimum of one billion doses of its vaccine candidate, when approved, for low- and middle-income countries and India.As part of the expanded agreement, Serum Institute will also manufacture the antigen component of the vaccine, dubbed NVX-CoV2373, which Novavax said will bring its manufacturing capacity to over two billion doses by mid-2021.Novavax’s vaccine is currently in mid-stage trials after an early-stage study showed it produced high levels of antibodies against the novel coronavirus . The company plans to begin late-stage trials in the third quarter.Last month, Novavax said it will supply 60 million doses of its coronavirus vaccine candidate to the UK beginning as early as the first quarter of 2021.The company is also preparing to deliver 100 million doses to the United States by January after it was awarded $1.6 billion for its potential vaccine, and has also signed supply agreements with Canada and Japan.Other drugmakers such as Pfizer Inc and Moderna Inc have already begun large late-stage studies of their experimental vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">More on Covid-19</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/photo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/photo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dr Reddy s To Supply 100 Million Doses Of Russia Corona Vaccine</title><link href="/Dr-Reddy-s-To-Supply-100-Million-Doses-Of-Russia-Corona-Vaccine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dr Reddy s To Supply 100 Million Doses Of Russia Corona Vaccine" /><published>2020-09-17T11:41:04+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:41:04+05:30</updated><id>/Dr-Reddy-s-To-Supply-100-Million-Doses-Of-Russia-Corona-Vaccine</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Dr-Reddy-s-To-Supply-100-Million-Doses-Of-Russia-Corona-Vaccine/">&lt;p&gt;Dr Reddy’s Laboratories and Russian Direct Investment Fund (RDIF) have agreed to cooperate on clinical trials and distribution of Sputnik V vaccine in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon regulatory approval in India, Russia’s sovereign wealth fund will supply 100 million doses of the vaccine to Dr Reddy’s. The Sputnik V vaccine, which is based on well-studied human adenoviral vector platform with proven safety, is undergoing clinical trials for the coronavirus pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deliveries could potentially begin in late 2020 subject to completion of successful trials and registration of the vaccine by regulatory authorities in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The agreement between RDIF and Dr Reddy’s reflects growing awareness of countries and organisations to have a diversified anti-Covid vaccine portfolio to protect their populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“India is among the most severely impacted countries from Covid-19 and we believe our human adenovirus dual vector platform will provide a safe and scientifically validated option to India in the battle against it,” said Kirill Dmitriev, Chief Executive Officer of RDIF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;G V Prasad, Co-Chairman and Managing Director of Dr Reddy’s said Sputnik V vaccine could provide a credible option in our fight against Covid-19 in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The phase one and two clinical trials have shown promising results. We will be conducting phase three trials in India to ensure safety and efficacy for the Indian population,” he said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: (ANI)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the Streaming/OTT Updates you ever want. In One Place!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="BUSINESS" /><summary type="html">Dr Reddy’s Laboratories and Russian Direct Investment Fund (RDIF) have agreed to cooperate on clinical trials and distribution of Sputnik V vaccine in India.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/AP-Coronavirus-cases-660x330.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/AP-Coronavirus-cases-660x330.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">6 foods that add to your stress levels and its healthy swaps</title><link href="/6-foods-that-add-to-your-stress-levels-and-its-healthy-swaps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 foods that add to your stress levels and its healthy swaps" /><published>2020-09-17T11:40:37+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:40:37+05:30</updated><id>/6-foods-that-add-to-your-stress-levels-and-its-healthy-swaps</id><content type="html" xml:base="/6-foods-that-add-to-your-stress-levels-and-its-healthy-swaps/">&lt;p&gt;Many people get into the habit of daily drinking only because they feel it helps them relieve stress. Though yes, alcohol may temporarily relieve some stress, it should not become a habit. Alcohol is actually a depressant that can increase anxiety. Choose herbal tea over alcohol. It has been observed that tea drinkers have a lower level of cortisol, the stress hormone. Herbal teas are caffeine-free. Caffeine can trigger anxiety and interfere with sleep. So, a cup of herbal tea might not look as great as a glass of wine but it surely will make you feel better if you are stressed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Many people get into the habit of daily drinking only because they feel it helps them relieve stress. Though yes, alcohol may temporarily relieve some stress, it should not become a habit. Alcohol is actually a depressant that can increase anxiety. Choose herbal tea over alcohol. It has been observed that tea drinkers have a lower level of cortisol, the stress hormone. Herbal teas are caffeine-free. Caffeine can trigger anxiety and interfere with sleep. So, a cup of herbal tea might not look as great as a glass of wine but it surely will make you feel better if you are stressed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/78127080.cms" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/78127080.cms" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Do You Feel Lonely This Sad Feeling Can Make You a Diabetic</title><link href="/Do-You-Feel-Lonely-This-Sad-Feeling-Can-Make-You-a-Diabetic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do You Feel Lonely This Sad Feeling Can Make You a Diabetic" /><published>2020-09-17T11:38:50+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:38:50+05:30</updated><id>/Do-You-Feel-Lonely-This-Sad-Feeling-Can-Make-You-a-Diabetic</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Do-You-Feel-Lonely-This-Sad-Feeling-Can-Make-You-a-Diabetic/">&lt;p&gt;Amid the Covid-19 pandemic, the researchers have shown that the absence of quality connections with people and not the lack of contact predicts the onset of type 2 diabetes. Also Read - Wait, What? Handgrip Can Detect People at High Diabetes Risk?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study, published in the journal Diabetologia, indicates that prolonged loneliness may influence the development of diabetes, suggesting the experience of lockdown could potentially compound people’s vulnerability in this pandemic if the loneliness continues for some time. Also Read - Are You Suffering From Diabetes? Here’s How You Can Cut Your Risk of Developing Heart Attack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The study shows a strong relationship between loneliness and the later onset of type 2 diabetes,” said study lead author Ruth Hackett from the King’s College London in the UK. Also Read - Antibiotics May up Heart Disease Risk in People With Diabetes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research team analysed data from the English Longitudinal Study Ageing on 4,112 adults aged 50 years and over which was collected at several times from 2002 to 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of data collection all participants were free of diabetes and had normal levels of blood glucose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study showed that over a period of 12 years 264 people developed type 2 diabetes. and the level of loneliness measured at the start of data collection was a significant predictor of the onset of type 2 diabetes later on in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This relationship remained intact when accounting for smoking, alcohol, weight, level of blood glucose, high blood pressure and cardiovascular disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The association was also independent of depression, living alone and social isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study also demonstrated a clear distinction between loneliness and social isolation in that isolation or living alone does not predict type 2 diabetes whereas loneliness, which is defined by a person’s quality of relationships, does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the team, a possible biological reason behind the association between loneliness and type 2 diabetes could be the impact of constant loneliness on the biological system responsible for stress, which, over time affects the body and increases the risk for diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If the feeling of loneliness becomes chronic, then everyday you’re stimulating the stress system and over time that leads to wear and tear on your body and those negative changes in stress-related biology may be linked to type 2 diabetes development,” Hackett explained.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Amid the Covid-19 pandemic, the researchers have shown that the absence of quality connections with people and not the lack of contact predicts the onset of type 2 diabetes. Also Read - Wait, What? Handgrip Can Detect People at High Diabetes Risk?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/pjimage-8-3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/pjimage-8-3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple releases Spatial Audio support for AirPods Pro</title><link href="/Apple-releases-Spatial-Audio-support-for-AirPods-Pro/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple releases Spatial Audio support for AirPods Pro" /><published>2020-09-17T11:38:06+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:38:06+05:30</updated><id>/Apple-releases-Spatial-Audio-support-for-AirPods-Pro</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Apple-releases-Spatial-Audio-support-for-AirPods-Pro/">&lt;p&gt;The Spatial audio feature for the AirPods Pro was announced at this year’s WWDC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple is rolling out a firmware update for the AirPods Pro. The new firmware is called 3A283. When you pair your AirPods running the iPhone with iOS 14, users can enjoy “spatial audio”, a feature that simulates surround sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you are not aware, Spatial audio is a feature what Apple calls a “theatre-like experience” for audio when you are watching a movie or playing video games. The feature essentially uses the sensors in your iPhone and AirPods Pro to provide an immersive sound. When you move your head in one direction or another, the audio changes to reflect that movement. Spatial audio is essentially a way of creating sound in 360 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatial audio for AirPods Pro supports audio encoded in 5.1 7.1 surround sound, as well as Dolby Atmos. Right now, AirPods Pro are the only headphones that support Apple’s new spatial audio features. The regular AirPods won’t get Apple’s new spatial audio feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the automatic device switching feature is also coming to the AirPods Pro. The feature automatically switches audio inputs based on which Apple device you’re using through your iCloud account. The new automatic switching feature is coming to the AirPods Pro, second-generation AirPods, Powerbeats, Powerbeats Pro, and Beats Solo Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check the software version of your AirPods and AirPods Pro, simply connect them to an iOS 14-powered iPhone or iPad and then go to the Settings app. Go to General &amp;gt; About &amp;gt; AirPods, and look at the firmware version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AirPods Pro, which currently retails for Rs 22,000 in India, offer comfortable design, ultra-long battery life, and impressive noise-cancellation feature. The AirPods Pro’s battery life can last up to five hours of listening time when noise cancellation or Transparency mode is off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 The Indian Express is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@indianexpress) and stay updated with the latest headlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© IE Online Media Services Pvt Ltd&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">The Spatial audio feature for the AirPods Pro was announced at this year’s WWDC</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/AirPods-Pro.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/AirPods-Pro.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">HP Omen Frequency Wireless Headset With 7 1 Surround Sound Up to 30 Hour Battery Announced</title><link href="/HP-Omen-Frequency-Wireless-Headset-With-7-1-Surround-Sound-Up-to-30-Hour-Battery-Announced/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HP Omen Frequency Wireless Headset With 7 1 Surround Sound Up to 30 Hour Battery Announced" /><published>2020-09-17T11:38:04+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-17T11:38:04+05:30</updated><id>/HP-Omen-Frequency-Wireless-Headset-With-7-1-Surround-Sound-Up-to-30-Hour-Battery-Announced</id><content type="html" xml:base="/HP-Omen-Frequency-Wireless-Headset-With-7-1-Surround-Sound-Up-to-30-Hour-Battery-Announced/">&lt;p&gt;HP Omen Frequency wireless headset, along with Omen Vector wireless mouse and Omen Spacer wireless TKL keyboard, has been announced. The company has introduced Warp Wireless Technology with Omen Command Center integration in its new Omen gaming accessories that are claimed to offer lag-free gaming experience. HP says that these wireless accessories will be showcased during the Omen Underground event that is scheduled at 1pm PDT on Tuesday (1.30am IST on Wednesday) via the official PAX Arena Twitch channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HP Omen Frequency wireless headset price, features&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HP Omen Frequency wireless headset features the company’s Warp Wireless Technology that is claimed to provide lag-free, low-latency audio. HP says that the headset delivers a 7.1 surround sound and C-Media Xear technology produces 360-degree sound. The headset comes with customisable EQ and lighting that can be adjusted from the Omen Command Center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HP says that the Omen Frequency wireless headset delivers up to 30 hours of battery life, and comes with USB Type-C charging. It has an environmental noise cancelling microphone that comes with flip-to-mute feature. The headset features removable earpads, suspension headband, rotating earcups, and a rotating volume control situated on the earcup. HP says that the headset can be used with Mac, iOS, PC, PS4, PS4 Pro, Xbox One, Xbox One X, and Nintendo Switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Omen Frequency wireless headset is expected to be available this December at a starting price of $169.99 (roughly Rs. 12,500).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HP Omen Vector wireless mouse price, features&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Omne Vector wireless mouse is claimed to be the world’s fastest USB Type-C charging gaming mouse. It is claimed to deliver up to 10 hours of battery life in five minutes of charging. It is said to fully charge in 90 minutes and is claimed to deliver up to 180 hours of battery life. The mouse is claimed to have a 16000 DPI Pixart PAW3335 wireless sensor, and Omron mechanical switches with a 50 million click lifespan. It comes with a rugged rubber grip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Omen Vector Wireless Mouse is available via HP.com at a starting price of $99.99 (roughly Rs 7,300) in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Omen Spacer Wireless TKL Keyboard price, features&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Omen Spacer Wireless TKL keyboard is claimed to deliver up to 75 hours of play on a single charge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo Credit: HP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Omen Spacer Wireless TKL keyboard can be used in wireless or wired modes. It is claimed to deliver up to 75 hours of play on a single charge, and said to provide six hours of battery life (without backlight) in five minutes of charging. It comes with MX Cherry Brown switches, 100 percent anti-ghost and N key roll-over, and magnetic detachable palm rest. It is said to come with AES Standard 128-bit encryption to prevent cyber-thieves from intercepting keystrokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Omen Spacer Wireless TLK keyboard is available for pre-order via HP.com at a starting price of $159.99 (roughly Rs. 11,700) in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How are we staying sane during this Coronavirus lockdown? We discussed this on Orbital, our weekly technology podcast, which you can subscribe to via Apple Podcasts or RSS, download the episode, or just hit the play button below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">HP Omen Frequency wireless headset, along with Omen Vector wireless mouse and Omen Spacer wireless TKL keyboard, has been announced. The company has introduced Warp Wireless Technology with Omen Command Center integration in its new Omen gaming accessories that are claimed to offer lag-free gaming experience. HP says that these wireless accessories will be showcased during the Omen Underground event that is scheduled at 1pm PDT on Tuesday (1.30am IST on Wednesday) via the official PAX Arena Twitch channel.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/HP_Omen_frequency_headset_1600177675405.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/17-09-2020/HP_Omen_frequency_headset_1600177675405.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>