<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-08T15:13:01+05:30</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">GeekyPanda</title><subtitle>Learning never stops</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Common cold can help combat flu research suggests</title><link href="/Common-cold-can-help-combat-flu-research-suggests/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Common cold can help combat flu research suggests" /><published>2020-09-08T11:07:27+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T11:07:27+05:30</updated><id>/Common-cold-can-help-combat-flu-research-suggests</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Common-cold-can-help-combat-flu-research-suggests/">&lt;p&gt;It was found in the research that during months when both the viruses were typically active, if the common cold virus was present in the body, the flu virus was not. (Source: Getty/Thinkstock)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new research has highlighted that the common cold virus may be able to block the flu virus from infecting airways. Researchers suggest the presence of rhinovirus — the most common viral infectious agent in humans and the predominant cause of common cold — may be enough to kickstart the body’s antiviral defences, thereby providing protection against the flu, The Independent reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the outlet, a Yale University team led by Dr Ellen Foxman studied three years of clinical data of more than 13,000 patients at the Yale New Haven Hospital. These patients had symptoms of respiratory infection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ALSO READ&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Quarantine fatigue: Everything you need to know about it&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was found in the research that during months when both the viruses were typically active, if the common cold virus was present in the body, the flu virus was not. “When we looked at the data, it became clear that very few people had both viruses at the same time,” Dr Foxman, an assistant professor of laboratory medicine and immunobiology, and senior author of the study was quoted as saying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, she also added that it is still to be known if the annual seasonal spread of the common cold virus will have a similar impact on those exposed to the coronavirus. “It is impossible to predict how two viruses will interact without doing the research.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ALSO READ&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Early rising for a healthy, wealthy life: Myth or reality?&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this particular study, researchers created a ‘human airway tissue’ from the stem cells that give rise to the epithelial cells, which line the airways of the lung and are always targeted by respiratory viruses, the outlet reports. It was then found that after the tissue had been exposed to the rhinovirus, the influenza virus was not able to infect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study was published in The Lancet Microbe journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;For more lifestyle news, follow us: Twitter: lifestyle_ie&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Facebook: IE Lifestyle&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Instagram: ie_lifestyle&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 The Indian Express is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@indianexpress) and stay updated with the latest headlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the latest Lifestyle News, download Indian Express App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;© IE Online Media Services Pvt Ltd&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">It was found in the research that during months when both the viruses were typically active, if the common cold virus was present in the body, the flu virus was not. (Source: Getty/Thinkstock)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/GettyImages-virus_1200.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/GettyImages-virus_1200.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Arthritis drug may improve early stages of heart disease</title><link href="/Arthritis-drug-may-improve-early-stages-of-heart-disease/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arthritis drug may improve early stages of heart disease" /><published>2020-09-08T11:07:16+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T11:07:16+05:30</updated><id>/Arthritis-drug-may-improve-early-stages-of-heart-disease</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Arthritis-drug-may-improve-early-stages-of-heart-disease/">&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Arthritis drug may improve early stages of heart disease&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Photo Credit: iStock Images&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London: Drugs used to treat initial signs of rheumatoid arthritis (RA) can also improve the early stages of heart disease, according to a new study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having rheumatoid arthritis (RA) is known to at least double the chances of developing cardiovascular disease (CVD) because of links to atherosclerosis (a build-up of plaque inside the arteries), heart failure and strokes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study, published in the journal Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases, linked treatment of RA with improvements in vascular stiffness - an indicator of CVD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our research shows that even at the earliest stages of rheumatoid arthritis, there is increased vascular stiffness in people with no or minimal traditional CVD risk factors such as hypertension, high cholesterol or smoking,” said study author Sven Plein from the University of Leeds in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the study, the research team had set out to explore possible connections between the very earliest signs of RA and indicators of CVD. Detailed MRI heart scans were given to 82 patients with no known heart issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scans revealed the presence of increased vascular stiffness in the aorta, which is a gradual loss of elasticity in the large arteries, compared to healthy people.There was also evidence of cardiac scarring and changes in the wall of the left ventricle (the heart’s main pumping chamber), suggesting heart abnormalities had started before the RA diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After their initial scans, the 82 patients were given one of two RA drug courses. After a year of treatment, further scans were then carried out on 71 of the patients.The scans revealed that the vascular stiffness of the aorta (the main artery) had improved during the RA therapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The rheumatoid arthritis treatment improved vascular stiffness, regardless of how the patient responded to the RA medication and these improvements in vascular stiffness independently of response to RA treatment were unexpected,” Plein said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research highlights the importance of commencing treatment of RA early to also lessen the risk of developing CVD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Identifying patients at the earliest stage of RA with most risk of CVD is important to inform management strategy,” said study researcher Maya Buch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The benefits of RA treatment on CVD extend beyond traditional suppression of inflammation,” Buch noted.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Arthritis drug may improve early stages of heart disease Photo Credit: iStock Images</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/iStock-868985874_3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/iStock-868985874_3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The brain can induce diabetes remission in rodents but how</title><link href="/The-brain-can-induce-diabetes-remission-in-rodents-but-how/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The brain can induce diabetes remission in rodents but how" /><published>2020-09-08T11:06:15+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T11:06:15+05:30</updated><id>/The-brain-can-induce-diabetes-remission-in-rodents-but-how-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/The-brain-can-induce-diabetes-remission-in-rodents-but-how/">&lt;p&gt;Glucoregulatory neurons within the hypothalamic arcuate nucleus-median eminence of the brain are enmeshed by extracellular matrices known as perineuronal nets that can profoundly impact neuronal function. Latest findings implicate these structures in both brain control of glucose homeostasis and as potential targets for diabetes treatment. Credit: KImberly Alonge/Schwartz Lab/UW Medicine Diabetes Research Institute&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In rodents with type 2 diabetes, a single surgical injection of a protein called fibroblast growth factor 1 can restore blood sugar levels to normal for weeks or months. Yet how this growth factor acts in the brain to generate this lasting benefit has been poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clarifying how this occurs might lead to more effective diabetes treatments that tap into the brain’s inherent potential to ameliorate the condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Until recently, the brain’s ability to normalize elevated blood sugar levels in diabetic animals was unrecognized,” said Dr. Michael Schwartz, professor of medicine at the University of Washington School of Medicine and co-director of the UW Medicine Diabetes Institute. “By interrogating cellular and molecular responses induced in the hypothalamus by a brain peptide called fibroblast growth factor 1, our international teams’ latest findings chart a path towards a more complete understanding how this effect is achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These insights,” he said, “may one day inform therapeutic strategies for inducing sustained diabetes remission, rather than simply lowering blood sugar levels on a day-to-day basis as current treatments do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type 2 diabetes affects 10% of the U.S. population. It is closely tied to obesity and causes serious health problems including heart disease, vision loss, kidney failure, dementia, difficult-to-cure infections, and nerve damage. It also increases the risk of needing amputations. Control of blood sugar levels can prevent these problems, but is often hard to achieve and becomes an ongoing struggle for many patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In two companion papers in the Sept. 7 editions of Nature Communications and Nature Metabolism, international teams of researchers describe the intricate biology of the brain’s response to fibroblast growth factor 1. The first team describes robust cellular responses that appear to safeguard brain-signaling pathways critical to keeping blood sugar in check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second team, containing some of the same researchers, made discoveries about extracellular matrix assemblies called “perineuronal nets” that enmesh groups of neurons involved in blood sugar control. The investigators learned that fibroblast growth factor 1 repairs perineuronal nets that have been damaged by diabetes. This response is required for diabetes remission to be sustained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Tunes Pers, of the Novo Nordisk Foundation Center for Basic Metabolic Research, University of Copenhagen in Denmark, and diabetes and obesity researcher Dr. Michael Schwartz at UW Medicine in Seattle were senior authors of the Nature Communications report. The lead authors from their labs were Dr. Marie Bentsen and Dr. Dylan Rausch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The international team of scientists that they assembled began by detailing changes of gene expression induced by fibroblast growth factor 1 treatment across diverse brain cell types located in the hypothalamus. This small region of the brain regulates many body functions, including levels of blood sugar, hunger, food intake, and energy use and storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scientists found that glial cells, which not only provide structural support but also help to organize and regulate neurocircuit activity, responded more intensely than did neurons, brain cells known for electrical transmission of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers also observed enhanced interactions between astrocytes and a subset of neurons that make agouti-related protein (called Agrp neurons). Astrocytes are abundant, star-shaped glial cells that nourish neurons and support their electrical transmissions. Agrp neurons are essential components of the melanocortin signaling system, a brain circuit crucial to control of feeding, body weight and blood sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excessive activation of Agrp neurons is known to dampen melanocortin signaling. This effect has been linked to diabetes development in people and rodents. The researchers noted that prohibiting melancortin signaling after fibroblast growth factor 1 injection into the brain prevents sustained diabetes remission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among other cell types that responded robustly to fibroblast growth factor 1 are tanycytes, elongated, nutrient-sensing glial cells found only in the hypothalamus. Their contributions to normalizing of glucose levels require additional study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper published in Nature Metabolism looked at structures that the scientists called “the previously unrecognized participants” in the mechanism behind fibroblast growth factor 1’s ability to induce diabetes remission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the perineuronal nets that enmesh blood sugar-regulating neurons in the hypothalamus, including Agrp neurons. The lead author of this paper is Kim Alonge, acting instructor in medicine at the UW School of Medicine. The senior author is Michael Schwartz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perineuronal nets promote neurocircuit stability by enmeshing neurons and girding the connections between them. The researchers wanted to know if obesity-related diabetes is associated with structural changes in these perineuronal nets, and whether those could be treated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research team noted that in the Zucker Diabetes Fatty rat model of type 2 diabetes, these nets are scarce in the hypothalamus compared to rats with normal blood sugar levels, Yet in other parts of the brain the nets are normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This loss of perineuronal nets was rapidly reversed following a single injection of fibroblast growth factor 1 into the brain. The ability of fibroblast growth factor 1 to ameliorate diabetes was hampered by removing the nets through enzymatic digestion. In contrast, intact perineuronal nets are not required for fibroblast growth factor 1 to affect food intake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These finding identify perineuronal nets as key targets for sustained diabetes remission induced by the action of fibroblast growth factor 1. The researchers speculate that perhaps these nets help to constrain the activity of Agrp neurons and thereby pump up melanocortin signaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers plan to continue to try to bridge the gap between the cellular (and extracellular) responses to fibroblast growth factor 1 and the normalization of blood sugar levels. This, they hope, may ultimately uncover novel strategies for achieving sustained diabetes remission in patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explore further Changes in brain cartilage may explain why sleep helps you learn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information: Hypothalamic perineuronal net assembly is required for sustained diabetes remission induced by fibroblast growth factor 1 in rats, Nature Metabolism (2020). www.nature.com/articles/s42255-020-00275-6 Journal information: Nature Communications , Nature Metabolism Hypothalamic perineuronal net assembly is required for sustained diabetes remission induced by fibroblast growth factor 1 in rats,(2020). DOI: 10.1038/s42255-020-00275-6&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">Glucoregulatory neurons within the hypothalamic arcuate nucleus-median eminence of the brain are enmeshed by extracellular matrices known as perineuronal nets that can profoundly impact neuronal function. Latest findings implicate these structures in both brain control of glucose homeostasis and as potential targets for diabetes treatment. Credit: KImberly Alonge/Schwartz Lab/UW Medicine Diabetes Research Institute</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/thebraincani.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/thebraincani.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Who Should Get a Covid19 Vaccine First Experts Disagree</title><link href="/Who-Should-Get-a-Covid19-Vaccine-First-Experts-Disagree/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Who Should Get a Covid19 Vaccine First Experts Disagree" /><published>2020-09-08T11:05:54+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T11:05:54+05:30</updated><id>/Who-Should-Get-a-Covid19-Vaccine-First-Experts-Disagree-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Who-Should-Get-a-Covid19-Vaccine-First-Experts-Disagree/">&lt;p&gt;The world is currently racing to develop a safe, effective, and accessible Covid19 vaccine. While these efforts tout new achievements every day and take us closer to a way out of this pandemic, medical experts and ethicists have also been trying to figure out one important, soon-to-be-pressing question: when we finally do get a Covid19 vaccine, its doses will be limited; so, who will get it first?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who are at high risk of contracting Covid19 and who are at risk for having severe symptoms should be prioritized, according to a proposal published last week by the U.S. National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine. It drew its recommendations from past vaccination attempts during the H1N1 and Ebola outbreaks and outlined four criteria for determining who will get the Covid19 vaccine first — people who are at high risk of acquiring infection, who have a high morbidity and mortality risk, those on whom others depend on for essential work, and who are at most risk of transmitting Covid19 to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping these criteria in mind, the expert task force laid out four phases of vaccine distribution. The first phase would prioritize frontline workers (such as doctors and nurses) and older adults living together in institutions such as nursing homes, both to protect the group that is most vulnerable to Covid19, and the group that takes care of them. Phase 2 would bring in people who have underlying conditions that make them more susceptible to a severe Covid19 infection, and essential workers in society — food delivery workers, school teachers for example — on whom society depends on to normally function. Phase 3 would focus on young adults who are not severely affected by Covid19 but serve as asymptomatic vectors of transmission, and Phase 4 would bring in the rest of the population not covered by the other phases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach, however, was criticized by another group of experts that also released their own global vaccination distribution model last week, published in Science, offering up a ‘Fair Priority Model’ that instead centered social justice and equity, and denounced vaccine nationalism (countries hoarding more vaccine doses than they need for their own citizens). “It’s clear that health care workers aren’t equally high-risk, especially in developed countries, where proper PPE [personal protective equipment] has driven their risk down significantly,” Ezekiel J. Emanuel, one of the authors of the ‘Fair Priority Model’ and chair of medical ethics and health policy at the University of Pennsylvania’s Perelman School of Medicine, tells Scientific American. “The approach is biased toward rich, well-developed countries because those countries have more health care workers per capita and also have more elderly people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related on The Swaddle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waiting For a Vaccine Cannot be Our Pandemic Response Strategy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, the experts urged governments to focus on three main aspects of what equitable distribution could prioritize — “benefiting people and limiting harm, prioritizing the disadvantaged, and equal moral concern.” This, they wrote, could happen in three phases — first would focus on reducing premature death, especially in poorer countries where it is more prevalent. Second would center the economic and social consequences of the Covid19 pandemic, such as the closure of schools and businesses that impact the livelihoods, and therefore, health, of populations around the world. And finally, the third phase would focus on reducing community transmission, targeted for countries with high transmission rates, geared toward restoring pre-pandemic freedoms and other economic and social activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“From an ethical standpoint, there’s not a good reason for absolute partiality, where a country covers every one of its citizens before giving any vaccine internationally,” Emanuel says. But, “the problem is: there’s almost no definition of what ‘fair and equitable’ means, specifically in terms of distribution.” In the interview, Emanuel also criticizes one of the World Health Organization’s proposed vaccine distribution models, which suggested giving the coronavirus vaccine to the top 3% of every country’s population, and then to 20% more, and so on. This, however, doesn’t take into account “that different areas of the world are suffering at different rates. Typically, when you’re giving international assistance, you give it to the people who are suffering most,” Emanuel says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that making sweeping statements about who is most at risk is a dangerous, and inconclusive practice — frontline workers are exposing themselves to Covid19 every day, but those who have proper PPE are at relatively low risk; older people with comorbidities are at risk, but medical research is unsure just how much a vaccine would help them in mounting a Covid19 immune response in the long run; people with underlying conditions are at risk, but in populations that have a high number of chronic illnesses, should the cancer patient get the vaccine over the person with an autoimmune disease? Experts around the world are currently struggling with these ideas, not just at the national, but also international level. Answering the question — who gets a Covid19 vaccine first? — is not easy, but asking it right now is imperative.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">The world is currently racing to develop a safe, effective, and accessible Covid19 vaccine. While these efforts tout new achievements every day and take us closer to a way out of this pandemic, medical experts and ethicists have also been trying to figure out one important, soon-to-be-pressing question: when we finally do get a Covid19 vaccine, its doses will be limited; so, who will get it first?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/CV_3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/CV_3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Covid 19 has sidetracked cancer care</title><link href="/How-Covid-19-has-sidetracked-cancer-care/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Covid 19 has sidetracked cancer care" /><published>2020-09-08T11:04:12+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T11:04:12+05:30</updated><id>/How-Covid-19-has-sidetracked-cancer-care</id><content type="html" xml:base="/How-Covid-19-has-sidetracked-cancer-care/">&lt;p&gt;According to a report from the World Health Organization, cancer is the second leading cause of death globally, accounting for an estimated 9.6 million deaths, or one in six deaths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the outbreak of Covid-19 has accelerated deaths due to cancer as hospitals are riveted by Covid-19 patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The implications of the pandemic to the treatment of cancer were discussed in Episode-6 of HEAL-Thy Samvaad organised by the ‘Healthcare Advocacy Group’ — HEAL Foundation. The programme was conducted in association with The International Council for Control of Iodine Deficiency Disorders (ICCIDD) last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALSO READ It’s ‘trading one health crisis for another’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elaborating on the rising death rate of cancer, Harit Chaturvedi, Chairman, Max Institute of Cancer Care, said: “Of course, the obstructions created by Covid-19 for patients with cancer have increased the current death rate of cancer. However, there is no need to worry — but go for treatment positively.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added: “Cancer facilities are as safe as they were in pre-Covid times, so don’t delay treatment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nutritional management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the prevention of cancer and the role of nutritional management in its care, Chaturvedi added: “Almost 50 per cent of cancer cases can be prevented if we take care of proper nutrition and a balanced diet. A healthy lifestyle, proper exercise, and intermittent fasting also help prevent cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Addiction to tobacco and high-fat content intake in the diet and faulty lifestyle contributes to 35 per cent and 15 per cent, respectively in the incidence of cancer cases. Fruits, vegetables, yoga &amp;amp; regular exercise help prevent cancer. The role of nutrition is pivotal in cancer prevention,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderating the session, Manjari Chandra, Clinical Nutritional &amp;amp; Founder, Manjari Wellness, said: “Research shows that certain plant foods contain powerful compounds — called phytochemicals — that can help fight cancer and reduce the risk of its development.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She added that these specific foods may hold a key to prevent the growth of cancer cells in the body. During Covid times, the role of good nutrition has substantially increased as it helps boost immunity, which helps fight all types of diseases including cancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can also be corroborated by a research paper published in the Asia Pacific Journal of Cancer that stated the Covid-19 pandemic has taken a big toll on the clinical trials running for oncology, the study and treatment of tumours.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">According to a report from the World Health Organization, cancer is the second leading cause of death globally, accounting for an estimated 9.6 million deaths, or one in six deaths.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/cancer" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/cancer" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AIIMS Researchers Sound Caution After Finding Zoonotic Malarial Parasite in Indian Patients</title><link href="/AIIMS-Researchers-Sound-Caution-After-Finding-Zoonotic-Malarial-Parasite-in-Indian-Patients/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AIIMS Researchers Sound Caution After Finding Zoonotic Malarial Parasite in Indian Patients" /><published>2020-09-08T11:01:29+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T11:01:29+05:30</updated><id>/AIIMS-Researchers-Sound-Caution-After-Finding-Zoonotic-Malarial-Parasite-in-Indian-Patients</id><content type="html" xml:base="/AIIMS-Researchers-Sound-Caution-After-Finding-Zoonotic-Malarial-Parasite-in-Indian-Patients/">&lt;p&gt;AIIMS researchers have sounded a note of caution after finding the presence of malarial parasite ‘Plasmodium knowlesi’ in the north Indian population, while doing a study on patients with Acute Febrile Illnesses (AFI) and pathogens causing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presence of the zoonotically transmitted malaria parasite was found during the study of Acute Febrile Iillnesses and causative pathogens in cerain patients admitted in AIIMS from July 2017 to September 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The All Indian Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS) researchers from the Department of Biochemistry along with clinicians from the Department of Medicine were involved in the study on the pathogens causing severe fever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A zoonotic disease is a disease that can be spread/jump from animals to humans, and vice versa. It can be caused by viruses, bacteria, parasites, and fungi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is necessary to understand how zoonotic diseases spread, and the way they infect humans, given the fact that the world is at present battling novel coronavirus that has emerged from bats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plasmodium knowlesi is a malaria parasite found in nature in long-tailed and pig-tailed macaques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team is led by Pragyan Acharya, Associate Professor, Department of Biochemistry, and comprises Manish Soneja from the Department of Medicine, along with Rajendra Mandage, Atreyi Pramanik, Parul Kodan, Vinod Sinha, Shivam Pandey and R.M. Pandey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The major lesson from this study is that zoonotic parasites are all around us – therefore maintaining a clean environment and following specific guidelines for the prevention of these diseases are important,” Acharya told IANS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A major reason for zoonotic pathogens’ effect on our lives is because we are encroaching the space of their animal hosts – massive decline in forest cover and consequent depleted habitats,” Acharya added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“However, this pathogen is not commonly tested during diagnosis, possibly due to its low prevalence and absence of rapid diagnostic methods.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The researchers said that their study shows the presence of the zoonotic parasite in states of Uttar Pradesh, Haryana, and Delhi. An earlier study at AIIMS had shown its presence in the Andaman and Nicobar Islands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the World Health Organisation, the parasite can give rise to daily fever spikes 9-12 days after the infection. Severe infection may lead to organ failure as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acharya and her team also found that simultaneous pathogenic infections in patients with fever can occur, influencing the severity of disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team found that malaria can exist with other co-infecting pathogens like dengue virus and bacterial species Leptospira and Orientia Tsutsugamushi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In tropical countries like India, acute febrile illnesses comprise a group of infections with similar clinical presentations such as fever, malaise, bodyache, chills, hepatic and renal dysfunction, and CNS effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is often difficult to distinguish between the causative agents of AFI, which can be bacterial, parasitic, or viral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, these pathogens may infect individuals at the same time and lead to modulation of immune responses, change treatment outcomes, and affect disease severity. The correct diagnosis of the infective agent causing fever is thus very important to ensure the right treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study results ask us to be vigilant about the possibility of multiple pathogenic causes of fever, and to maintain the habitats and ecosystems of animals, the AIIMS researchers added.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="HEALTH" /><summary type="html">AIIMS researchers have sounded a note of caution after finding the presence of malarial parasite ‘Plasmodium knowlesi’ in the north Indian population, while doing a study on patients with Acute Febrile Illnesses (AFI) and pathogens causing them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/1595861679_aiims-pti.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__11/1595861679_aiims-pti.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Microsoft to developers Say goodbye to cloud based dev environment Visual Studio Codespaces</title><link href="/Microsoft-to-developers-Say-goodbye-to-cloud-based-dev-environment-Visual-Studio-Codespaces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Microsoft to developers Say goodbye to cloud based dev environment Visual Studio Codespaces" /><published>2020-09-08T10:53:04+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T10:53:04+05:30</updated><id>/Microsoft-to-developers-Say-goodbye-to-cloud-based-dev-environment-Visual-Studio-Codespaces</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Microsoft-to-developers-Say-goodbye-to-cloud-based-dev-environment-Visual-Studio-Codespaces/">&lt;p&gt;Developer: What programming language would Julia users switch to? Watch Now&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has decided to end Visual Studio Codespaces, the rebranded version of Visual Studio Online, and instead will merge it with GitHub’s take on the same product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio Codespaces (formerly Visual Studio Online) is a cloud-based development environment aimed at making developers more more productive by creating a fully configured development environment in minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The announcement that Visual Studio Codespaces will be “consolidating” into GitHub Codespaces isn’t a surprise given the duplication between the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEE: Cheat sheet: Windows 10 PowerToys (free PDF) (TechRepublic)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft announced the rebranded product in May at Build 2020 alongside the new GitHub Codespaces, which itself is a take on VS Codespaces. Both products are online companions to Visual Studio and Visual Studio Code (VS Code).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Microsoft, the decision to move Visual Studio Codespaces to GitHub was to reduce confusion between the two near-identical products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“After the GitHub-native experience was released, we started hearing that the two distinct experiences were causing confusion amongst our users,” explains Allison Buchholtz-Au, a program manager for Visual Studio Online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe that by consolidating the current Codespaces experiences into one, we can eliminate confusion, simplify the experience for everyone, and make more rapid progress to address customer feedback.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shift means Visual Studio Codespaces users will need to move to GitHub Codespaces by February 2021, when the Visual Studio Codespaces offering on Azure will end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s not clear yet is the pricing for GitHub Codespaces, which is currently in a private beta. In May, along with the rebrand from Visual Studio Online, Microsoft reduced the price of VS Codespaces in the Microsoft Azure cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft cut the prices of instances for Visual Studio Codespaces in Azure by more than half their previous prices. For example, the Basic tier with two cores and 4GB of RAM was reduced to to .08 per hour, while the standard offer with four cores and 8GB of RAM on a Linux instance was reduced from about .45 per hour to .17 per hour. The premium tier with eight cores and 16GB of RAM was reduced from .87 to .34.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pricing for GitHub Codespaces hasn’t been finalized and there’s no mention of Azure on its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s Buchholtz-Au notes that, from September 4, current Visual Studio Codespaces users can begin transitioning to the GutHub private beta. On November 20, Microsoft will prevent users from creating new plans and Visual Studio Codespaces, though existing ones will live on. At that point new users will only be able to sign up for Codespaces on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final cut-off date comes on February 17, 2021, when Microsoft will shut the Visual Studio Codespaces portal and “all plans and codespaces remaining in the service will be deleted”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SEE: Seven Windows 10 annoyances (and how to fix them)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for pricing of GitHub Codespaces, Microsoft explains in an FAQ document that it will provide details later this year when GitHub Codespaces reaches general availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no charge for GitHub Codespaces while it is in limited public beta. Final pricing for GitHub Codespaces will be announced when Codespaces reaches general availability, which is expected later this year,” Microsoft states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is not a way to move Visual Studio Codespaces over to GitHub Codespaces. You will need to re-create your codespaces once you gain access to the GitHub Codespaces beta,” Microsoft notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hosting options are yet to be determined for developers who’ve used Visual Studio Codespaces with GitHub rivals like GitLab and BitBucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While GitHub Codespaces provides an optimized creation experience for GitHub repositories, we are currently iterating on the experience for repositories hosted elsewhere and will keep you updated as plans formalize,” Microsoft says.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Developer: What programming language would Julia users switch to? Watch Now</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__10/istock-1151967494.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__10/istock-1151967494.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">AMD is selling mountain bikes now</title><link href="/AMD-is-selling-mountain-bikes-now/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AMD is selling mountain bikes now" /><published>2020-09-08T10:49:08+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T10:49:08+05:30</updated><id>/AMD-is-selling-mountain-bikes-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="/AMD-is-selling-mountain-bikes-now/">&lt;p&gt;With such fierce competition on the GPU horizon thanks to Nvidia’s RTX 30 series, AMD is preparing to traverse the rocky roads ahead, cutting into its usual cycle of hardware releases to enter the bicycle market. You read that correctly. Not only can you brand yourself from head to toe in AMD gear, you can let everyone know you’re a part of the red team (or is it orange team, now?) with a new set of wheels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Available in the AMD fan shop to those in the US willing to pay a $50 shipping fee, there are two models to choose from: the AMD Custom Cruiser and the AMD Custom Mountain Bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both vehicles sport an 18.5” frame and 26” aluminium wheels, but there are noticeable differences between them. Designed for the casual cyclist, AMD’s Cruiser is much simpler, forgoing gears and adding fenders to prevent dirt and muck from being thrown up. AMD’s Mountain Bike goes in the opposite direction, packing 21-gear Shimano index-shifting gears on a dual-suspension frame and linear brakes. And yet both cost the exact same amount at $299.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether you choose a black frame with white wheels or a white frame with black wheels, you’ll be promoting AMD with a bold logo on the frame and Ryzen’s signature colour on the handlebars. If you truly want to show your dedication, though, you can always opt for the white frame with orange wheels, exclusive to the Mountain Bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not yet certain whether these bikes will see an international release, or just how serious AMD is about its travel products. Will we see AMD bunny hop from esports partnerships to extreme sports with its very own BMX? Only time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">With such fierce competition on the GPU horizon thanks to Nvidia’s RTX 30 series, AMD is preparing to traverse the rocky roads ahead, cutting into its usual cycle of hardware releases to enter the bicycle market. You read that correctly. Not only can you brand yourself from head to toe in AMD gear, you can let everyone know you’re a part of the red team (or is it orange team, now?) with a new set of wheels.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__10/AMD-Sells-Mountain-Bikes.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__10/AMD-Sells-Mountain-Bikes.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">OnePlus 8T details revealed When is the launch what are the specifications</title><link href="/OnePlus-8T-details-revealed-When-is-the-launch-what-are-the-specifications/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OnePlus 8T details revealed When is the launch what are the specifications" /><published>2020-09-08T10:48:50+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T10:48:50+05:30</updated><id>/OnePlus-8T-details-revealed-When-is-the-launch-what-are-the-specifications</id><content type="html" xml:base="/OnePlus-8T-details-revealed-When-is-the-launch-what-are-the-specifications/">&lt;p&gt;OnePlus 8T is tipped to launch later this year. (Representational photo)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year OnePlus launches two new series and two smartphones under each. Similar was the case with the OnePlus 8 series and the same will happen with the OnePlus 8T series as well. Besides working on an affordable OnePlus phone dubbed Clover the company is also gearing up to bring OnePlus 8T.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A report from Android Central reveals some details about the OnePlus 8T. The report reveals some of the key specifications of the upcoming OnePlus 8T and also when the phone will launch. Let’s take a look at everything that the report reveals about the upcoming OnePlus flagship smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OnePlus 8T specifications (expected)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the OnePlus 8T is codenamed Kebab. The report suggests that the OnePlus 8T will come with a 6.55-inch AMOLED display similar to the OnePlus 8. The smartphone is tipped to come with a 120Hz screen refresh rate. The report suggests that the OnePlus 8T will feature two modes to choose from 60Hz and 120Hz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sources close to the development revealed to the publication that the OnePlus 8T will pack four rear cameras at the back. The report suggests that the phone will include a 48MP primary image sensor, 16MP wide-angle module, 5MP macro, and 2MP portrait lens. This means that OnePlus will add an extra lens to the 8T when compared to the OnePlus 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OnePlus 8 features a triple rear camera setup including a 48MP primary sensor, secondary 16MP wide-angle, and third is a 2MP macro sensor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is OnePlus Clover and everything we know so far&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report further reveals that the OnePlus 8T will be powered by Qualcomm’s latest flagship processor Snapdragon 865+ processor paired with 8GB RAM with 128GB of internal storage. On the software front. the 8T is said to run OxygenOS 11 based on Android 11 out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, alleged renders of the OnePlus 8T were revealed for the first time. The renders suggested that OnePlus will not bring a major change to the 8T when compared to the 7T launched last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OnePlus 8T launch timeline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the report, OnePlus 8T will launch by the end of September or the first week of October. At the same time, last year OnePlus announced the 7T. The smartphone manufacturer is yet to reveal details about the OnePlus 8T and also the official launch timeline. Meanwhile, the company is also working on an affordable smartphone dubbed OnePlus Clover. OnePlus recently launched the Nord, the first mid-range smartphone after the OnePlus One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Express Tech is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@expresstechie) and stay updated with the latest tech news&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;📣 The Indian Express is now on Telegram. Click here to join our channel (@indianexpress) and stay updated with the latest headlines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the latest Technology News, download Indian Express App.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">OnePlus 8T is tipped to launch later this year. (Representational photo)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__10/oneplus-7t-fb.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__10/oneplus-7t-fb.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Maps uses AI to predict traffic and ETA dark mode for Maps may be in the works</title><link href="/Google-Maps-uses-AI-to-predict-traffic-and-ETA-dark-mode-for-Maps-may-be-in-the-works/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Maps uses AI to predict traffic and ETA dark mode for Maps may be in the works" /><published>2020-09-08T10:48:04+05:30</published><updated>2020-09-08T10:48:04+05:30</updated><id>/Google-Maps-uses-AI-to-predict-traffic-and-ETA-dark-mode-for-Maps-may-be-in-the-works</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Google-Maps-uses-AI-to-predict-traffic-and-ETA-dark-mode-for-Maps-may-be-in-the-works/">&lt;p&gt;Google Maps takes assistance from Deep Minds, a London-based AI lab owned by Google’s parent company Alphabet to get accurate results for users. Google, in a blog post, explains how the AI helps it collect data using neural networks to predict future traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This data includes live traffic information collected anonymously from Android devices, historical traffic data, information like speed limits and construction sites from local governments, and also factors like the quality, size, and direction of any given road, The Verge noted. “We then combine this database of historical traffic patterns with live traffic conditions, using machine learning to generate predictions based on both sets of data,” Johann Lau, product Manager Google Maps, wrote in the blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the AI, Google relies on traffic data from authorities of local governments and real-time feedback from users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google noted that its traffic predictions have been consistently accurate for over 97 per cent of trips. For the noted inaccuracy in Estimated Time Arrival (ETA), Google takes help of DeepMind using Graph Neural Networks that helps it in achieving accuracy. Google noted that it has seen improvements in Berlin, Jakarta, São Paulo, Sydney, Tokyo, and Washington DC. Through neural networks, Google Maps is able to better predict a journey well before it is even started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Google, the traffic patterns around the world have dramatically changed since the beginning of COVID 19 and so it will prioritise historical traffic patterns from the last two-to-four weeks, and deprioritise patterns from any time before that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In related news, Google Maps is testing a dark mode for the app. Until now, users were able to use the dark-mode in navigate option but as per a report by 9to5Google, Google may roll out an app-wide dark mode. However, it was just the APK versions that were uploaded by Google to the Play Store, meaning that they may or may not get materialised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 10.5.0 version of Google Maps describes a new “Appearance” menu in Settings where users will have three options: Default to device theme, Dark theme, and Light theme. The report noted that creating a dark map is likely a big effort and not as simple as inverting colours.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="TECHNOLOGY" /><summary type="html">Google Maps takes assistance from Deep Minds, a London-based AI lab owned by Google’s parent company Alphabet to get accurate results for users. Google, in a blog post, explains how the AI helps it collect data using neural networks to predict future traffic.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__10/Screenshot_2020-09-07_at_3.47.-647x363.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/08-09-2020__10/Screenshot_2020-09-07_at_3.47.-647x363.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>